[{"questionId":"B-001-001-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the ITU Radio Regulations"},{"letter":"B","text":"the Radiocommunication Act"},{"letter":"C","text":"the Radiocommunication Regulations"},{"letter":"D","text":"the Standards for the Operation of RadioStations in the Amateur Radio Service"}],"questionText":"Authority to make regulations governingradiocommunications is derived from:"},{"questionId":"B-001-001-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the Standards for the Operation of RadioStations in the Amateur Radio Service"},{"letter":"B","text":"the ITU Radio Regulations"},{"letter":"C","text":"the Radiocommunication Act"},{"letter":"D","text":"the Radiocommunication Regulations"}],"questionText":"Authority to make \"Standards for theOperation of Radio Stations in the AmateurRadio Service\" is derived from:"},{"questionId":"B-001-001-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"National Defence"},{"letter":"B","text":"Industry Canada"},{"letter":"C","text":"Transport Canada"},{"letter":"D","text":"Communications Canada"}],"questionText":"The Department that is responsible for theadministration of the RadiocommunicationAct is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-001-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the Radiocommunication Act"},{"letter":"B","text":"the Standards for the Operation of RadioStations in the Amateur Radio Service"},{"letter":"C","text":"the FCC's Part 97 rules"},{"letter":"D","text":"the Radiocommunication Regulations"}],"questionText":"The \"amateur radio service\" is defined in:"},{"questionId":"B-001-002-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Contact an accredited examiner andprovide details of your address change"},{"letter":"B","text":"Write amateur organizations advisingthem of your new address, enclosingyour certificate"},{"letter":"C","text":"Contact Industry Canada and providedetails of your address change"},{"letter":"D","text":"Telephone your local club, and give themyour new address"}],"questionText":"What must you do to notify your mailingaddress changes ?"},{"questionId":"B-001-002-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"three years"},{"letter":"B","text":"one year"},{"letter":"C","text":"life"},{"letter":"D","text":"five years"}],"questionText":"An Amateur Radio Operator Certificate isvalid for:"},{"questionId":"B-001-002-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"within the same province, there is noneed to notify Industry Canada"},{"letter":"B","text":"Industry Canada must be advised of anychange in postal address"},{"letter":"C","text":"Industry Canada must be notified within14 days of operation at the new address"},{"letter":"D","text":"the station shall not be operated until achange of address card is forwarded toIndustry Canada"}],"questionText":"Whenever a change of address is made:"},{"questionId":"B-001-002-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"must be retained at the station"},{"letter":"B","text":"must be put on file"},{"letter":"C","text":"must be kept in a safe place"},{"letter":"D","text":"must be kept on the person to whom it isissued"}],"questionText":"The Amateur Radio Operator Certificate:"},{"questionId":"B-001-002-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"12"},{"letter":"B","text":"24"},{"letter":"C","text":"72"},{"letter":"D","text":"48"}],"questionText":"The holder of an Amateur Radio OperatorCertificate shall, at the request of a dulyappointed radio inspector, produce thecertificate, or a copy thereof, to theinspector, within ____ hours after therequest:"},{"questionId":"B-001-002-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"retained in the radio amateur's vehicle"},{"letter":"B","text":"retained at the address provided toIndustry Canada"},{"letter":"C","text":"retained in a safety deposit box"},{"letter":"D","text":"retained on the radio amateur's person"}],"questionText":"The Amateur Radio Operator Certificateshould be:"},{"questionId":"B-001-003-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"are permitted for short tests only"},{"letter":"B","text":"are prohibited - penalties could beassessed to the control operator"},{"letter":"C","text":"must be identified with your call sign"},{"letter":"D","text":"are permitted"}],"questionText":"Out of amateur band transmissions:"},{"questionId":"B-001-003-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"False or deceptive signals"},{"letter":"B","text":"A traditional greeting in May"},{"letter":"C","text":"An emergency test transmission"},{"letter":"D","text":"Nothing special: \"MAYDAY\" has nomeaning in an emergency"}],"questionText":"If an amateur pretends there is anemergency and transmits the word\"MAYDAY,\" what is this called?"},{"questionId":"B-001-003-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a prison term of two years"},{"letter":"B","text":"a fine of $1 000"},{"letter":"C","text":"a fine, not exceeding $5 000, or a prisonterm of one year, or both"},{"letter":"D","text":"a fine of $10 000"}],"questionText":"A person found guilty of transmitting a falseor fraudulent distress signal, or interferingwith, or obstructing any radiocommunication, without lawful cause, maybe liable, on summary conviction, to apenalty of:"},{"questionId":"B-001-003-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The Radiocommunications Regulations"},{"letter":"B","text":"The Radiocommunications Law ReformAct of 2002"},{"letter":"C","text":"The Radiocommunication Act"},{"letter":"D","text":"The Official Radio Rules of Canada"}],"questionText":"What government document states theoffences and penalties for non compliance ofthe rules governing radiocommunications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-003-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Where the certificate was obtainedthrough misrepresentation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Where the holder has failed to complywith a request to pay fees or interest due"},{"letter":"C","text":"With no notice, or opportunity to makerepresentation thereto"},{"letter":"D","text":"Where the holder has contravened theRadiocommunication Act, itsRegulations, or the terms and conditionsof the certificate"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not correct? TheMinister may suspend an Amateur RadioOperator Certificate:"},{"questionId":"B-001-003-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"In executing a warrant, a radio inspectorshall not use force, unless accompaniedby a peace officer, and force isauthorized"},{"letter":"B","text":"The person in charge of a place enteredby a radio inspector shall give theinspector information that the inspectorrequests"},{"letter":"C","text":"A radio inspector may enter a dwellingwithout the consent of the occupant andwithout a warrant"},{"letter":"D","text":"Where entry is refused, and is necessaryto perform his duties under the Act, aradio inspector may obtain a warrant"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is notcorrect?"},{"questionId":"B-001-004-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"14 years or older"},{"letter":"B","text":"There are no age limits"},{"letter":"C","text":"70 years or younger"},{"letter":"D","text":"18 years or older"}],"questionText":"What age must you be to hold an AmateurRadio Operator Certificate with BasicQualification?"},{"questionId":"B-001-004-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Canadian Restricted Operator Certificate- Maritime (ROC-M)"},{"letter":"B","text":"Canadian Restricted Operator'sCertificate - Maritime Commercial (ROC-MC)"},{"letter":"C","text":"Canadian Restricted Operator Certificate- Aeronautical (ROC-A)"},{"letter":"D","text":"Canadian Radiocommunication OperatorGeneral Certificate Maritime (RGMC)"}],"questionText":"Holders of which one of the followingcertificates may be issued an AmateurRadio Operator Certificate?"},{"questionId":"B-001-004-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Morse code after passing the Basic withHonours"},{"letter":"B","text":"Advanced after passing Morse code"},{"letter":"C","text":"any order"},{"letter":"D","text":"Morse code after passing the Advanced"}],"questionText":"After an Amateur Radio Operator Certificatewith Basic qualifications is issued, theholder may be examined for additionalqualifications in the following order:"},{"questionId":"B-001-004-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"15 w.p.m."},{"letter":"B","text":"5 w.p.m."},{"letter":"C","text":"12 w.p.m."},{"letter":"D","text":"7 w.p.m."}],"questionText":"One Morse code qualification is available forthe Amateur Radio Operator Certificate. It is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-004-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a station authorized in the maritimeservice"},{"letter":"B","text":"any authorized station except stationsauthorized in the amateur, aeronautical ormaritime services"},{"letter":"C","text":"a station authorized in the amateurservice"},{"letter":"D","text":"a station authorized in the aeronauticalservice"}],"questionText":"The holder of an Amateur Radio OperatorCertificate with the Basic Qualification isauthorized to operate following stations:"},{"questionId":"B-001-004-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Have a valid address in Canada"},{"letter":"B","text":"Be a Canadian citizen"},{"letter":"C","text":"Be a Canadian citizen or permanentresident"},{"letter":"D","text":"Be at least 14 years of age and aCanadian citizen or permanent resident"}],"questionText":"What conditions must candidates toamateur radio certification meet?"},{"questionId":"B-001-005-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"pending the granting of a radioauthorization, if the apparatus covers theamateur and commercial frequencybands"},{"letter":"B","text":"pending the granting of an Amateur RadioOperator Certificate if the apparatuscovers the amateur frequency bands only"},{"letter":"C","text":"if the transmitter of a station, for which aradio authorization is to be applied for, istype approved and crystal controlled"},{"letter":"D","text":"if the other person is the holder of anAmateur Radio Operator Certificate tooperate in the amateur radio service"}],"questionText":"Radio apparatus may be installed, placed inoperation, repaired or maintained by theholder of an Amateur Radio OperatorCertificate with Advanced Qualification onbehalf of another person:"},{"questionId":"B-001-005-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"not install, place in operation, modify,repair, maintain, or permit the operationof the radio apparatus"},{"letter":"B","text":"install an amateur station, but notoperate or permit the operation of theapparatus"},{"letter":"C","text":"install and operate the radio apparatus,using your own call sign"},{"letter":"D","text":"modify and repair the radio apparatus butnot install it"}],"questionText":"Where a friend is not the holder of any typeof radio operator certificate, you, as a holderof an Amateur Radio Operator Certificatewith Basic Qualification, may, on behalf ofyour friend:"},{"questionId":"B-001-005-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"only if the station is for use on one of theVHF bands"},{"letter":"B","text":"only if the DC power input to the finalstage does not exceed 200 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"only if the other person is the holder of avalid Amateur Radio Operator Certificate"},{"letter":"D","text":"only if the final power input does notexceed 100 watts"}],"questionText":"A radio amateur with Basic and Morse codequalifications may install an amateur stationfor another person:"},{"questionId":"B-001-006-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"must be licensed by Industry Canada"},{"letter":"B","text":"need not be licensed in isolated areasonly"},{"letter":"C","text":"is exempt from regulatory control byIndustry Canada"},{"letter":"D","text":"must be operated by a person with anAmateur Certificate and call sign"}],"questionText":"An amateur radio station with a maximuminput power to the final stage of 2 watts:"},{"questionId":"B-001-006-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"stations operated under similarauthorizations"},{"letter":"B","text":"any stations which are identified forspecial contests"},{"letter":"C","text":"armed forces stations during specialcontests and training exercises"},{"letter":"D","text":"any station transmitting in the amateurbands"}],"questionText":"An amateur station may be used tocommunicate with:"},{"questionId":"B-001-006-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A radio amateur may not operate, orpermit to be operated, a radio apparatuswhich he knows is not performing to theRadiocommunication Regulations"},{"letter":"B","text":"A radio amateur may use a linearamplifier to amplify the output of alicence-exempt transmitter outside anyamateur radio allocations"},{"letter":"C","text":"A considerate operator does not transmitunnecessary signals"},{"letter":"D","text":"A courteous operator refrains from usingoffensive language"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is notcorrect?"},{"questionId":"B-001-006-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A person may operate an amateur radiostation when the person complies withthe Standards for the Operation of RadioStations in the Amateur Radio Service"},{"letter":"B","text":"An amateur radio operator transmittingunnecessary or offensive signals doesnot violate accepted practice"},{"letter":"C","text":"Except for a certified radio amateuroperating within authorized amateur radioallocations, no person shall possess oroperate any device for the purpose ofamplifying the output power of a licence-exempt radio apparatus"},{"letter":"D","text":"A person may operate or permit theoperation of radio apparatus only wherethe apparatus is maintained to theRadiocommunication Regulationstolerances"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is notcorrect?"},{"questionId":"B-001-006-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The radio is certified under the properRadio Standard Specification for use inCanada and licensed by Industry Canadaon the specified frequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"The radio operator has a RestrictedOperator's Certificate"},{"letter":"C","text":"The equipment has a RF power output of2 watts or less"},{"letter":"D","text":"The equipment is used in remote areasnorth of 60 degrees latitude"}],"questionText":"Some VHF and UHF FM radios purchasedfor use in the amateur service can also beprogrammed to communicate on frequenciesused for the land mobile service. Under whatconditions is this permissible?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Recreation planning"},{"letter":"B","text":"Code practice planning"},{"letter":"C","text":"Emergency planning"},{"letter":"D","text":"Business planning"}],"questionText":"Which of the following cannot be discussedon an amateur club net?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only when broadcasts last longer than 15minutes"},{"letter":"B","text":"Never"},{"letter":"C","text":"Only when the operator is being paid"},{"letter":"D","text":"Only when broadcasts last less than 1hour"}],"questionText":"When is a radio amateur allowed tobroadcast information to the general public?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"When playing a harmless \"practical joke\""},{"letter":"B","text":"When you need to hide the meaning of amessage for secrecy"},{"letter":"C","text":"Never"},{"letter":"D","text":"When operating a beacon transmitter in a\"fox hunt\" exercise"}],"questionText":"When may false or deceptive amateursignals or communications be transmitted?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Radio control commands to model craft"},{"letter":"B","text":"Brief transmissions to make adjustmentsto the station"},{"letter":"C","text":"Morse code practice"},{"letter":"D","text":"Broadcasts intended for the generalpublic"}],"questionText":"Which of the following one-waycommunications may not be transmitted inthe amateur service?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"When it includes sending the amateurstation's call sign"},{"letter":"B","text":"When the encoding technique ispublished in the public domain"},{"letter":"C","text":"When it is used for music streamingcontent"},{"letter":"D","text":"When it is used for commercial traffic"}],"questionText":"You wish to develop and use a new digitalencoding technique to transmit data overamateur radio spectrum. Under whatconditions is this permissible?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"When transmitting above 450 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"Only when the encoding or cipher is notsecret"},{"letter":"C","text":"During a declared communicationsemergency"},{"letter":"D","text":"During contests"}],"questionText":"When may an amateur station in two-waycommunication transmit an encodedmessage?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Speak closer to the microphone toincrease your signal strength"},{"letter":"B","text":"Adjust your transceiver noise blanker"},{"letter":"C","text":"Turn down the volume of backgroundaudio"},{"letter":"D","text":"Turn up the volume of your transmitter"}],"questionText":"What should you do to keep you stationfrom retransmitting music or signals from anon-amateur station?"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"is permitted for contests"},{"letter":"B","text":"must be approved by Industry Canada"},{"letter":"C","text":"is permitted for third-party traffic"},{"letter":"D","text":"is not permitted"}],"questionText":"The transmission of a secret code by theoperator of an amateur station:"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"commercially recorded material"},{"letter":"B","text":"Q signals"},{"letter":"C","text":"programming that originates from abroadcasting undertaking"},{"letter":"D","text":"radiocommunication in support ofindustrial, business, or professionalactivities"}],"questionText":"A radio amateur may be engaged incommunication which include thetransmission of:"},{"questionId":"B-001-007-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"are only permitted if they are for thesafety of life or immediate protection ofproperty"},{"letter":"B","text":"are not prohibited by regulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"are not permitted under anycircumstance"},{"letter":"D","text":"are permitted on some bands"}],"questionText":"In the amateur radio service, businesscommunications:"},{"questionId":"B-001-008-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Anywhere in Canada"},{"letter":"B","text":"Anywhere in Canada during times ofemergency"},{"letter":"C","text":"Only at the address shown on IndustryCanada records"},{"letter":"D","text":"Anywhere in your call sign prefix area"}],"questionText":"Where may the holder of an Amateur RadioOperator Certificate operate an amateurradio station in Canada?"},{"questionId":"B-001-008-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"HF station"},{"letter":"B","text":"VHF station"},{"letter":"C","text":"Beacon station"},{"letter":"D","text":"Repeater station"}],"questionText":"Which type of station may transmit one-waycommunications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-008-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"at the address which is on record atIndustry Canada and at one otherlocation"},{"letter":"B","text":"at the address which is on record atIndustry Canada and in two mobiles"},{"letter":"C","text":"at any location in Canada"},{"letter":"D","text":"only at the address which is on record atIndustry Canada"}],"questionText":"Amateur radio operators may install oroperate radio apparatus:"},{"questionId":"B-001-008-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Basic and Advanced"},{"letter":"B","text":"Basic, Advanced and Morse code"},{"letter":"C","text":"Basic"},{"letter":"D","text":"Basic with Honours"}],"questionText":"In order to install any radio apparatus, to beused specifically for an amateur radio clubstation, the radio amateur must hold anAmateur Radio Operator Certificate, with aminimum of the following qualifications:"},{"questionId":"B-001-008-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Basic, Advanced and Morse code"},{"letter":"B","text":"Basic and Advanced"},{"letter":"C","text":"Basic with Honours"},{"letter":"D","text":"Basic and Morse code"}],"questionText":"In order to install or operate a transmitter orRF amplifier that is neither professionallydesigned nor commercially manufactured foruse in the amateur service, a radio amateurmust hold an Amateur Operator's Certificate,with a minimum of which qualifications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The person who owns the stationequipment"},{"letter":"B","text":"Only the control operator"},{"letter":"C","text":"Both the control operator and the stationowner"},{"letter":"D","text":"Only the station owner who is the holderof an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate"}],"questionText":"Who is responsible for the proper operationof an amateur station?"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The station owner, unless the stationrecords show that you were the controloperator at the time"},{"letter":"B","text":"The station owner"},{"letter":"C","text":"Both of you"},{"letter":"D","text":"You"}],"questionText":"If you transmit from another amateur'sstation, who is responsible for its properoperation?"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"You are responsible for the properoperation of the station in accordancewith the regulations"},{"letter":"B","text":"You must allow another amateur tooperate your station upon request"},{"letter":"C","text":"You must be present whenever thestation is operated"},{"letter":"D","text":"You must notify Industry Canada ifanother amateur acts as the controloperator"}],"questionText":"What is your responsibility as a stationowner?"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Any person over 21 years of age withBasic and Morse code qualifications"},{"letter":"B","text":"Any person over 21 years of age"},{"letter":"C","text":"Any qualified amateur chosen by thestation owner"},{"letter":"D","text":"Any person over 21 years of age with aBasic Qualification"}],"questionText":"Who may be the control operator of anamateur station?"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Whenever the station receiver is operated"},{"letter":"B","text":"Only when training another amateur"},{"letter":"C","text":"Whenever the station is transmitting"},{"letter":"D","text":"A control operator is not needed"}],"questionText":"When must an amateur station have acontrol operator?"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"They must hold suitable amateur radioqualifications before they are allowed tobe control operators"},{"letter":"B","text":"They must not use your equipmentwithout your permission"},{"letter":"C","text":"They must first know how to use the rightabbreviations and Q signals"},{"letter":"D","text":"They must first know the rightfrequencies and emission modes fortransmitting"}],"questionText":"Why can't family members withoutqualifications transmit using your amateurstation if they are alone with yourequipment?"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"permit anyone to take part incommunications only if prior writtenpermission is received from IndustryCanada"},{"letter":"B","text":"permit anyone to use the station withoutrestrictions"},{"letter":"C","text":"permit anyone to use the station andtake part in communications"},{"letter":"D","text":"permit any person to operate the stationunder the supervision and in the presenceof the holder of the amateur operatorcertificate"}],"questionText":"The owner of an amateur station may:"},{"questionId":"B-001-009-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Any person may operate an amateurstation under supervision, and in thepresence of, a person holding appropriatequalifications"},{"letter":"B","text":"A person, holding only BasicQualification, may operate anotherstation on 14.2 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"Radio amateurs may permit any personto operate the station without supervision"},{"letter":"D","text":"Any person may operate a station in theamateur radio service"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements iscorrect?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Unidentified transmissions"},{"letter":"B","text":"Harmful interference"},{"letter":"C","text":"Interrupted CW"},{"letter":"D","text":"Transponder signals"}],"questionText":"What is a transmission called that disturbsother communications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only if the station is operating illegally"},{"letter":"B","text":"Only if the station begins transmitting ona frequency you are using"},{"letter":"C","text":"You may expect, and cause, deliberateinterference because it can't be helpedduring crowded band conditions"},{"letter":"D","text":"Never"}],"questionText":"When may you deliberately interfere withanother station's communications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Nothing special: all users of a frequencyband have equal rights to operate"},{"letter":"B","text":"Amateurs are only allowed to use thefrequency band during emergencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"Amateurs must increase transmitterpower to overcome any interferencecaused by primary users"},{"letter":"D","text":"Amateurs are allowed to use thefrequency band only if they do not causeinterference to primary users"}],"questionText":"If the regulations say that the amateurservice is a secondary user of a frequencyband, and another service is a primary user,what does this mean?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Station operators in ITU Regions 1 and 3must yield the frequency to stations inITU Region 2"},{"letter":"B","text":"Both station operators have an equal rightto operate on the frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"The station operator with a lesserqualification must yield the frequency toan operator of higher qualification"},{"letter":"D","text":"The station operator with a lower poweroutput must yield the frequency to thestation with a higher power output"}],"questionText":"What rule applies if two amateurs want touse the same frequency?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the Minister may require that thenecessary steps for the prevention of theinterference be taken by the radioamateur"},{"letter":"B","text":"the amateur station operator is notobligated to take any action"},{"letter":"C","text":"the amateur station operator maycontinue to operate without restrictions"},{"letter":"D","text":"the amateur station operator maycontinue to operate and the necessarysteps can be taken when the amateuroperator can afford it"}],"questionText":"Where interference to the reception ofradiocommunications is caused by theoperation of an amateur station:"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"144.0 to 148.0 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"14.0 to 14.2 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"430.0 to 450.0 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"7.0 to 7.1 MHz"}],"questionText":"Radio amateur operation must not causeinterference to other radio services operatingin which of the following bands?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"222 to 225 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"50 to 54 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"902 to 928 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"144 to 148 MHz"}],"questionText":"Radio amateur operations are not ARE NOTprotected from interference caused byanother service operating in which of thefollowing frequency bands?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"may conduct technical experimentsusing the station apparatus"},{"letter":"B","text":"may make trials or tests, except if thereis a possibility of interference to otherstations"},{"letter":"C","text":"may make trials or tests, even thoughthere is a possibility of interfering withother stations"},{"letter":"D","text":"shall not cause harmful interference to astation in another service which hasprimary use of that band"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not correct? Theoperator of an amateur station:"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3.5 to 4.0 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"430 to 450 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"135.7 to 137.8 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"902 to 928 MHz"}],"questionText":"Which of these amateur bands may beheavily occupied by licence exemptdevices?"},{"questionId":"B-001-010-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1240 to 1300 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"2300 to 2450 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"430 to 450 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"144 to 148 MHz"}],"questionText":"The amateur radio service is authorized toshare a portion of what Industrial ScientificMedical (ISM) band that is heavily used bylicence exempt devices?"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"with any station involved in a real orsimulated emergency"},{"letter":"B","text":"only with other amateur stations"},{"letter":"C","text":"with anyone who uses internationalMorse code"},{"letter":"D","text":"with non amateur stations"}],"questionText":"Amateur radio stations may communicate:"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"you may offer assistance after contactingIndustry Canada for permission to do so"},{"letter":"B","text":"you may not offer assistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"you should offer assistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"you may offer assistance usinginternational Morse code only"}],"questionText":"If you hear an unanswered distress signal onan amateur band where you do not haveprivileges to communicate:"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radio communications required for theimmediate safety of life of individuals orthe immediate protection of property"},{"letter":"B","text":"music"},{"letter":"C","text":"commercially recorded material"},{"letter":"D","text":"programming that originates from abroadcast undertaking"}],"questionText":"In the amateur radio service, it is permissibleto broadcast:"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"use any means of radiocommunication,but only on internationally recognizedemergency channels"},{"letter":"B","text":"only Morse code communications oninternationally recognized emergencychannels"},{"letter":"C","text":"any means of radiocommunication"},{"letter":"D","text":"only use radiocommunication bands forwhich the operator is qualified to use"}],"questionText":"An amateur radio station in distress may:"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only when the local emergency net isactivated"},{"letter":"B","text":"When normal communication systemsare overloaded, damaged or disrupted"},{"letter":"C","text":"Never: only official emergency stationsmay transmit in a disaster"},{"letter":"D","text":"When normal communication systemsare working but are not convenient"}],"questionText":"During a disaster, when may an amateurstation make transmissions necessary tomeet essential communication needs andassist relief operations?"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1500 watts PEP"},{"letter":"B","text":"200 watts PEP"},{"letter":"C","text":"There are no limitations for a station indistress"},{"letter":"D","text":"1000 watts PEP during daylight hours,reduced to 200 watts PEP during thenight"}],"questionText":"During an emergency, what power outputlimitations must be observed by a station indistress?"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"use only frequencies in the 40 metreband"},{"letter":"B","text":"use any United Nations approvedfrequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"most communications are handled bynets using predetermined frequencies inamateur bands. Operators not directlyinvolved with disaster communicationsare requested to avoid makingunnecessary transmissions on or nearfrequencies being used for disastercommunications"},{"letter":"D","text":"use only frequencies in the 80 metreband"}],"questionText":"During a disaster:"},{"questionId":"B-001-011-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"using Morse code only"},{"letter":"B","text":"when Industry Canada has issued aspecial authorization"},{"letter":"C","text":"only on the 7 and 14 MHz bands"},{"letter":"D","text":"during peace time and civil emergenciesand exercises"}],"questionText":"Messages from recognized public serviceagencies may be handled by amateur radiostations:"},{"questionId":"B-001-012-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"No payment of any kind is allowed"},{"letter":"B","text":"Donation of amateur equipment"},{"letter":"C","text":"Donation of equipment repairs"},{"letter":"D","text":"Any amount agreed upon in advance"}],"questionText":"What kind of payment is allowed for third-party messages sent by an amateurstation?"},{"questionId":"B-001-012-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"if transmitted in English or French"},{"letter":"B","text":"during peacetime civil emergencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"if it is transmitted by an amateur station"},{"letter":"D","text":"if transmitted by any station using theinternational Morse code"}],"questionText":"Radiocommunications transmitted bystations other than a broadcasting stationmay be divulged or used:"},{"questionId":"B-001-012-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"shall charge no less than $10 for eachmessage that the person transmits orreceives"},{"letter":"B","text":"shall charge no more than $10 for eachmessage that the person transmits orreceives"},{"letter":"C","text":"may accept a gift or gratuity in lieu ofremuneration for any message that theperson transmits or receives"},{"letter":"D","text":"shall not demand or accept remunerationin any form, in respect of aradiocommunication that the persontransmits or receives"}],"questionText":"The operator of an amateur station:"},{"questionId":"B-001-012-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Where it is for the purpose of preservingor protecting property, or for theprevention of harm to a person"},{"letter":"B","text":"Where it is for the purpose of givingevidence in a criminal or civil proceedingin which persons are required to giveevidence"},{"letter":"C","text":"Where it is on behalf of Canada, for thepurpose of international or nationaldefence or security"},{"letter":"D","text":"Where it is to provide information for ajournalist"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not an exceptionfrom the penalties under the Act, fordivulging, intercepting or using informationobtained through radiocommunication, otherthan broadcasting?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"SM2CAN"},{"letter":"B","text":"BY7HY"},{"letter":"C","text":"KA9OLS"},{"letter":"D","text":"VA3XYZ"}],"questionText":"Which of the following call signs is a validCanadian amateur radio call sign?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"At least every thirty minutes, and at thebeginning and at the end of a contact"},{"letter":"B","text":"At the beginning of a contact and at leastevery thirty minutes after that"},{"letter":"C","text":"At least once during each transmission"},{"letter":"D","text":"At the beginning and end of eachtransmission"}],"questionText":"How often must an amateur station beidentified?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Your \"handle\""},{"letter":"B","text":"Your first name and your location"},{"letter":"C","text":"Your full name"},{"letter":"D","text":"Your call sign"}],"questionText":"What do you transmit to identify youramateur station?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Each station must transmit its own callsign"},{"letter":"B","text":"No identification is required"},{"letter":"C","text":"Both stations must transmit both callsigns"},{"letter":"D","text":"One of the stations must give bothstations' call signs"}],"questionText":"What identification, if any, is required whentwo amateur stations begincommunications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20 minutes"},{"letter":"B","text":"15 minutes"},{"letter":"C","text":"10 minutes"},{"letter":"D","text":"30 minutes"}],"questionText":"What is the longest period of time anamateur station can transmit, withoutidentifying by call sign?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only for two-way or third-partycommunications"},{"letter":"B","text":"Never, except to control a model craft"},{"letter":"C","text":"Only for brief tests not meant asmessages"},{"letter":"D","text":"Only if it does not interfere with others"}],"questionText":"When may an amateur transmit unidentifiedcommunications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Any language being used for a contact,providing Canada has a third-partycommunications agreement with thatcountry"},{"letter":"B","text":"Any language of a country which is amember of the InternationalTelecommunication Union"},{"letter":"C","text":"English or French"},{"letter":"D","text":"Any language being used for a contact"}],"questionText":"What language may you use whenidentifying your station?"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"at intervals not greater than ten minuteswhen using Morse code"},{"letter":"B","text":"when requested to do so by the stationbeing called"},{"letter":"C","text":"at the beginning and at the end of eachexchange of communications and atintervals not greater than 30 minutes"},{"letter":"D","text":"at intervals not greater than three minuteswhen using voice communications"}],"questionText":"The call sign of an amateur station must betransmitted:"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"every minute"},{"letter":"B","text":"every 15 minutes"},{"letter":"C","text":"once after initial contact"},{"letter":"D","text":"at the beginning and end of eachexchange of communications, and atleast every 30 minutes, while incommunications"}],"questionText":"The call sign of an amateur station must besent:"},{"questionId":"B-001-013-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"GA, GE, MO or VQ"},{"letter":"B","text":"A, K, N or W"},{"letter":"C","text":"EA, EI, RO or UY"},{"letter":"D","text":"VA, VE, VO or VY"}],"questionText":"The call sign of a Canadian amateur radiostation would normally start with the letters:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Report the incident to the foreignamateur's government"},{"letter":"B","text":"Stop all discussions and quickly sign off"},{"letter":"C","text":"Have your friend wait until you determinefrom the foreign station if theiradministration permits third-party traffic"},{"letter":"D","text":"Since you can talk to foreign amateurs,your friend may keep talking as long asyou are the control operator"}],"questionText":"If a non-amateur friend is using your stationto talk to someone in Canada, and a foreignstation breaks in to talk to your friend, whatshould you do?"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"such communications have beenauthorized by the other countryconcerned"},{"letter":"B","text":"the amateur station has received writtenauthorization from Industry Canada topass third party traffic"},{"letter":"C","text":"the communication is transmitted bysecret code"},{"letter":"D","text":"prior remuneration has been received"}],"questionText":"Radio amateurs may use their stations totransmit international communications onbehalf of a third party only if:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"until he has properly identified his station"},{"letter":"B","text":"unless he is passing third-party traffic"},{"letter":"C","text":"when that country has notified theInternational Telecommunication Unionthat it objects to such communications"},{"letter":"D","text":"without written permission from IndustryCanada"}],"questionText":"A person operating a Canadian amateurstation is forbidden to communicate withamateur stations of another country:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radiotelegraphy is used"},{"letter":"B","text":"the countries concerned have authorizedsuch communications"},{"letter":"C","text":"English or French is used to identify thestation at the end of each transmission"},{"letter":"D","text":"the countries for which the traffic isintended have registered their consent tosuch communications with the ITU"}],"questionText":"International communications on behalf ofthird parties may be transmitted by anamateur station only if:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a simultaneous communication betweenthree operators"},{"letter":"B","text":"none of these answers"},{"letter":"C","text":"the transmission of non-commercial orpersonal messages to or on behalf of athird party"},{"letter":"D","text":"the transmission of commercial or secretmessages"}],"questionText":"Amateur third party communications is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the foreign administration is in a declaredstate of war"},{"letter":"B","text":"internet service is working well in theforeign country involved"},{"letter":"C","text":"specifically prohibited by the foreignadministration concerned"},{"letter":"D","text":"satellite communication can be originatedin the disaster area"}],"questionText":"International third party amateur radiocommunication in case of emergencies ordisaster relief is expressly permitted unless:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"all messages received from Canadianstations"},{"letter":"B","text":"messages originated from CanadianForces Affiliate Radio Service (CFARS)"},{"letter":"C","text":"messages that are handled within a localnetwork"},{"letter":"D","text":"messages addressed to points withinCanada"}],"questionText":"One of the following is not considered to becommunications on behalf of a third party,even though the message is originated by,or addressed to, a non-amateur:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"add to his call sign the Canadian callsign prefix for the geographic location ofthe station"},{"letter":"B","text":"qualify his identification when operatingphone by adding to the call sign the word\"mobile\" or \"portable\" or when operatingMorse code by adding a slash \"/\""},{"letter":"C","text":"identify with the call sign assigned by theFCC"},{"letter":"D","text":"obtain a Canadian amateur certificatebefore operating in Canada"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not correct? Whileoperating in Canada a radio amateurlicensed by the Government of the UnitedStates must:"},{"questionId":"B-001-014-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"pass third-party traffic with all dulylicensed amateur stations in any countrywhich is a member of the ITU"},{"letter":"B","text":"pass messages originating from ordestined to the United States MilitaryAuxiliary Radio System (MARS)"},{"letter":"C","text":"pass messages originating from ordestined to the Canadian Forces AffiliateRadio Service (CFARS)"},{"letter":"D","text":"communicate with a similar station of acountry which has not notified ITU that itobjects to such communications"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is notcorrect? A Canadian radio amateur may, onamateur frequencies,:"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only the privileges allowed by yourqualifications"},{"letter":"B","text":"Any privileges allowed by the additionalqualifications"},{"letter":"C","text":"All the emission privileges of theadditional qualifications, but only thefrequency privileges of your qualifications"},{"letter":"D","text":"All the frequency privileges of theadditional qualifications, but only theemission privileges of your qualifications"}],"questionText":"If you let another amateur with additionalqualifications than yours control yourstation, what operating privileges areallowed?"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Any privileges allowed by the additionalqualifications"},{"letter":"B","text":"All the emission privileges of theadditional qualifications, but only thefrequency privileges of your qualifications"},{"letter":"C","text":"All the frequency privileges of theadditional qualifications, but only theemission privileges of your qualifications"},{"letter":"D","text":"Only the privileges allowed by yourqualifications"}],"questionText":"If you are the control operator at the stationof another amateur who has additionalqualifications to yours, what operatingprivileges are you allowed?"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"You must pass a Morse code test"},{"letter":"B","text":"You must attend a class to learn aboutHF communications"},{"letter":"C","text":"You must pass a Morse code orAdvanced test or attain a mark of 80% onthe Basic exam"},{"letter":"D","text":"You must notify Industry Canada that youintend to operate on the HF bands"}],"questionText":"In addition to passing the Basic writtenexamination, what must you do before youare allowed to use amateur frequenciesbelow 30 MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"if only pulse modulation is used"},{"letter":"B","text":"on all frequencies above 30 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"if the control transmitter does not exceed15 kHz of occupied bandwidth"},{"letter":"D","text":"if the frequency used is below 30 MHz"}],"questionText":"The holder of an amateur radio certificatemay operate radio controlled models:"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2.25 to 2.5 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.8 to 2.0 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.5 to 2.0 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"2.0 to 2.25 MHz"}],"questionText":"In Canada, the 160 metre amateur bandcorresponds in frequency to:"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6.5 to 6.8 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"6.0 to 6.3 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"7.7 to 8.0 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"7.0 to 7.3 MHz"}],"questionText":"In Canada, the 40 metre amateur bandcorresponds in frequency to:"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"14.000 to 14.350 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"13.500 to 14.000 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"15.000 to 15.750 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"16.350 to 16.830 MHz"}],"questionText":"In Canada, the 20 meter amateur bandcorresponds in frequency to:"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"21.000 to 21.450 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"18.068 to 18.168 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"14.000 to 14.350 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"28.000 to 29.700 MHz"}],"questionText":"In Canada, the 15 metre amateur bandcorresponds in frequency to:"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"21.000 to 21.450 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"50.000 to 54.000 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"28.000 to 29.700 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"24.890 to 24.990 MHz"}],"questionText":"In Canada, the 10 metre amateur bandcorresponds in frequency to:"},{"questionId":"B-001-015-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"all amateur frequency bands"},{"letter":"B","text":"50 to 54, 144 to 148, and 222 to 225MHz only"},{"letter":"C","text":"all amateur frequency bands above 30MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"50 to 54 MHz only"}],"questionText":"In Canada, radio amateurs may use which ofthe following for radio control of models:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The total bandwidth shall not exceed 10times that of a CW emission"},{"letter":"B","text":"30 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"20 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"The total bandwidth shall not exceed thatof a single-sideband phone emission"}],"questionText":"What is the maximum authorized bandwidthwithin the frequency range of 50 to 148MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"15 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"20 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"6 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"30 kHz"}],"questionText":"The maximum bandwidth of an amateurstation's transmission allowed in the band28 to 29.7 MHz is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"15 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"20 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"30 kHz"}],"questionText":"Except for one band, the maximumbandwidth of an amateur station'stransmission allowed between 7 and 28 MHzis:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"30 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"20 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"6 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"15 kHz"}],"questionText":"The maximum bandwidth of an amateurstation's transmission allowed in the band50 to 54 MHz is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"24.89 to 24.99 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.8 to 2.0 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"10.1 to 10.15 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"18.068 to 18.168 MHz"}],"questionText":"Which of the following bands of amateurfrequencies has a maximum allowedbandwidth of less than 6 kHz. That band is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"7.0 to 7.3 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"10.1 to 10.15 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"18.068 to 18.168 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"24.89 to 24.99 MHz"}],"questionText":"Single sideband is not permitted in the band:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Ensure that the bandwidth required oneither side of the carrier frequency doesnot fall out of band"},{"letter":"B","text":"Restrict operation to telegraphy"},{"letter":"C","text":"Make sure that the emission mode iscompatible with agreed band plans"},{"letter":"D","text":"Watch the standing wave ratio so as notto damage the transmitter"}],"questionText":"What precaution must an amateur radiooperator take when transmitting near bandedges?"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"300 bps packet on 10.145 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"fast-scan television (ATV) on 440 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"fast-scan television (ATV) on 145 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"AMTOR on 14.08 MHz"}],"questionText":"Which of the following answers is notcorrect? Based on the bandwidth required,the following modes may be transmitted onthese frequencies:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"single-sideband (SSB) on 3.76 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"fast-scan television (ATV) on 14.23 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"slow-scan television (SSTV) on 14.23MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"frequency modulation (FM) on 29.6 MHz"}],"questionText":"Which of the following answers is notcorrect? Based on the bandwidth required,the following modes may be transmitted onthese frequencies:"},{"questionId":"B-001-016-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"300 bps packet on 10.148 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"single-sideband (SSB) on 10.12 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"frequency modulation (FM) on 29.6 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"Morse radiotelegraphy (CW) on 10.11MHz"}],"questionText":"Which of the following answers is notcorrect? Based on the bandwidth required,the following modes may be transmitted onthese frequencies:"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2000 watts PEP output"},{"letter":"B","text":"The minimum legal power necessary tocommunicate"},{"letter":"C","text":"25 watts PEP output"},{"letter":"D","text":"250 watts PEP output"}],"questionText":"What amount of transmitter power shouldradio amateurs use at all times?"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1000 watts DC input"},{"letter":"B","text":"200 watts PEP output"},{"letter":"C","text":"25 watts PEP output"},{"letter":"D","text":"250 W DC input"}],"questionText":"What is the most FM transmitter power aholder of only Basic Qualification may useon 147 MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"560 watts PEP output for SSB operation"},{"letter":"B","text":"1000 watts PEP output for SSB operation"},{"letter":"C","text":"1500 watts PEP output for SSB operation"},{"letter":"D","text":"2000 watts PEP output for SSB operation"}],"questionText":"What is the maximum transmitting outputpower an amateur station may use on 3750kHz, if the operator has Basic and Morsecode qualifications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2000 watts PEP output"},{"letter":"B","text":"200 watts PEP output"},{"letter":"C","text":"560 watts PEP output"},{"letter":"D","text":"1000 watts PEP output"}],"questionText":"What is the maximum transmitting power anamateur station may use for SSB operationon 7055 kHz, if the operator has Basic withHonours qualifications?"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"500 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"750 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"1000 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"250 watts"}],"questionText":"The DC power input to the anode or collectorcircuit of the final RF stage of a transmitter,used by a holder of an Amateur RadioOperator Certificate with AdvancedQualification, shall not exceed:"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"250 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"1500 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"500 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"1000 watts"}],"questionText":"The maximum DC input to the final stage ofan amateur transmitter, when the operator isthe holder of both the Basic and Advancedqualifications, is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"150 watts peak power"},{"letter":"B","text":"560 watts peak-envelope power, fortransmitters producing any type of singlesideband emission"},{"letter":"C","text":"2500 watts peak power"},{"letter":"D","text":"1000 watts carrier power for transmittersproducing other emissions"}],"questionText":"The operator of an amateur station, who isthe holder of a Basic Qualification, shallensure that the station power, whenexpressed as RF output power measuredacross an impedance matched load, doesnot exceed:"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"750"},{"letter":"B","text":"100"},{"letter":"C","text":"250"},{"letter":"D","text":"1000"}],"questionText":"The holder of an Amateur Radio OperatorCertificate with Basic Qualification is limitedto a maximum of _______ watts whenexpressed as direct current input power tothe anode or collector circuit of thetransmitter stage supplying radio frequencyenergy to the antenna:"},{"questionId":"B-001-017-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 watts carrier power HF transmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"200 watts carrier power HF transceiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"600 watts PEP HF linear amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"160 watts carrier power VHF amplifier"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is the most powerfulequipment the holder of a Basic withHonours certificate can legally operate at fullpower?"},{"questionId":"B-001-018-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"for brief tests on frequencies below 30MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"if the output to the final RF amplifier iskept under 5W"},{"letter":"C","text":"when transmitting SSB"},{"letter":"D","text":"in frequency bands below 30 MHz"}],"questionText":"An unmodulated carrier may be transmittedonly:"},{"questionId":"B-001-018-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"50 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"144 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"29.5 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"29.7 MHz"}],"questionText":"Radiotelephone signals in a frequency bandbelow ____ MHz cannot be automaticallyretransmitted, unless these signals arereceived from a station operated by a personqualified to transmit on frequencies belowthe above frequency:"},{"questionId":"B-001-018-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"in the 50-54 MHz frequency band, whenreceived from a station operated by aperson with only Basic Qualification"},{"letter":"B","text":"in the 144-148 MHz frequency band,when received from a station operated bya person with only Basic Qualification"},{"letter":"C","text":"in the 21 MHz band, when received in aVHF band, from a station operated by aperson with only Basic Qualification"},{"letter":"D","text":"in the 29.5-29.7 MHz band, whenreceived in a VHF band, from a stationoperated by a person with only BasicQualification"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is notcorrect? Radiotelephone signals may beretransmitted:"},{"questionId":"B-001-019-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the bandwidth for any emission must notexceed 3 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"the frequency stability of the transmittermust be at least two parts per millionover a period of one hour"},{"letter":"C","text":"an overmodulation indicator must be used"},{"letter":"D","text":"the frequency stability must becomparable to crystal control"}],"questionText":"When operating on frequencies below 148MHz:"},{"questionId":"B-001-019-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"persons other than the holder of theauthorization use the station"},{"letter":"B","text":"radiotelephony is used"},{"letter":"C","text":"DC input power to the anode or collectorcircuit of the final RF stage is in excessof 250 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"radiotelegraphy is used"}],"questionText":"A reliable means to prevent or indicateovermodulation must be employed at anamateur station if:"},{"questionId":"B-001-019-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"plate voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"overmodulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"resonance"},{"letter":"D","text":"antenna power"}],"questionText":"An amateur station using radiotelephonymust install a device for indicating orpreventing:"},{"questionId":"B-001-019-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 percent"},{"letter":"B","text":"75 percent"},{"letter":"C","text":"50 percent"},{"letter":"D","text":"90 percent"}],"questionText":"The maximum percentage of modulationpermitted in the use of radiotelephony by anamateur station is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-019-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a reliable means of determining theoperating radio frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"a DC power meter"},{"letter":"C","text":"an overmodulation indicating device"},{"letter":"D","text":"a dummy antenna"}],"questionText":"All amateur stations, regardless of the modeof transmission used, must be equippedwith:"},{"questionId":"B-001-020-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Messages of a technical nature orpersonal remarks of relative unimportance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Messages of any type, if the foreigncountry allows third-partycommunications with Canada"},{"letter":"C","text":"Messages that are not religious, political,or patriotic in nature"},{"letter":"D","text":"Messages of any type"}],"questionText":"What type of messages may be transmittedto an amateur station in a foreign country?"},{"questionId":"B-001-020-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"all communications are conducted insecret code"},{"letter":"B","text":"charges are properly applied to all third-party communications"},{"letter":"C","text":"communications are limited to messagesof a technical or personal nature"},{"letter":"D","text":"communications are exchanged only withcommercial stations"}],"questionText":"The operator of an amateur station shallensure that:"},{"questionId":"B-001-020-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Radiocommunications between countriesshall be forbidden, if the administration ofone of the countries objects"},{"letter":"B","text":"Administrations shall take suchmeasures as they judge necessary toverify the operational and technicalqualifications of amateurs"},{"letter":"C","text":"Transmissions between countries shallnot include any messages of a technicalnature, or remarks of a personalcharacter"},{"letter":"D","text":"It is forbidden to transmit internationalmessages on behalf of third parties,unless those countries make specialarrangements"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not a provision ofthe ITU Radio Regulations which apply toCanadian radio amateurs?"},{"questionId":"B-001-020-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"28 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"none of the other answers"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.8 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"3.5MHz"}],"questionText":"The ITU Radio Regulations limit those radioamateurs, who have not demonstratedproficiency in Morse code, to frequenciesabove:"},{"questionId":"B-001-020-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"American Radio Relay League"},{"letter":"B","text":"Radio Amateurs of Canada Inc."},{"letter":"C","text":"International Amateur Radio Union"},{"letter":"D","text":"International Telecommunication Union"}],"questionText":"In addition to complying with theRadiocommunication Act and Regulations,Canadian radio amateurs must also complywith the regulations of the:"},{"questionId":"B-001-021-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Region 3"},{"letter":"B","text":"Region 1"},{"letter":"C","text":"Region 2"},{"letter":"D","text":"Region 4"}],"questionText":"In which International TelecommunicationUnion Region is Canada?"},{"questionId":"B-001-021-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ITU Region 2"},{"letter":"B","text":"ITU Region 3"},{"letter":"C","text":"ITU Region 1"},{"letter":"D","text":"Those applicable to US radio amateurs"}],"questionText":"A Canadian radio amateur, operating hisstation in the state of Florida, is subject towhich frequency band limits?"},{"questionId":"B-001-021-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Those applicable to US radio amateurs"},{"letter":"B","text":"Those applicable to Canadian radioamateurs"},{"letter":"C","text":"ITU Region 1"},{"letter":"D","text":"ITU Region 2"}],"questionText":"A Canadian radio amateur, operating hisstation 7 kilometres (4 miles) offshore fromthe coast of Florida, is subject to whichfrequency band limits?"},{"questionId":"B-001-021-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Region 3"},{"letter":"B","text":"Region 4"},{"letter":"C","text":"Region 2"},{"letter":"D","text":"Region 1"}],"questionText":"Canada is located in ITU Region:"},{"questionId":"B-001-022-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The fee for taking an examination for anAmateur Radio Operator Certificate at anIndustry Canada office is $5 perqualification"},{"letter":"B","text":"An accredited examiner may recover thecost of administering an examination"},{"letter":"C","text":"An accredited volunteer examiner musthold an Amateur Radio OperatorCertificate with Basic, Advanced, andMorse code qualifications"},{"letter":"D","text":"The fee for taking an examination for anAmateur Radio Operator Certificate at anIndustry Canada office is $20 perqualification"}],"questionText":"Which of these statements is not correct?"},{"questionId":"B-001-022-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A disabled candidate must pass a normalamateur radio certificate examinationbefore being granted any qualification"},{"letter":"B","text":"A disabled candidate, taking a Morsecode sending test, may be allowed torecite the examination text in Morse codesounds"},{"letter":"C","text":"Examinations for disabled candidatesmay be given orally, or tailored to thecandidate's ability to complete theexamination"},{"letter":"D","text":"An accredited examiner may recover thecost of administering an examination."}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is notcorrect?"},{"questionId":"B-001-022-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"always $20 per qualification"},{"letter":"B","text":"always free of charge"},{"letter":"C","text":"always $20 per visit regardless of thenumber of examinations"},{"letter":"D","text":"to be negotiated between examiner andcandidate"}],"questionText":"The fee for taking examinations for amateurradio operator certificates by an accreditedvolunteer examiner is:"},{"questionId":"B-001-022-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"$5 per qualification examination"},{"letter":"B","text":"$20 per qualification"},{"letter":"C","text":"$20 per visit, regardless of the number ofqualification examinations"},{"letter":"D","text":"no charge for qualification examinations"}],"questionText":"The fee for taking amateur radio certificateexaminations at an Industry Canada officeis:"},{"questionId":"B-001-022-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An examiner may request medicalevidence from a practicing medicalphysician before accommodating testing"},{"letter":"B","text":"A candidate with insufficient knowledge ofEnglish or French may be accompaniedby an interpreter"},{"letter":"C","text":"A candidate who fails a writtenexamination for lack of reading skills maybe given an oral examination"},{"letter":"D","text":"A candidate who fails a writtenexamination due to not usually speakingEnglish or French may be given an oralexamination"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is false?"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The majority of neighbours residing withina distance of three times the proposedantenna structure height"},{"letter":"B","text":"The Minister of Industry"},{"letter":"C","text":"The person planning to use the tower ortheir spouse"},{"letter":"D","text":"The local municipal government"}],"questionText":"Who has authority over antenna installationsincluding antenna masts and towers?"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"When the structure is part of an amateurradio antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"When transmitting will only be done atlow power"},{"letter":"C","text":"When an exclusion criterion defined byIndustry Canada applies"},{"letter":"D","text":"In a rural area"}],"questionText":"If you are planning to install or modify anantenna system under what conditions mayyou not be required to contact land useauthorities to determine public consultationrequirements?"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"must implement a public consultationprocess of their own design"},{"letter":"B","text":"must wait for the land use authority todevelop a public consultation process"},{"letter":"C","text":"must fulfill the public consultationrequirements set out in Industry Canada'sDefault Public Consultation Processunless the land use authority excludestheir type of proposal from consultation orit is excluded by Industry Canada'sprocess"},{"letter":"D","text":"can proceed with their project withoutpublic consultation"}],"questionText":"The land use authority has not established aprocess for public consultation for antennasystems. The radio amateur planning toinstall or modify an antenna system:"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Participating in public meetings on theproject"},{"letter":"B","text":"Providing written notice"},{"letter":"C","text":"Addressing relevant questions commentsand concerns"},{"letter":"D","text":"Providing an opportunity for the public torespond regarding measures to addressreasonable and relevant concerns"}],"questionText":"Which is not an element of the IndustryCanada Public Consultation Process forantenna systems?"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"opposition to the project"},{"letter":"B","text":"reasonable and relevant concernsprovided in writing within the 30 daypublic comment period"},{"letter":"C","text":"all questions, comments and concernsraised"},{"letter":"D","text":"comments reported in media reporting onthe proposal"}],"questionText":"The Default Public Consultation Process forantenna systems requires proponents toaddress:"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"be made by Industry Canada"},{"letter":"B","text":"be postponed until those in dispute reachan agreement"},{"letter":"C","text":"be made by the municipality in which theantenna is to be built"},{"letter":"D","text":"be made by a majority vote of thoseresiding within a radius of three times theantenna structure height"}],"questionText":"Where the proponent and a stakeholderother than the general public reach animpasse over a proposed antenna systemthe final decision will:"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the taller of the height exclusion in theland use authority public consultationprocess and Industry Canada's antennasiting procedures"},{"letter":"B","text":"10m"},{"letter":"C","text":"15m"},{"letter":"D","text":"21m"}],"questionText":"In general, what is the tallest amateur radioantenna system excluded from therequirement to consult with the land useauthority and the public where there is aland use authority defined publicconsultation process?"},{"questionId":"B-001-023-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The person planning to erect an antennastructure"},{"letter":"B","text":"The provincial government"},{"letter":"C","text":"The municipality or local land useauthority"},{"letter":"D","text":"Industry Canada"}],"questionText":"Where a land use authority or municipalityhas established a public consultationprocess for antenna systems, whodetermines how public consultation shouldtake place?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Transport Canada"},{"letter":"B","text":"Health Canada"},{"letter":"C","text":"Canadian Standards Association"},{"letter":"D","text":"Environment Canada"}],"questionText":"What organization has published safetyguidelines for the maximum limits of RFenergy near the human body?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It sets antenna height limits for aircraftprotection"},{"letter":"B","text":"It gives RF exposure limits for the humanbody"},{"letter":"C","text":"It lists all RF frequency allocations forinterference protection"},{"letter":"D","text":"It sets transmitter power limits forinterference protection"}],"questionText":"What is the purpose of the Safety Code 6?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3 to 30 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"30 to 300 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"300 to 3000 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"Above 1500 MHz"}],"questionText":"According to Safety Code 6, whatfrequencies cause us the greatest risk fromRF energy?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Most transmissions in this range are for alonger time"},{"letter":"B","text":"The human body absorbs RF energy themost in this range"},{"letter":"C","text":"There are more transmitters operating inthis range"},{"letter":"D","text":"There are fewer transmitters operating inthis range"}],"questionText":"Why is the limit of exposure to RF thelowest in the frequency range of 30 MHz to300 MHz, according to Safety Code 6?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Permissible exposure levels of RF fieldsdecreases as frequency is decreasedbelow 10 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"Maximum exposure levels of RF fields tothe general population, in the frequencyrange 10 to 300 MHz, is 28 V/m RMS (E-field)"},{"letter":"C","text":"Permissible exposure levels of RF fieldsincreases as frequency is increased from300 MHz to 1.5 GHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"Permissible exposure levels of RF fieldsincreases as frequency is decreasedfrom 10 MHz to 1 MHz"}],"questionText":"Which of the following statements is notcorrect?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"increases, as frequency is increasedfrom 300 MHz to 1.5 GHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"decreases, as frequency is decreasedbelow 10 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"increases, as frequency is increasedfrom 10 MHz to 300 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"decreases, as frequency is increasedabove 300 MHz"}],"questionText":"The permissible exposure levels of RF fields:"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"hand held transmitters are excluded fromSafety Code 6 requirements"},{"letter":"B","text":"Antenna gain, distance, transmitterpower and frequency are all factors whichinfluence the electric field strength and aperson's exposure to radio energy."},{"letter":"C","text":"Safety Code 6 uses different units for themagnetic field strength and the electricfield strength when stating limits"},{"letter":"D","text":"Safety Code 6 specifies lower exposurelimits for the general public inuncontrolled areas than it does for peoplein controlled areas"}],"questionText":"Which statement is not correct?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The operation of portable transmittingequipment is of no concern in SafetyCode 6"},{"letter":"B","text":"Portable transmitters, operating below 1GHz, with an output power equal to, orless than 7 watts, are exempt from therequirements of Safety Code 6"},{"letter":"C","text":"Safety Code 6 sets limits for RFexposure from all radio transmittersregardless of power output"},{"letter":"D","text":"Safety Code 6 regulates the operation ofreceivers only"}],"questionText":"Which statement is correct?"},{"questionId":"B-001-024-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Safety Code 6 sets limits for allowablerates at which RF energy is absorbed inthe body (Specific Absorption Rate)"},{"letter":"B","text":"Safety Code 6 sets limits in terms ofpower levels fed into antennas"},{"letter":"C","text":"Safety Code 6 sets limits for contactcurrents that could be drawn fromungrounded or poorly grounded objects"},{"letter":"D","text":"Safety Code 6 sets limits for inducedcurrents, electrical field strength andmagnetic field strength fromelectromagnetic radiation"}],"questionText":"Which of these statements about SafetyCode 6 is false?"},{"questionId":"B-001-025-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"on the neighbour's premises is aboveIndustry Canada's specified immunitycriteria"},{"letter":"B","text":"near the TV is below Industry Canada'sspecified immunity criteria"},{"letter":"C","text":"at the transmitting location is below theradio amateur's maximum allowabletransmitter power"},{"letter":"D","text":"at the transmitting location is above theradio amateur's maximum allowabletransmitter power"}],"questionText":"In the event of interference to a neighbour'stelevision receiver, according to EMCAB-2 itwill be deemed that a radio amateur'stransmission is the cause of the problem ifthe field strength:"},{"questionId":"B-001-025-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Broadcast receivers"},{"letter":"B","text":"Radio-sensitive equipment"},{"letter":"C","text":"Cable television converters"},{"letter":"D","text":"Audio and video recorders"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is defined in EMCAB-2 as \"any device, machinery or equipment,other than radio apparatus, the use orfunctioning of which is, or can be, adverselyaffected by radiocommunication emissions\"?"},{"questionId":"B-001-025-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Broadcast transmitters"},{"letter":"B","text":"Broadcast receivers"},{"letter":"C","text":"Associated equipment"},{"letter":"D","text":"Radio-sensitive equipment"}],"questionText":"According to EMCAB-2 which of thefollowing types of equipment is not includedin the list of field strength criteria forresolution of immunity complaints?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Say the call sign of the station you wantto contact, then your call sign"},{"letter":"B","text":"Say the other operator's name, then yourcall sign three times"},{"letter":"C","text":"Say, \"Breaker, breaker,\""},{"letter":"D","text":"Say the call sign of the station you wantto contact three times"}],"questionText":"What is a good way to make contact on arepeater?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To increase the range of portable andmobile stations"},{"letter":"B","text":"To link amateur stations with thetelephone system"},{"letter":"C","text":"To retransmit weather information duringsevere storm warnings"},{"letter":"D","text":"To make local information available 24hours a day"}],"questionText":"What is the main purpose of a repeater?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The selection of simplex frequencies byindividual operators"},{"letter":"B","text":"A part of the planning prior to a contest"},{"letter":"C","text":"A process which seeks to carefullyassign frequencies so as to minimizeinterference with neighbouring repeaters"},{"letter":"D","text":"A band plan detailing modes andfrequency segments within a band"}],"questionText":"What is frequency coordination on VHF andUHF bands?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It tells how long someone has been usinga repeater"},{"letter":"B","text":"It interrupts lengthy transmissionswithout pauses"},{"letter":"C","text":"It lets a repeater have a rest period afterheavy use"},{"letter":"D","text":"It logs repeater transmit time to predictwhen a repeater will fail"}],"questionText":"What is the purpose of a repeater time-outtimer?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Wait for the station to call \"CQ\", thenanswer it"},{"letter":"B","text":"Say the station's call sign, then identifyyour own station"},{"letter":"C","text":"Say \"break, break 79,\" then say thestation's call sign"},{"letter":"D","text":"Say \"CQ\" three times, then say thestation's call sign"}],"questionText":"How do you call another station on arepeater if you know the station's call sign?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To check the SWR of the repeater"},{"letter":"B","text":"To reach for pencil and paper for third-party communications"},{"letter":"C","text":"To dial up the repeater's autopatch"},{"letter":"D","text":"To listen for anyone else wanting to usethe repeater"}],"questionText":"Why should you pause briefly betweentransmissions when using a repeater?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To see if the receiving station operator isstill awake"},{"letter":"B","text":"A long transmission may preventsomeone with an emergency from usingthe repeater"},{"letter":"C","text":"To keep long-distance charges down"},{"letter":"D","text":"To give any listening non-hams a chanceto respond"}],"questionText":"Why should you keep transmissions shortwhen using a repeater?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Wait for the end of a transmission andstart calling the desired party"},{"letter":"B","text":"Shout, \"break, break!\" to show that you'reeager to join the conversation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Turn on an amplifier and override whoeveris talking"},{"letter":"D","text":"Say your call sign during a breakbetween transmissions"}],"questionText":"What is the proper way to join into aconversation on a repeater?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"What is your 12?"},{"letter":"B","text":"Where are you?"},{"letter":"C","text":"What is your 20?"},{"letter":"D","text":"Locations are not normally told by radio"}],"questionText":"What is the accepted way to ask someonetheir location when using a repeater?"},{"questionId":"B-002-001-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"800 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1 000 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"400 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"600 kHz"}],"questionText":"FM repeater operation on the 2 metre banduses one frequency for transmission andone for reception. The difference in frequencybetween the transmit and receive frequencyis normally:"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Turn up your microphone gain"},{"letter":"B","text":"Use Standard International Phonetics foreach letter of your call sign"},{"letter":"C","text":"Use any words which start with the sameletters as your call sign for each letter ofyour call"},{"letter":"D","text":"Talk louder"}],"questionText":"To make your call sign better understoodwhen using voice transmissions, whatshould you do?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Unique words of your choice"},{"letter":"B","text":"A speech compressor"},{"letter":"C","text":"The Standard International PhoneticAlphabet"},{"letter":"D","text":"Q signals"}],"questionText":"What can you use as an aid for correctstation identification when using phone?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Baker"},{"letter":"B","text":"Bravo"},{"letter":"C","text":"Brazil"},{"letter":"D","text":"Borneo"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter B?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Dog"},{"letter":"B","text":"Denmark"},{"letter":"C","text":"David"},{"letter":"D","text":"Delta"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter D?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Echo"},{"letter":"B","text":"Easy"},{"letter":"C","text":"Edward"},{"letter":"D","text":"England"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter E?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Germany"},{"letter":"B","text":"Gibraltar"},{"letter":"C","text":"Golf"},{"letter":"D","text":"George"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter G?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"India"},{"letter":"B","text":"Iran"},{"letter":"C","text":"Italy"},{"letter":"D","text":"Item"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter I?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Love"},{"letter":"B","text":"London"},{"letter":"C","text":"Luxembourg"},{"letter":"D","text":"Lima"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter L?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Portugal"},{"letter":"B","text":"Paris"},{"letter":"C","text":"Peter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Papa"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter P?"},{"questionId":"B-002-002-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Roger"},{"letter":"B","text":"Radio"},{"letter":"C","text":"Romania"},{"letter":"D","text":"Romeo"}],"questionText":"What is the Standard International Phoneticfor the letter R?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Say \"CQ\" at least ten times, followed by\"this is,\" followed by your call signspoken once"},{"letter":"B","text":"Say \"CQ\" three times, followed by \"thisis,\" followed by your call sign spokenthree times"},{"letter":"C","text":"Say \"CQ\" once, followed by \"this is,\"followed by your call sign spoken threetimes"},{"letter":"D","text":"Say \"CQ\" at least five times, followed by\"this is,\" followed by your call signspoken once"}],"questionText":"What is the correct way to call \"CQ\" whenusing voice?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Transmitting one-way communications"},{"letter":"B","text":"Transmitting and receiving on the samefrequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"Transmitting and receiving over a widearea"},{"letter":"D","text":"Transmitting on one frequency andreceiving on another"}],"questionText":"What is simplex operation?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"When the most reliable communicationsare needed"},{"letter":"B","text":"When an emergency telephone call isneeded"},{"letter":"C","text":"When you are traveling and need somelocal information"},{"letter":"D","text":"When signals are reliable betweencommunicating parties without using arepeater"}],"questionText":"When should you consider using simplexoperation instead of a repeater?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To minimize interference on HF bandscapable of long-distance communication"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because greater output power ispermitted on VHF and UHF"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because HF transmissions are notpropagated locally"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because signals are stronger on VHFand UHF frequencies"}],"questionText":"Why should local amateur communicationsuse VHF and UHF frequencies instead of HFfrequencies?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Some frequencies are designated fornarrow band FM and others for widebandFM"},{"letter":"B","text":"You may inadvertently choose a channelthat is the input to a local repeater"},{"letter":"C","text":"Interference may be caused tounlicensed devices operating in the sameband"},{"letter":"D","text":"Implanted medical devices share thesame spectrum"}],"questionText":"Why should we be careful in choosing asimplex frequency when operating VHF orUHF FM?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"See if you can clearly receive the stationon the repeater's input frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"See if a third station can clearly receiveboth of you"},{"letter":"C","text":"See if you can clearly receive a moredistant repeater"},{"letter":"D","text":"See if you can clearly receive the stationon a lower frequency band"}],"questionText":"If you are talking to a station using arepeater, how would you find out if you couldcommunicate using simplex instead?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Changing the repeater's frequencyrequires the authorization of IndustryCanada"},{"letter":"B","text":"Changing the repeater's frequency is notpractical"},{"letter":"C","text":"The repeater's output power may ruinyour station's receiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"There are more repeater operators thansimplex operators"}],"questionText":"If you are operating simplex on a repeaterfrequency, why would it be good amateurpractice to change to another frequency?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Lower"},{"letter":"B","text":"FM"},{"letter":"C","text":"Double"},{"letter":"D","text":"Upper"}],"questionText":"Which sideband is commonly used for 20-metre phone operation?"},{"questionId":"B-002-003-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Telephone an experienced local amateur"},{"letter":"B","text":"Look at the propagation forecasts in anamateur radio magazine"},{"letter":"C","text":"Listen for signals from that area from anamateur beacon station or a foreignbroadcast or television station on anearby frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"Ask others on your local 2 metre FMrepeater"}],"questionText":"What is the best method to tell if a band is\"open\" for communication with a particulardistant location?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Listen to make sure that someone will beable to hear you"},{"letter":"B","text":"Listen to make sure others are not usingthe frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"Check your antenna for resonance at theselected frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"Make sure the SWR on your antennatransmission line is high enough"}],"questionText":"What should you do before you transmit onany frequency?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Turn on your speech processor"},{"letter":"B","text":"Reduce your SWR"},{"letter":"C","text":"Continue with your contact, making nochanges"},{"letter":"D","text":"Turn down your power output to theminimum necessary"}],"questionText":"If you contact another station and yoursignal is extremely strong and perfectlyreadable, what adjustment should you maketo your transmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Use a long wire antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"Tune up on 40 metres first, then switch tothe desired band"},{"letter":"C","text":"Use twin lead instead of coaxial cabletransmission lines"},{"letter":"D","text":"Tune the transmitter into a dummy load"}],"questionText":"What is one way to shorten transmitter tune-up time on the air to cut down oninterference?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Use a dummy load"},{"letter":"B","text":"Choose an unoccupied frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"Use a non-resonant antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"Use a resonant antenna that requires noloading-up procedure"}],"questionText":"How can on-the-air interference beminimized during a lengthy transmittertesting or tuning procedure?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is faster to tune"},{"letter":"B","text":"To reduce output power"},{"letter":"C","text":"To test or adjust your transceiver withoutcausing interference"},{"letter":"D","text":"To give comparative signal reports"}],"questionText":"Why would you use a dummy load?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Cancel the net for that day"},{"letter":"B","text":"Call and ask occupants to relinquish thefrequency for the scheduled netoperations, but if they are not agreeable,conduct the net on a frequency 3 to 5kHz away from the regular net frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"Reduce your output power and start thenet as usual"},{"letter":"D","text":"Increase your power output so that netparticipants will be able to hear you overthe existing activity"}],"questionText":"If you are the net control station of a dailyHF net, what should you do if the frequencyon which you normally meet is in use justbefore the net begins?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Move your contact to another frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"Tell the interfering stations to changefrequency, since you were there first"},{"letter":"C","text":"Report the interference to your localAmateur Auxiliary Coordinator"},{"letter":"D","text":"Increase the output power of yourtransmitter to overcome the interference"}],"questionText":"If propagation changes during your contactand you notice increasing interference fromother activity on the same frequency, whatshould you do?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Approximately 10 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"Approximately 3 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"150 to 500 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"Approximately 6 kHz"}],"questionText":"When selecting a single-sideband phonetransmitting frequency, what minimumfrequency separation from a contact inprogress should you allow (betweensuppressed carriers) to minimizeinterference?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A plan of operating schedules within anamateur band published by IndustryCanada"},{"letter":"B","text":"A plan devised by a club to best use afrequency band during a contest"},{"letter":"C","text":"A guideline for deviating from amateurfrequency band allocations"},{"letter":"D","text":"A guideline for using different operatingmodes within an amateur band"}],"questionText":"What is a band plan?"},{"questionId":"B-002-004-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"listen carefully so as not to interruptcommunications already in progress"},{"letter":"B","text":"ask if the frequency is occupied"},{"letter":"C","text":"make an announcement on the frequencyindicating that you intend to make a call"},{"letter":"D","text":"decrease your receiver's volume"}],"questionText":"Before transmitting, the first thing youshould do is:"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Send the letters \"CQ\" over and over"},{"letter":"B","text":"Send the letters \"CQ\" three times,followed by \"DE\", followed by your callsign sent three times"},{"letter":"C","text":"Send the letters \"CQ\" three times,followed by \"DE\", followed by your callsign sent once"},{"letter":"D","text":"Send the letters \"CQ\" ten times, followedby \"DE\", followed by your call sign sentonce"}],"questionText":"What is the correct way to call \"CQ\" whenusing Morse code?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Send your call sign followed by yourname, station location and a signal report"},{"letter":"B","text":"Send the other station's call sign twice,followed by \"DE\", followed by your callsign twice"},{"letter":"C","text":"Send your call sign four times"},{"letter":"D","text":"Send the other station's call sign once,followed by \"DE\", followed by your callsign four times"}],"questionText":"How should you answer a routine Morsecode \"CQ\" call?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"At the highest speed at which you cancontrol the keyer"},{"letter":"B","text":"At any speed which you can reliablyreceive"},{"letter":"C","text":"At any speed below 5 w.p.m."},{"letter":"D","text":"At the highest speed your keyer willoperate"}],"questionText":"At what speed should a Morse code \"CQ\"call be transmitted?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Received all correctly"},{"letter":"B","text":"Calling any station"},{"letter":"C","text":"Directional Emissions"},{"letter":"D","text":"From"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of the procedural signal\"DE\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"All received correctly"},{"letter":"B","text":"Any station please reply"},{"letter":"C","text":"End of message"},{"letter":"D","text":"Called station only transmit"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of the procedural signal\"K\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Calling any station"},{"letter":"B","text":"Go ahead"},{"letter":"C","text":"Best regards"},{"letter":"D","text":"Distant station"}],"questionText":"What is meant by the term \"DX\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Go ahead"},{"letter":"B","text":"Best regards"},{"letter":"C","text":"Long distance"},{"letter":"D","text":"Love and kisses"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of the term \"73\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An operator must activate a manualsend/receive switch before and after everytransmission"},{"letter":"B","text":"Breaking stations send the Morse codeprosign \"BK\""},{"letter":"C","text":"Incoming signals are received betweentransmitted Morse code dots and dashes"},{"letter":"D","text":"Automatic keyers are used to sendMorse code instead of hand keys"}],"questionText":"Which of the following describes full break-intelegraphy (QSK)?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3 to 6 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"150 to 500 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"5 to 50 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"1 to 3 kHz"}],"questionText":"When selecting a CW transmittingfrequency, what minimum frequencyseparation from a contact in progress shouldyou allow to minimize interference?"},{"questionId":"B-002-005-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"save time by leaving out spaces betweenwords"},{"letter":"B","text":"tune the transmitter using the operatingantenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"listen to the frequency to make sure thatit is not in use before transmitting"},{"letter":"D","text":"always give stations a good readabilityreport"}],"questionText":"Good Morse telegraphy operators:"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A short way to describe ionosphericconditions"},{"letter":"B","text":"A short way to describe signal reception"},{"letter":"C","text":"A short way to describe transmitterpower"},{"letter":"D","text":"A short way to describe sunspot activity"}],"questionText":"What are \"RST\" signal reports?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Recovery, signal strength, tempo"},{"letter":"B","text":"Recovery, signal speed, tone"},{"letter":"C","text":"Readability, signal speed, tempo"},{"letter":"D","text":"Readability, signal strength, tone"}],"questionText":"What does \"RST\" mean in a signal report?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The contact is serial number 33"},{"letter":"B","text":"Your signal is readable with considerabledifficulty and weak in strength"},{"letter":"C","text":"Your signal is unreadable, very weak instrength"},{"letter":"D","text":"The station is located at latitude 33degrees"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of: \"Your signal reportis 3 3 \"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"You are perfectly readable with a signalstrength 20 decibels greater than S 9"},{"letter":"B","text":"The bandwidth of your signal is 20decibels above linearity"},{"letter":"C","text":"Repeat your transmission on a frequency20 kHz higher"},{"letter":"D","text":"Your signal strength has increased by afactor of 100"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of: \"You are 5 9 plus20 dB\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The other operator needs to know howwell he is received at the repeater, nothow well you receive the repeater"},{"letter":"B","text":"The repeater gain affects your S-meterreading"},{"letter":"C","text":"You need to listen to the repeater inputfrequency for an accurate signal report"},{"letter":"D","text":"Signal reports are only useful on simplexcommunications"}],"questionText":"A distant station asks for a signal report ona local repeater you monitor. Which factaffects your assessment?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Increase by approximately one S unit"},{"letter":"B","text":"Increase by approximately four S units"},{"letter":"C","text":"Decrease by approximately four S units"},{"letter":"D","text":"Decrease by approximately one S unit"}],"questionText":"If the power output of a transmitter isincreased by four times, how might a nearbyreceiver's S-meter reading change?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Approximately 4 times"},{"letter":"B","text":"Approximately 5 times"},{"letter":"C","text":"Approximately 3 times"},{"letter":"D","text":"Approximately 2 times"}],"questionText":"By how many times must the power outputof a transmitter be increased to raise the S-meter reading on a nearby receiver from S8to S9?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Your signal is barely readable,moderately strong, and with faint ripple"},{"letter":"B","text":"Your signal is perfectly readable,moderately strong, and with perfect tone"},{"letter":"C","text":"Your signal is perfectly readable, weakstrength, and with perfect tone"},{"letter":"D","text":"Your signal is fairly readable, fairstrength, and with perfect tone"}],"questionText":"What does \"RST 579\" mean in a Morsecode contact?"},{"questionId":"B-002-006-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Your signal is barely readable, very weak,and with perfect tone"},{"letter":"B","text":"Your signal is moderately readable, veryweak, and with hum on the tone"},{"letter":"C","text":"Your signal is quite readable, fairstrength, and with perfect tone"},{"letter":"D","text":"Your signal is very readable, very strong,and with perfect tone"}],"questionText":"What does \"RST 459\" mean in a Morsecode contact?"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Send \"RST\" report"},{"letter":"B","text":"Radio station location is:"},{"letter":"C","text":"Send more slowly"},{"letter":"D","text":"Interference from static"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of the Q signal \"QRS\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"My name is"},{"letter":"B","text":"Time here is"},{"letter":"C","text":"My location is"},{"letter":"D","text":"Stop sending"}],"questionText":"What is one meaning of the Q signal \"QTH\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"QRL?"},{"letter":"B","text":"QRV?"},{"letter":"C","text":"QRU?"},{"letter":"D","text":"QRZ?"}],"questionText":"What is the proper Q signal to use to see ifa frequency is in use before transmitting onCW?"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Use more power"},{"letter":"B","text":"Send faster"},{"letter":"C","text":"Send more slowly"},{"letter":"D","text":"Change frequency"}],"questionText":"What is one meaning of the Q signal\"QSY\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"I am busy"},{"letter":"B","text":"I have no message"},{"letter":"C","text":"A contact is confirmed"},{"letter":"D","text":"Your signal is fading"}],"questionText":"What is the meaning of the Q signal \"QSB\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"QSL?"},{"letter":"B","text":"QRL?"},{"letter":"C","text":"QRT?"},{"letter":"D","text":"QRZ?"}],"questionText":"What is the proper Q signal to ask who iscalling you on CW?"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"your signals are fading"},{"letter":"B","text":"is my transmission being interfered with"},{"letter":"C","text":"I am being interfered with"},{"letter":"D","text":"I am troubled by static"}],"questionText":"The signal \"QRM\" signifies:"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"I am busy"},{"letter":"B","text":"are you troubled by static"},{"letter":"C","text":"I am being interfered with"},{"letter":"D","text":"I am troubled by static"}],"questionText":"The signal \"QRN\" means:"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"QRS"},{"letter":"B","text":"QRM"},{"letter":"C","text":"QRL"},{"letter":"D","text":"QRN"}],"questionText":"The \"Q signal\" indicating that you want theother station to send slower is:"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"QRZ?"},{"letter":"B","text":"QRK?"},{"letter":"C","text":"QRP?"},{"letter":"D","text":"QRM?"}],"questionText":"Who is calling me is denoted by the \"Qsignal\":"},{"questionId":"B-002-007-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"QRX"},{"letter":"B","text":"QRZ"},{"letter":"C","text":"QRS"},{"letter":"D","text":"QRT"}],"questionText":"The \"Q signal\" which signifies \"I will call youagain\" is:"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Direct the calling station to the nearestemergency net frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"Call your local police station and informthem of the emergency call"},{"letter":"C","text":"Immediately stop your contact andacknowledge the emergency call"},{"letter":"D","text":"Tell the calling station that the frequencyis in use"}],"questionText":"If you are in contact with another station andyou hear an emergency call for help on yourfrequency, what should you do?"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Say \"SOS\" several times"},{"letter":"B","text":"Say \"EMERGENCY\" several times"},{"letter":"C","text":"Say \"HELP\" several times"},{"letter":"D","text":"Say \"MAYDAY\" several times"}],"questionText":"What is the proper distress call to use whenoperating phone?"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"CQD"},{"letter":"B","text":"QRRR"},{"letter":"C","text":"MAYDAY"},{"letter":"D","text":"SOS"}],"questionText":"What is the proper distress call to use whenoperating CW?"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Break-in immediately following thetransmission of the active party and stateyour situation and call sign"},{"letter":"B","text":"Say \"EMERGENCY\" three times"},{"letter":"C","text":"Say \"SOS,\" then your call sign"},{"letter":"D","text":"Say \"HELP\" as many times as it takesto get someone to answer"}],"questionText":"What is the proper way to interrupt arepeater conversation to signal a distresscall?"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"So you may operate in contests whereAC power is not allowed"},{"letter":"B","text":"So you may use your station whilemobile"},{"letter":"C","text":"So you may provide communications inan emergency"},{"letter":"D","text":"So you will comply with rules"}],"questionText":"Why is it a good idea to have a way tooperate your amateur station without usingcommercial AC power lines?"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An extra antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"A portable amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"A microphone headset for hands-freeoperation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Several sets of charged batteries"}],"questionText":"What is the most important accessory tohave for a hand-held radio in an emergency?"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A dipole"},{"letter":"B","text":"A parabolic dish"},{"letter":"C","text":"A three-element Yagi"},{"letter":"D","text":"A three-element quad"}],"questionText":"Which type of antenna would be a goodchoice as part of a portable HF amateurstation that could be set up in case of anemergency?"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an emergency message"},{"letter":"B","text":"no other messages"},{"letter":"C","text":"a government priority message"},{"letter":"D","text":"a safety message"}],"questionText":"In order of priority, a distress messagecomes before:"},{"questionId":"B-002-008-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"take no action"},{"letter":"B","text":"tell all other stations to ceasetransmitting"},{"letter":"C","text":"contact authorities and then maintainwatch until you are certain thatassistance will be forthcoming"},{"letter":"D","text":"enter the details in the log book and takeno further action"}],"questionText":"If you hear distress traffic and are unable torender direct assistance you should:"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A written proof of communicationbetween two amateurs"},{"letter":"B","text":"A Notice of Violation from IndustryCanada"},{"letter":"C","text":"A postcard reminding you when yourcertificate will expire"},{"letter":"D","text":"A letter or postcard from an amateur penpal"}],"questionText":"What is a \"QSL card\"?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A map projection centered on a particularlocation, used to determine the shortestpath between points on the Earth'ssurface"},{"letter":"B","text":"A map projection centered on the NorthPole"},{"letter":"C","text":"A map that shows the angle at which anamateur satellite crosses the equator"},{"letter":"D","text":"A map that shows the number of degreeslongitude that an amateur satelliteappears to move westward at the equator"}],"questionText":"What is an azimuthal map?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Mercator"},{"letter":"B","text":"Polar projection"},{"letter":"C","text":"Topographical"},{"letter":"D","text":"Azimuthal"}],"questionText":"What is the most useful type of map to usewhen orienting a directional HF antennatoward a distant station?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"90 degrees"},{"letter":"B","text":"270 degrees"},{"letter":"C","text":"180 degrees"},{"letter":"D","text":"45 degrees"}],"questionText":"A directional antenna pointed in the long-path direction to another station is generallyoriented how many degrees from its short-path heading?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A packet message"},{"letter":"B","text":"A signed post card listing contact date,time, frequency, mode and power, calleda \"QSL card\""},{"letter":"C","text":"A two-page letter containing a photographof the operator"},{"letter":"D","text":"A radiogram sent over the CW traffic net"}],"questionText":"What method is used by radio amateurs toprovide written proof of communicationbetween two amateur stations?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A log is important for recording contactsfor operating awards"},{"letter":"B","text":"A well-kept log preserves your fondestamateur radio memories for years"},{"letter":"C","text":"A log is important for handling neighbourinterference complaints"},{"letter":"D","text":"A logbook is required by Industry Canada"}],"questionText":"Which statement about recording allcontacts and unanswered \"CQ calls\" in astation logbook or computer log is notcorrect?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because it looks impressive"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because it shows the angle at which anamateur satellite crosses the equator"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because it shows the number of degreeslongitude that an amateur satellite moveswest"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because it shows the compass bearingfrom your station to any place on Earth,for antenna planning and pointing"}],"questionText":"Why would it be useful to have an azimuthalworld map centred on the location of yourstation?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Greenwich, England"},{"letter":"B","text":"Geneva, Switzerland"},{"letter":"C","text":"Ottawa, Canada"},{"letter":"D","text":"Newington, Connecticut"}],"questionText":"Station logs and confirmation (QSL) cardsare always kept in UTC (Universal TimeCoordinated). Where is that time based?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Universal Time Constant"},{"letter":"B","text":"Unlisted Telephone Call"},{"letter":"C","text":"Unlimited Time Capsule"},{"letter":"D","text":"Universal Time Coordinated (formerlyGreenwich Mean Time - GMT)"}],"questionText":"When referring to contacts in the station log,what do the letters UTC mean?"},{"questionId":"B-002-009-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"CHU, WWV or WWVH"},{"letter":"B","text":"A non-directional beacon station"},{"letter":"C","text":"Your local television station"},{"letter":"D","text":"Your local radio station"}],"questionText":"To set your station clock accurately to UTC,you could receive the most accurate time offthe air from _______?"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"as close as possible to the antenna tuneroutput"},{"letter":"B","text":"as close as possible to the antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"midway between the transceiver andantenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"as close as possible to the transceiveroutput"}],"questionText":"A low pass filter in an HF station is mosteffective when connected:"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"as close as possible to the linearamplifier output"},{"letter":"B","text":"as close as possible to the antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"as close as possible to the antenna tuneroutput"},{"letter":"D","text":"as close as possible to the linearamplifier input"}],"questionText":"A low pass filter in an HF station is mosteffective when connected:"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"SWR bridge"},{"letter":"B","text":"Low pass filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Dummy load"},{"letter":"D","text":"Antenna switch"}],"questionText":"In designing an HF station, whichcomponent would you use to reduce theeffects of harmonic radiation?"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Antenna switch"},{"letter":"B","text":"Transceiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"Low pass filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"SWR bridge"}],"questionText":"Of the components in an HF station, whichcomponent would normally be connectedclosest to the antenna, antenna tuner anddummy load?"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Antenna tuner"},{"letter":"B","text":"Antenna switch"},{"letter":"C","text":"Dummy load"},{"letter":"D","text":"SWR bridge"}],"questionText":"Of the components in an HF station, whichcomponent would be used to matchimpedances between the transceiver andantenna?"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Dummy load"},{"letter":"B","text":"SWR bridge"},{"letter":"C","text":"Low pass filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Antenna tuner"}],"questionText":"In an HF station, which component istemporarily connected in the tuning processor for adjustments to the transmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"tri-band Yagi antennas"},{"letter":"B","text":"most antennas when operating below 14MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"most antennas when operating above 14MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"mono-band Yagi type antennas"}],"questionText":"In an HF station, the antenna tuner isusually used for matching the transceiverwith:"},{"questionId":"B-003-001-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"with most antennas when operatingbelow 14 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"with most antennas when operatingabove 14 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"to tune into dummy loads"},{"letter":"D","text":"to tune low pass filters"}],"questionText":"In an HF Station, the antenna tuner iscommonly used:"},{"questionId":"B-003-002-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"frequency multiplier"},{"letter":"C","text":"microphone"},{"letter":"D","text":"modulator"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation transmitter, theinput to the speech amplifier is connected tothe:"},{"questionId":"B-003-002-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"speech amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"modulator"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation transmitter, themicrophone is connected to the:"},{"questionId":"B-003-002-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"microphone"},{"letter":"B","text":"frequency multiplier"},{"letter":"C","text":"modulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"power amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation transmitter, the____________is in between the speechamplifier and the oscillator."},{"questionId":"B-003-002-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"speech amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"microphone"},{"letter":"D","text":"oscillator"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation transmitter, the__________is located between themodulator and the frequency multiplier."},{"questionId":"B-003-002-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"modulator"},{"letter":"B","text":"speech amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"power amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation transmitter, the_________ is located between the frequencymultiplier and the antenna."},{"questionId":"B-003-002-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"frequency multiplier"},{"letter":"B","text":"microphone"},{"letter":"C","text":"modulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"antenna"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation transmitter, thepower amplifier output is connected to the:"},{"questionId":"B-003-003-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"C","text":"frequency discriminator"},{"letter":"D","text":"limiter"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver, the________is connected to the input of theradio frequency amplifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-003-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"audio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver, the__________ is in between the antenna andthe mixer."},{"questionId":"B-003-003-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"C","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"limiter"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver, theoutput of the local oscillator is fed to the:"},{"questionId":"B-003-003-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"speaker or headphones"},{"letter":"C","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"frequency discriminator"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver, theoutput of the ________is connected to themixer."},{"questionId":"B-003-003-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"limiter"},{"letter":"B","text":"frequency discriminator"},{"letter":"C","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"filter"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver,the_________ is in between the mixer andthe intermediate frequency amplifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-003-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"C","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver, the________ is located between the filter andthe limiter."},{"questionId":"B-003-003-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"limiter"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver,the__________ is in between theintermediate frequency amplifier and thefrequency discriminator."},{"questionId":"B-003-003-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"audio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"limiter"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver, the_________ is located between the speakeror headphones and the frequencydiscriminator."},{"questionId":"B-003-003-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"speaker or headphones"},{"letter":"B","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"frequency discriminator"},{"letter":"D","text":"limiter"}],"questionText":"In a frequency modulation receiver, the__________ connects to the audiofrequency amplifier output."},{"questionId":"B-003-004-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"master oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"telegraph key"},{"letter":"D","text":"power supply"}],"questionText":"In a CW transmitter, the output from the__________ is connected to the driver/buffer."},{"questionId":"B-003-004-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"master oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"power supply"},{"letter":"D","text":"driver/buffer"}],"questionText":"In a typical CW transmitter, the___________ is the primary source of directcurrent."},{"questionId":"B-003-004-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"power supply"},{"letter":"B","text":"telegraph key"},{"letter":"C","text":"driver/buffer"},{"letter":"D","text":"audio amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a CW transmitter, the_________ isbetween the master oscillator and the poweramplifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-004-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"driver/buffer"},{"letter":"B","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"telegraph key"},{"letter":"D","text":"master oscillator"}],"questionText":"In a CW transmitter, the_____________controls when RF energy is applied to theantenna."},{"questionId":"B-003-004-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"power supply"},{"letter":"C","text":"telegraph key"},{"letter":"D","text":"master oscillator"}],"questionText":"In a CW transmitter, the ______________ isin between the driver/buffer stage and theantenna."},{"questionId":"B-003-004-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"power amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"driver/buffer"},{"letter":"C","text":"power supply"},{"letter":"D","text":"master oscillator"}],"questionText":"In a CW transmitter, the output of the_____________ is transferred to theantenna."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"product detector"},{"letter":"C","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, theantenna is connected to the ____________ ."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"B","text":"beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"product detector"},{"letter":"D","text":"filter"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, the__________ is connected to the radiofrequency amplifier and the local oscillator."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"product detector"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, theoutput of the ___________ is connected tothe mixer."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"product detector"},{"letter":"D","text":"filter"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, the_____________ is in between the mixer andintermediate frequency amplifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"audio frequency amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, the__________ is in between the filter andproduct detector."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"product detector"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, the__________ output is connected to theaudio frequency amplifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"audio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"D","text":"radio frequency amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, theoutput of the ___________ is connected tothe product detector."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"intermediate frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"local oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"audio frequency amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, the__________ is connected to the output ofthe product detector."},{"questionId":"B-003-005-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"B","text":"radio frequency amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"beat frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"speaker or headphones"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband and CW receiver, the__________ is connected to the output ofthe audio frequency amplifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radio frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"variable frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"linear amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"mixer"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband transmitter, the outputof the ________ is connected to thebalanced modulator."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"radio frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"speech amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"microphone"},{"letter":"D","text":"filter"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband transmitter, the_____________ is in between the balancedmodulator and the mixer."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"microphone"},{"letter":"B","text":"radio frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"mixer"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband transmitter, the______________ is connected to thespeech amplifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"variable frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"linear amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"speech amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"filter"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband transmitter, the outputof the ___________ is connected to thebalanced modulator."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"mixer"},{"letter":"B","text":"antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"balanced modulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"linear amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband transmitter, the outputof the variable frequency oscillator isconnected to the __________."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"variable frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"radio frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"D","text":"linear amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband transmitter, the outputof the _________ is connected to the mixer."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"linear amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"variable frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"balanced modulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"radio frequency oscillator"}],"questionText":"In an single sideband transmitter, the____________ is in between the mixer andthe antenna."},{"questionId":"B-003-006-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"variable frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"speech amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"antenna"}],"questionText":"In a single sideband transmitter, the outputof the linear amplifier is connected to the______________."},{"questionId":"B-003-007-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"power supply"},{"letter":"C","text":"transceiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"input/output"}],"questionText":"In an amateur digital radio system, the__________________interfaces with thecomputer."},{"questionId":"B-003-007-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"computer"},{"letter":"B","text":"amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"input/output"}],"questionText":"In an amateur digital radio system, themodem is connected to the ________."},{"questionId":"B-003-007-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"transceiver"},{"letter":"B","text":"input/output"},{"letter":"C","text":"scanner"},{"letter":"D","text":"antenna"}],"questionText":"In an amateur digital radio system, the audioconnections of the modem/sound card areconnected to the ___________."},{"questionId":"B-003-007-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"keyboard"},{"letter":"B","text":"scanner"},{"letter":"C","text":"serial port"},{"letter":"D","text":"sound card"}],"questionText":"In an amateur digital radio system, themodem function is often performed by thecomputer____________ ."},{"questionId":"B-003-008-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"input"},{"letter":"B","text":"regulator"},{"letter":"C","text":"filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"rectifier"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, the transformerconnects to an external source which isreferred to as______________."},{"questionId":"B-003-008-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"output"},{"letter":"B","text":"regulator"},{"letter":"C","text":"filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"transformer"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, the_______________ is between the input andthe rectifier."},{"questionId":"B-003-008-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"input"},{"letter":"B","text":"output"},{"letter":"C","text":"regulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"rectifier"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, the_______________ is between thetransformer and the filter."},{"questionId":"B-003-008-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"output"},{"letter":"C","text":"transformer"},{"letter":"D","text":"regulator"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, the output ofthe rectifier is connected to the______________."},{"questionId":"B-003-008-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"rectifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"output"},{"letter":"C","text":"regulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"transformer"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, the output ofthe filter connects to the____________________."},{"questionId":"B-003-008-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"transformer"},{"letter":"B","text":"output"},{"letter":"C","text":"rectifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"input"}],"questionText":"In a regulated power supply, the_______________is connected to theregulator."},{"questionId":"B-003-009-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"driven element"},{"letter":"B","text":"director"},{"letter":"C","text":"boom"},{"letter":"D","text":"reflector"}],"questionText":"In a Yagi 3 element directional antenna, the____________ is primarily for mechanicalsupport purposes."},{"questionId":"B-003-009-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"boom"},{"letter":"B","text":"reflector"},{"letter":"C","text":"driven element"},{"letter":"D","text":"director"}],"questionText":"In a Yagi 3 element directional antenna, the______________ is the shortest radiatingelement."},{"questionId":"B-003-009-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"driven element"},{"letter":"B","text":"boom"},{"letter":"C","text":"director"},{"letter":"D","text":"reflector"}],"questionText":"In a Yagi 3 element directional antenna, the______________is not the longest nor theshortest radiating element."},{"questionId":"B-003-010-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"CW, SSB voice, RTTY, FM voice"},{"letter":"B","text":"CW, FM voice, RTTY, SSB voice"},{"letter":"C","text":"RTTY, CW, SSB voice, FM voice"},{"letter":"D","text":"CW, RTTY, SSB voice, FM voice"}],"questionText":"Which list of emission types is in order fromthe narrowest bandwidth to the widestbandwidth?"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"audio output in watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"bandwidth of the IF in kilohertz"},{"letter":"C","text":"number of RF amplifiers"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF input signal needed to achieve a givensignal plus noise to noise ratio"}],"questionText":"The figure in a receiver's specifications whichindicates its sensitivity is the:"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"less signal or more noise"},{"letter":"B","text":"a steady oscillator drift"},{"letter":"C","text":"more than one signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"more signal or less noise"}],"questionText":"If two receivers of different sensitivity arecompared, the less sensitive receiver willproduce:"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Single sideband suppressed carrier"},{"letter":"B","text":"Double sideband full carrier"},{"letter":"C","text":"Frequency modulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Pulse modulation"}],"questionText":"Which of the following modes oftransmission is usually detected with aproduct detector?"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"it phases out the unwanted sidebandsignal"},{"letter":"B","text":"the suppressed carrier must be replacedfor detection"},{"letter":"C","text":"it beats with the received carrier toproduce the other sideband"},{"letter":"D","text":"it reduces the passband of the IF stages"}],"questionText":"A receiver designed for SSB reception musthave a BFO (beat frequency oscillator)because:"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"7.435 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"3.995 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"3.54 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"455 kHz"}],"questionText":"A receiver receives an incoming signal of3.54 MHz, and the local oscillator producesa signal of 3.995 MHz. To which frequencyshould the IF be tuned?"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A pi-network filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A notch filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"A band pass filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"An all pass filter"}],"questionText":"What kind of filter would you use toattenuate an interfering carrier signal whilereceiving an SSB transmission?"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"250 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"6 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"500 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"2.4 kHz"}],"questionText":"A communications receiver has four filtersinstalled in it, respectively designated as250 Hz, 500 Hz, 2.4 kHz, and 6 kHz. If youwere listening to single sideband, which filterwould you utilize?"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2.4 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"6 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"250 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"500 Hz"}],"questionText":"A communications receiver has four filtersinstalled in it, respectively designated as250 Hz, 500 Hz, 2.4 kHz and 6 kHz. Youare copying a CW transmission and there isa great deal of interference. Which one ofthe filters would you choose?"},{"questionId":"B-003-010-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 - 1100 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"750 - 850 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"2100 - 2300 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 - 2700 Hz"}],"questionText":"Selectivity can be placed in the audio stagesof a receiver by the utilization of RC active orpassive audio filters. If you were to copyCW, which of the following bandpasseswould you choose?"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A high-pitched tone which is receivedalong with a CW signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"A slow change in transmitter frequencyas the circuit warms up"},{"letter":"C","text":"An overload in a receiver's audio circuitwhenever CW is received"},{"letter":"D","text":"A small change in a transmitter'sfrequency each time it is keyed"}],"questionText":"What does chirp mean?"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Keep the power supply voltages verysteady under transmit load"},{"letter":"B","text":"Add a key-click filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Keep the power supply current verysteady under transmit load"},{"letter":"D","text":"Add a low pass filter"}],"questionText":"What can be done to keep a CW transmitterfrom chirping?"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A single-sideband transmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A digital radio transmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"A VFO-controlled CW transmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A crystal-controlled AM transmitter"}],"questionText":"What circuit has a variable-frequencyoscillator connected to a buffer/driver and apower amplifier?"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Amplitude modulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Phase modulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Amplitude-rectification modulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Frequency modulation"}],"questionText":"What type of modulation system changesthe amplitude of an RF wave for the purposeof conveying information?"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Frequency shift keying"},{"letter":"B","text":"Amplitude modulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Frequency modulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Pulse modulation"}],"questionText":"In what emission type does theinstantaneous amplitude (envelope) of theRF signal vary in accordance with themodulating audio?"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the driver stage will not deliver power tothe final"},{"letter":"B","text":"the output tank circuit breaks down"},{"letter":"C","text":"full power will not be transferred to theantenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"loss of modulation in the transmittedsignal"}],"questionText":"A mismatched antenna or transmission linemay present an incorrect load to thetransmitter. The result may be:"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"lower modulation percentage"},{"letter":"B","text":"radiated key-clicks"},{"letter":"C","text":"reduced antenna radiation"},{"letter":"D","text":"smaller DC current drain"}],"questionText":"One result of a slight mismatch between thepower amplifier of a transmitter and theantenna would be:"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"become over modulated"},{"letter":"B","text":"generate key-clicks"},{"letter":"C","text":"cause undue distortion"},{"letter":"D","text":"drift in frequency"}],"questionText":"An RF oscillator should be electrically andmechanically stable. This is to ensure thatthe oscillator does not:"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It has been used to provide positivefeedback"},{"letter":"B","text":"It has been dissipated as heat loss"},{"letter":"C","text":"It has been used to provide greaterefficiency"},{"letter":"D","text":"It has been used to provide negativefeedback"}],"questionText":"The input power to the final stage of yourtransmitter is 200 watts and the output is125 watts. What has happened to theremaining power?"},{"questionId":"B-003-011-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"is due to oscillating"},{"letter":"B","text":"radiates from the antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"appears as heat dissipation"},{"letter":"D","text":"is lost in the transmission line"}],"questionText":"The difference between DC input power andRF output power of a transmitter RFamplifier:"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It may cause atmospheric interference inthe air around the antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"It may cause digital interference tocomputer equipment"},{"letter":"C","text":"It may cause splatter interference toother stations operating near itsfrequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"It may cause interference to otherstations operating on a higher frequencyband"}],"questionText":"What may happen if an SSB transmitter isoperated with the microphone gain set toohigh?"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It may cause atmospheric interference inthe air around the antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"It may cause interference to otherstations operating on a higher frequencyband"},{"letter":"C","text":"It may cause audio distortion or splatterinterference to other stations operatingnear its frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"It may cause digital interference tocomputer equipment"}],"questionText":"What may happen if an SSB transmitter isoperated with too much speech processing?"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Peak transmitter power"},{"letter":"B","text":"Peak envelope power"},{"letter":"C","text":"Peak output power"},{"letter":"D","text":"Average radio-frequency power"}],"questionText":"What is the term for the average powersupplied to an antenna transmission lineduring one RF cycle, at the crest of themodulation envelope?"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Carrier oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"Filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"IF amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF amplifier"}],"questionText":"In a typical single-sideband phonetransmitter, what circuit processes signalsfrom the balanced modulator and sendssignals to the mixer?"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only half the bandwidth is required for thesame information content"},{"letter":"B","text":"Greater modulation percentage isobtainable with lower distortion"},{"letter":"C","text":"Simpler equipment can be used toreceive a double-sideband suppressed-carrier signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"More power can be put into thesidebands for a given power amplifiercapacity"}],"questionText":"What is one advantage of carriersuppression in a double-sideband phonetransmission?"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It occupies less bandwidth with poorhigh-frequency response"},{"letter":"B","text":"It has higher fidelity and improved signal-to-noise ratio"},{"letter":"C","text":"It becomes distorted and occupies morebandwidth"},{"letter":"D","text":"It becomes stronger with no other effects"}],"questionText":"What happens to the signal of anovermodulated single-sideband or double-sideband phone transmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"For a dip in plate current"},{"letter":"B","text":"For slight movement of the ALC meter onmodulation peaks"},{"letter":"C","text":"For full deflection of the ALC meter onmodulation peaks"},{"letter":"D","text":"For 100% frequency deviation onmodulation peaks"}],"questionText":"How should the microphone gain control beadjusted on a single-sideband phonetransmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ensure that the percentage of modulationis kept constant"},{"letter":"B","text":"make sure that the carrier and bothsidebands are in phase"},{"letter":"C","text":"suppress the carrier and pass on the twosidebands"},{"letter":"D","text":"make sure that the carrier and bothsidebands are 180 degrees out of phase"}],"questionText":"The purpose of a balanced modulator in anSSB transmitter is to:"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inserted at the transmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"of no use at the receiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"reinserted at the receiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"transmitted with one sideband"}],"questionText":"In a SSB transmission, the carrier is:"},{"questionId":"B-003-012-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"reduces transmitter audio feedback"},{"letter":"B","text":"increases the occupied bandwidth"},{"letter":"C","text":"reduces the system noise"},{"letter":"D","text":"controls the peak audio input so that thepower amplifier is not overdriven"}],"questionText":"The automatic level control (ALC) in a SSBtransmitter:"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It may cause atmospheric interference inthe air around the antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"It may cause interference to otherstations operating on a higher frequencyband"},{"letter":"C","text":"It may cause interference to otherstations operating near its frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"It may cause digital interference tocomputer equipment"}],"questionText":"What may your FM hand-held or mobiletransceiver do if you shout into itsmicrophone and the deviation adjustment isset too high?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Let the transceiver cool off"},{"letter":"B","text":"Change to a higher power level"},{"letter":"C","text":"Talk farther away from the microphone"},{"letter":"D","text":"Talk louder into the microphone"}],"questionText":"What can you do if you are told your FMhand-held or mobile transceiver isoverdeviating?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A frequency-modulated carrier"},{"letter":"B","text":"An amplitude-modulated carrier"},{"letter":"C","text":"A phase-modulated carrier"},{"letter":"D","text":"An unmodulated carrier"}],"questionText":"What kind of emission would your FMtransmitter produce if its microphone failedto work?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The carrier is not detectable"},{"letter":"B","text":"It is more resistant to distortion causedby reflected signals"},{"letter":"C","text":"Its RF carrier stays on frequency betterthan the AM modes"},{"letter":"D","text":"It provides good signal plus noise tonoise ratio at low RF signal levels"}],"questionText":"Why is FM voice best for local VHF/UHFradio communications?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Between 5 and 10 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"Greater than 20 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"Between 10 and 20 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"Less than 5 kHz"}],"questionText":"What is the usual bandwidth of a frequency-modulated amateur signal for +/- 5kHzdeviation?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Increased transmitter power"},{"letter":"B","text":"Increased transmitter range"},{"letter":"C","text":"Poor carrier suppression"},{"letter":"D","text":"Out-of-channel emissions"}],"questionText":"What is the result of overdeviation in an FMtransmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Amplitude modulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Pulse modulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Phase modulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Multiplex modulation"}],"questionText":"What emission is produced by a reactancemodulator connected to an RF poweramplifier?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The frequency deviation of yourtransmitter is set too high"},{"letter":"B","text":"The power supply output voltage is low"},{"letter":"C","text":"The repeater is reversing your sidebands"},{"letter":"D","text":"The frequency counter is giving anincorrect reading and you are indeed offfrequency"}],"questionText":"You are transmitting FM on the 2 metreband. Several stations advise you that yourtransmission is loud and distorted. A quickcheck with a frequency counter tells youthat the transmitter is on the properfrequency. Which of the following is themost probable cause of the distortion?"},{"questionId":"B-003-013-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"interference effect"},{"letter":"B","text":"surrender effect"},{"letter":"C","text":"capture effect"},{"letter":"D","text":"attach effect"}],"questionText":"FM receivers perform in an unusual mannerwhen two or more stations are present. Thestrongest signal, even though it is only twoor three times stronger than the othersignals, will be the only transmissiondemodulated. This is called:"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An electronic keyer"},{"letter":"B","text":"A key-operated on/off switch"},{"letter":"C","text":"A notch filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A DTMF keypad"}],"questionText":"What do many amateurs use to help formgood Morse code characters?"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To an antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"To a transceiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"To a power supply"},{"letter":"D","text":"To an antenna switch"}],"questionText":"Where would you connect a microphone forvoice operation?"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A receiver audio filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A terminal-voice controller"},{"letter":"C","text":"A splatter filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A microphone"}],"questionText":"What would you connect to a transceiver forvoice operation?"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because it stores electric current"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because it changes RF energy into heat"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because it absorbs static electricity"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because it stores radio waves"}],"questionText":"Why might a dummy antenna get warmwhen in use?"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"VCO"},{"letter":"B","text":"VFO"},{"letter":"C","text":"VOX"},{"letter":"D","text":"VXO"}],"questionText":"What is the circuit called which causes atransmitter to automatically transmit whenan operator speaks into its microphone?"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It improves signal intelligibility at thereceiver"},{"letter":"B","text":"It reduces average transmitter powerrequirements"},{"letter":"C","text":"It reduces unwanted noise pickup fromthe microphone"},{"letter":"D","text":"It improves voice frequency fidelity"}],"questionText":"What is the reason for using a properlyadjusted speech processor with a single-sideband phone transmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It will decrease the average power output"},{"letter":"B","text":"It will add nothing to the output PeakEnvelope Power (PEP)"},{"letter":"C","text":"It will increase the output PEP"},{"letter":"D","text":"It will decrease the peak power output"}],"questionText":"If a single-sideband phone transmitter is100% modulated, what will a speechprocessor do to the transmitter's power?"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"switch between meters"},{"letter":"B","text":"disconnect the antenna tuner"},{"letter":"C","text":"disable the unit not being used"},{"letter":"D","text":"ground the antenna on receive"}],"questionText":"A switching system to enable the use of oneantenna for a transmitter and receiver shouldalso:"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"to allow more than one transmitter to beused"},{"letter":"B","text":"so that one antenna can be used fortransmitter and receiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"to change antennas for operation on otherfrequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"to prevent RF currents entering thereceiver circuits"}],"questionText":"An antenna changeover switch in atransmitter-receiver combination isnecessary:"},{"questionId":"B-003-014-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Resistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"Capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"Loudspeaker"},{"letter":"D","text":"Crystal earpiece"}],"questionText":"Which of the following components could beused as a dynamic microphone?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A transmitting and receiving station areusing a digipeater, so no other contactscan take place until they are finished"},{"letter":"B","text":"A transmitting station is sending data toonly one receiving station, it replies thatthe data is being received correctly"},{"letter":"C","text":"A telephone link is working between twostations"},{"letter":"D","text":"A message has reached an amateurstation for local delivery"}],"questionText":"What does \"connected\" mean in an AX.25packet-radio link?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Industry Canada is monitoring allmessages"},{"letter":"B","text":"A receiving station is displayingmessages that may not be sent to it, andis not replying to any message"},{"letter":"C","text":"A member of the Amateur Auxiliary iscopying all messages"},{"letter":"D","text":"A receiving station is displaying allmessages sent to it, and replying thatthe messages are being receivedcorrectly"}],"questionText":"What does \"monitoring\" mean on a packet-radio frequency?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A station that retransmits only data thatis marked to be retransmitted"},{"letter":"B","text":"A repeater built using only digitalelectronics parts"},{"letter":"C","text":"A repeater that changes audio signals todigital data"},{"letter":"D","text":"A station that retransmits any data that itreceives"}],"questionText":"What is a digipeater?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The connections on terminal-nodecontrollers"},{"letter":"B","text":"The programming in a terminal-nodecontroller that rejects other callers if astation is already connected"},{"letter":"C","text":"A way of connecting packet-radiostations so data can be sent over longdistances"},{"letter":"D","text":"A way of connecting terminal-nodecontrollers by telephone so data can besent over long distances"}],"questionText":"What does \"network\" mean in packet radio?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Connect a terminal-node controller tointerrupt the transceiver's carrier wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"Connect a keyboard to the transceiver'smicrophone input"},{"letter":"C","text":"Connect a DTMF key pad to thetransceiver's microphone input"},{"letter":"D","text":"Connect a terminal-node controller to thetransceiver's microphone input"}],"questionText":"How would you modulate a 2 meter FMtransceiver to produce packet-radioemissions?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"250 to 500 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"Approximately 6 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"Approximately 3 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"60 Hz"}],"questionText":"When selecting a RTTY transmittingfrequency, what minimum frequencyseparation from a contact in progress shouldyou allow (center to center) to minimizeinterference?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"packet and AMTOR"},{"letter":"B","text":"Baudot and ASCII"},{"letter":"C","text":"dot and dash"},{"letter":"D","text":"mark and space"}],"questionText":"Digital transmissions use signals called__________ to transmit the states 1 and 0:"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Automatic Packet Reporting System(APRS)"},{"letter":"B","text":"AX.25"},{"letter":"C","text":"Baudot"},{"letter":"D","text":"ASCII"}],"questionText":"Which of the following terms does not applyto packet radio?"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"only when communications have beencompleted"},{"letter":"B","text":"when making a general call"},{"letter":"C","text":"for communications after contact hasbeen established"},{"letter":"D","text":"at all times. Mode B is for test purposesonly"}],"questionText":"When using AMTOR transmissions, thereare two modes that may be utilized. Mode Auses Automatic Repeat Request (ARQ)protocol and is normally used:"},{"questionId":"B-003-015-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Splatter or out-of-channel emissions"},{"letter":"B","text":"Higher signal-to-noise ratio"},{"letter":"C","text":"Lower error rate"},{"letter":"D","text":"Power amplifier overheating"}],"questionText":"With a digital communication mode basedon a computer sound card, what is the resultof feeding too much audio in the transceiver?"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"About 12 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"About 240 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"About 120 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"About 9 volts"}],"questionText":"How much voltage does a standardautomobile battery usually supply?"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A potentiometer"},{"letter":"B","text":"A fuse"},{"letter":"C","text":"A resistor"},{"letter":"D","text":"A battery"}],"questionText":"Which component has a positive and anegative side?"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"P channel FET"},{"letter":"B","text":"carbon resistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"lithium-ion battery"},{"letter":"D","text":"germanium diode"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is a source ofelectromotive force (EMF)?"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"has two terminals"},{"letter":"B","text":"can be completely discharged"},{"letter":"C","text":"contains an electrolyte"},{"letter":"D","text":"can be repeatedly recharged"}],"questionText":"An important difference between aconventional flashlight battery and a leadacid battery is that only the lead acidbattery:"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"electrolyte becoming dry"},{"letter":"B","text":"current capacity"},{"letter":"C","text":"voltage capacity"},{"letter":"D","text":"internal resistance"}],"questionText":"An alkaline cell has a nominal voltage of 1.5volts. When supplying a great deal ofcurrent, the voltage may drop to 1.2 volts.This is caused by the cell's:"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"many times"},{"letter":"B","text":"once"},{"letter":"C","text":"never"},{"letter":"D","text":"twice"}],"questionText":"An inexpensive primary cell in use today isthe carbon-zinc or flashlight cell. This type ofcell can be recharged:"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The voltage delivered will be higher"},{"letter":"B","text":"A battery charge will not last as long"},{"letter":"C","text":"The internal resistance of the cell isshort-circuited"},{"letter":"D","text":"The battery will accept the subsequentcharge in shorter time"}],"questionText":"Battery capacity is commonly stated as avalue of current delivered over a specifiedperiod of time. What is the effect ofexceeding that specified current?"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"series resonant"},{"letter":"B","text":"parallel"},{"letter":"C","text":"series"},{"letter":"D","text":"parallel resonant"}],"questionText":"To increase the current capacity of a cell,several cells should be connected in:"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"resonance"},{"letter":"B","text":"series"},{"letter":"C","text":"parallel"},{"letter":"D","text":"series-parallel"}],"questionText":"To increase the voltage output, several cellsare connected in:"},{"questionId":"B-003-016-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"recharged"},{"letter":"B","text":"left disconnected"},{"letter":"C","text":"left overnight at room temperature"},{"letter":"D","text":"short-circuited"}],"questionText":"A lithium-ion battery should never be:"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The power supply"},{"letter":"B","text":"The speaker"},{"letter":"C","text":"The microphone"},{"letter":"D","text":"The SWR meter"}],"questionText":"If your mobile transceiver works in your carbut not in your home, what should youcheck first?"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A low pass filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"An RS-232 interface"},{"letter":"C","text":"A catalytic converter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A power supply"}],"questionText":"What device converts household current to12 volts DC?"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Bad design of the transmitter's RF poweroutput circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"A bad filter capacitor in the transmitter'spower supply"},{"letter":"C","text":"Using an antenna which is the wronglength"},{"letter":"D","text":"Energy from another transmitter"}],"questionText":"What may cause a buzzing or hum in thesignal of an AC-powered transmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"60 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"17 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.4 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"6 watts"}],"questionText":"A power supply is to supply DC at 12 voltsat 5 amperes. The power transformer shouldbe rated higher than:"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"allows electrons to flow in only onedirection from anode to cathode"},{"letter":"B","text":"allows electrons to flow in only onedirection from cathode to anode"},{"letter":"C","text":"has a high resistance to AC but not toDC"},{"letter":"D","text":"has a high resistance to DC but not toAC"}],"questionText":"The diode is an important part of a simplepower supply. It converts AC to DC, since it:"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"transformer"},{"letter":"B","text":"capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"resistor"},{"letter":"D","text":"diode"}],"questionText":"To convert AC to pulsating DC, you coulduse a:"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 and 200 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"130 and 260 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"120 and 240 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"110 and 220 volts"}],"questionText":"Power-line voltages have been madestandard over the years and the voltagesgenerally supplied to homes areapproximately:"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Number 8, 0.05 V per metre (0.01 V perfoot)"},{"letter":"B","text":"Number 10, 0.07 V per metre (0.02 V perfoot)"},{"letter":"C","text":"Number 14, 0.19 V per metre (0.06 V perfoot)"},{"letter":"D","text":"Number 12, 0.11 V per metre (0.03 V perfoot)"}],"questionText":"Your mobile HF transceiver draws 22amperes on transmit. The manufacturersuggests limiting voltage drop to 0.5 volt andthe vehicle battery is 3 metres (10 feet)away. Given the losses below at thatcurrent, which minimum wire gauge mustyou use?"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To protect the radio from transientvoltages"},{"letter":"B","text":"To prevent an overcurrent situation fromstarting a fire"},{"letter":"C","text":"To prevent interference to the vehicle'selectronic systems"},{"letter":"D","text":"To reduce the voltage drop in the radio'sDC supply"}],"questionText":"Why are fuses needed as close as possibleto the vehicle battery when wiring atransceiver directly to the battery?"},{"questionId":"B-003-017-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The power supply"},{"letter":"B","text":"The variable-frequency oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"The driver circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"The power amplifier circuit"}],"questionText":"You have a very loud low-frequency humappearing on your transmission. In what partof the transmitter would you first look for thetrouble?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Put a \"Do not touch\" sign on the radio"},{"letter":"B","text":"Disconnect the microphone when you arenot using it"},{"letter":"C","text":"Tune the radio to an unused frequencywhen you are done using it"},{"letter":"D","text":"Turn the radio off when you are not usingit"}],"questionText":"How could you best keep unauthorizedpersons from using a mobile amateur stationin your car?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"For safety, to turn off the station in theevent of an emergency"},{"letter":"B","text":"To keep unauthorized persons from usingyour station"},{"letter":"C","text":"For safety, in case the main fuses fail"},{"letter":"D","text":"To keep the power company from turningoff your electricity during an emergency"}],"questionText":"Why would you use a key-operated on/offswitch in the main power line of yourstation?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To turn the power supply off when it is notbeing used"},{"letter":"B","text":"To keep anyone opening the cabinet fromgetting shocked by dangerous highvoltages"},{"letter":"C","text":"To keep dangerous RF radiation fromleaking out through an open cabinet"},{"letter":"D","text":"To keep dangerous RF radiation fromcoming in through an open cabinet"}],"questionText":"Why would there be a switch in a high-voltage power supply to turn off the power ifits cabinet is opened?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Approximately 10 amperes"},{"letter":"B","text":"More than 20 amperes"},{"letter":"C","text":"Current flow through the human body isnever fatal"},{"letter":"D","text":"As little as 20 milliamperes"}],"questionText":"How little electrical current flowing throughthe human body can be fatal?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The heart"},{"letter":"B","text":"The brain"},{"letter":"C","text":"The liver"},{"letter":"D","text":"The lungs"}],"questionText":"Which body organ can be fatally affected bya very small amount of electrical current?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"1000 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"2000 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"30 volts"}],"questionText":"What is the minimum voltage which isusually dangerous to humans?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Wait for a few minutes to see if theperson can get away from the highvoltage on their own, then try to help"},{"letter":"B","text":"Immediately drag the person away fromthe high voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"Run from the area so you won't be burnedtoo"},{"letter":"D","text":"Turn off the power, call for emergencyhelp and provide first-aid if needed"}],"questionText":"What should you do if you discoversomeone who is being burned by highvoltage?"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"turn off the power and remove power plug"},{"letter":"B","text":"short out leads of filter capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"check action of capacitor bleederresistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"remove and check fuse from powersupply"}],"questionText":"Before checking a fault in a mains operatedpower supply unit, it would be safest to first:"},{"questionId":"B-003-018-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"electric shock"},{"letter":"B","text":"damaging the transmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"overmodulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"blowing the fuse"}],"questionText":"Fault finding in a power supply of an amateurtransmitter while the supply is operating isnot a recommended technique because ofthe risk of:"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"All station equipment"},{"letter":"B","text":"The antenna transmission line"},{"letter":"C","text":"The AC power line"},{"letter":"D","text":"The power supply primary"}],"questionText":"For best protection from electrical shock,what should be grounded in an amateurstation?"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a plastic cold water pipe"},{"letter":"B","text":"a window screen"},{"letter":"C","text":"a metallic natural gas pipe"},{"letter":"D","text":"a metallic cold water pipe"}],"questionText":"If a separate ground system is not possiblefor your amateur station, an alternativeindoor grounding point could be:"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a good ground connection"},{"letter":"B","text":"a dummy load"},{"letter":"C","text":"insulated shock mounts"},{"letter":"D","text":"the antenna"}],"questionText":"To protect you against electrical shock, thechassis of each piece of your stationequipment should be connected to:"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Copper-clad steel"},{"letter":"B","text":"Hard plastic"},{"letter":"C","text":"Iron or steel"},{"letter":"D","text":"Fiberglass"}],"questionText":"Which of these materials is best for aground rod driven into the earth?"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The station ground system must conformto applicable electrical code requirements"},{"letter":"B","text":"1.2 metre (4 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.5 metres (8 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"3 metres (10 ft)"}],"questionText":"If you ground your station equipment to aground rod driven into the earth, what is theshortest length the rod should be?"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To the white wire"},{"letter":"B","text":"To the \"hot\" side of the power switch"},{"letter":"C","text":"To the fuse"},{"letter":"D","text":"To the chassis"}],"questionText":"Where should the green wire in a three-wireAC line cord be connected in a powersupply?"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Drive the ground rod at least 4m (14 feet)into the ground"},{"letter":"B","text":"Use a beryllium ground wire for bestconductivity"},{"letter":"C","text":"Keep the station's ground wire as shortas possible"},{"letter":"D","text":"Make a couple of loops in the ground wirewhere it connects to your station"}],"questionText":"What is one good way to avoid stray RFenergy in your amateur station?"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A ground loop is an effective way toground station equipment"},{"letter":"B","text":"If the chassis of all station equipment isconnected with a good conductor, thereis no need to tie them to an earth ground"},{"letter":"C","text":"The chassis of each piece of stationequipment should be tied together withhigh-impedance conductors"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF hot spots can occur in a stationlocated above the ground floor if theequipment is grounded by a long groundwire"}],"questionText":"Which statement about station grounding istrue?"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"develops a high voltage compared to theground"},{"letter":"B","text":"does not develop a high voltage withrespect to the ground"},{"letter":"C","text":"does not become conductive to preventelectric shock"},{"letter":"D","text":"becomes conductive to prevent electricshock"}],"questionText":"On mains operated power supplies, theground wire should be connected to themetal chassis of the power supply. Thisensures, in case there is a fault in the powersupply, that the chassis:"},{"questionId":"B-003-019-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"prevent the chassis from becoming live"},{"letter":"B","text":"prevent the plug from being reversed inthe wall outlet"},{"letter":"C","text":"prevent internal short circuits"},{"letter":"D","text":"make it inconvenient to use"}],"questionText":"The purpose of using a three-wire power cordand plug on amateur radio equipment is to:"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To make sure everything will stay inplace"},{"letter":"B","text":"To help protect the station equipment andbuilding from lightning damage"},{"letter":"C","text":"To lock the antenna system in oneposition"},{"letter":"D","text":"To avoid radio frequency interference"}],"questionText":"Why should you ground all antenna androtator cables when your amateur station isnot in use?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Outside, as close to earth grounding aspossible"},{"letter":"B","text":"Close to the antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"Behind the transceiver"},{"letter":"D","text":"Anywhere on the line"}],"questionText":"You want to install a lightning arrestor onyour antenna transmission line, whereshould it be inserted?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Disconnect the ground system from allradios"},{"letter":"B","text":"Disconnect all equipment from the powerlines and antenna cables"},{"letter":"C","text":"Use heavy insulation on the wiring"},{"letter":"D","text":"Never turn off the equipment"}],"questionText":"How can amateur station equipment best beprotected from lightning damage?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To safely hold your tools so they don't falland injure someone on the ground"},{"letter":"B","text":"To prevent you from accidentally falling"},{"letter":"C","text":"To safely bring any tools you might useup and down the tower"},{"letter":"D","text":"To keep the tower from becomingunbalanced while you are working"}],"questionText":"Why should you wear approved fall arrestequipment if you are working on an antennatower?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Just high enough so you can easily reachit for adjustments or repairs"},{"letter":"B","text":"As close to the ground as possible"},{"letter":"C","text":"High enough so that no one can touchany part of it from the ground"},{"letter":"D","text":"Above high-voltage electrical lines"}],"questionText":"For safety, how high should you place ahorizontal wire antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To protect your head from somethingdropped from the tower"},{"letter":"B","text":"So you won't be hurt if the tower shouldaccidentally fall"},{"letter":"C","text":"To keep RF energy away from your headduring antenna testing"},{"letter":"D","text":"So someone passing by will know thatwork is being done on the tower and willstay away"}],"questionText":"Why should you wear a hard hat if you areon the ground helping someone work on anantenna tower?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Touching the antenna might reflect thesignal back to the transmitter and causedamage"},{"letter":"B","text":"Touching the antenna might radiateharmonics"},{"letter":"C","text":"Touching the antenna might causetelevision interference"},{"letter":"D","text":"Touching the antenna might cause RFburns"}],"questionText":"Why should your outside antennas be highenough so that no one can touch them whileyou are transmitting?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because contact might cause a shortcircuit and damage the transmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because high-voltage radio energy mightburn the person"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because contact might break thetransmission line"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because contact might cause spuriousemissions"}],"questionText":"Why should you make sure that no one cantouch an open wire transmission line whileyou are transmitting with it?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Be sure to turn off the transmitter anddisconnect the transmission line"},{"letter":"B","text":"Be sure you and the antenna structureare grounded"},{"letter":"C","text":"Inform your neighbours so they are awareof your intentions"},{"letter":"D","text":"Turn off the main power switch in yourhouse"}],"questionText":"What safety precautions should you takebefore beginning repairs on an antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-003-020-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It should be installed so no one cancome in contact with it"},{"letter":"B","text":"It should be painted so people or animalsdo not accidentally run into it"},{"letter":"C","text":"It should not be installed in a wet area"},{"letter":"D","text":"It should not be installed higher than youcan reach"}],"questionText":"What precaution should you take wheninstalling a ground-mounted antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Make sure the antenna is near theground to keep its RF energy pointing inthe correct direction"},{"letter":"B","text":"Make sure you connect an RF leakagefilter at the antenna feed point"},{"letter":"C","text":"Make sure that RF field screens are inplace"},{"letter":"D","text":"Make sure the antenna will be in a placewhere no one can get near it when youare transmitting"}],"questionText":"What should you do for safety if you put upa UHF transmitting antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Make sure the amplifier cannotaccidentally be turned on"},{"letter":"B","text":"Make sure that RF leakage filters areconnected"},{"letter":"C","text":"Make sure the antenna transmission lineis properly grounded"},{"letter":"D","text":"Make sure all RF screens are in place atthe antenna transmission line"}],"questionText":"What should you do for safety, beforeremoving the shielding on a UHF poweramplifier?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To keep static charges from building up"},{"letter":"B","text":"To help the antenna radiate energyequally in all directions"},{"letter":"C","text":"To reduce your exposure to the radio-frequency energy"},{"letter":"D","text":"To use your body to reflect the signal inone direction"}],"questionText":"Why should you make sure the antenna of ahand-held transceiver is not close to yourhead when transmitting?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Pointed away from the station you arecontacting"},{"letter":"B","text":"Pointed down to bounce the signal off theground"},{"letter":"C","text":"Away from your head and away fromothers"},{"letter":"D","text":"Pointed towards the station you arecontacting"}],"questionText":"How should you position the antenna of ahand-held transceiver while you aretransmitting?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It lowers blood pressure"},{"letter":"B","text":"It paralyzes the tissue"},{"letter":"C","text":"It causes hair to fall out"},{"letter":"D","text":"It heats the tissue"}],"questionText":"How can exposure to a large amount of RFenergy affect body tissue?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Heart"},{"letter":"B","text":"Liver"},{"letter":"C","text":"Hands"},{"letter":"D","text":"Eyes"}],"questionText":"Which body organ is the most likely to bedamaged from the heating effects of RFradiation?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It causes ionizing radiation poisoning"},{"letter":"B","text":"It causes blood flow to stop"},{"letter":"C","text":"It has no effect on the body"},{"letter":"D","text":"It heats the tissue"}],"questionText":"Depending on the wavelength of the signal,the energy density of the RF field, and otherfactors, in what way can RF energy affectbody tissue?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"So they will not direct RF energy towardpeople in nearby structures"},{"letter":"B","text":"So they will be dried by the wind after aheavy rain storm"},{"letter":"C","text":"So they will not damage nearbystructures with RF energy"},{"letter":"D","text":"So they will receive more sky waves andfewer ground waves"}],"questionText":"Why should directional high-gain antennasbe mounted higher than nearby structures?"},{"questionId":"B-003-021-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"As close to the transmitter as possibleso RF energy will be concentrated nearthe transmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Close to the ground so simpleadjustments can be easily made withoutclimbing a ladder"},{"letter":"C","text":"As high as possible to prevent peoplefrom coming in contact with the antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"Near or over moist ground so RF energywill be radiated away from the ground"}],"questionText":"For best RF safety, where should the endsand center of a dipole antenna be located?"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a receiver"},{"letter":"B","text":"an amplifier"},{"letter":"C","text":"a modulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"an oscillator"}],"questionText":"A circuit designed to increase the level of itsinput signal is called:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"cause oscillations"},{"letter":"B","text":"overload the power supply"},{"letter":"C","text":"become distorted"},{"letter":"D","text":"be saturated"}],"questionText":"If an amplifier becomes non-linear, theoutput signal would:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an RF oscillator"},{"letter":"B","text":"an audio oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"an audio amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"an RF amplifier"}],"questionText":"To increase the level of very weak radiosignals from an antenna, you would use:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an RF amplifier"},{"letter":"B","text":"an audio oscillator"},{"letter":"C","text":"an audio amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"an RF oscillator"}],"questionText":"To increase the level of very weak signalsfrom a microphone you would use:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3 to 300 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"300 to 1000 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"40 to 40 000 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 to 3000 Hz"}],"questionText":"The range of frequencies to be amplified by aspeech amplifier is typically:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Resistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Current"},{"letter":"C","text":"Power"},{"letter":"D","text":"Voltage"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not amplified by anamplifier?"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"modulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"gain"},{"letter":"C","text":"attenuation"},{"letter":"D","text":"amplitude"}],"questionText":"The increase in signal level by an amplifier iscalled:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"oscillation"},{"letter":"B","text":"modulation"},{"letter":"C","text":"amplification"},{"letter":"D","text":"attenuation"}],"questionText":"A device with gain has the property of:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"voltage, current, or power"},{"letter":"B","text":"current, power, or inductance"},{"letter":"C","text":"voltage, power, or inductance"},{"letter":"D","text":"voltage, current, or inductance"}],"questionText":"Amplifiers can amplify:"},{"questionId":"B-004-001-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Linearity"},{"letter":"B","text":"Distortion"},{"letter":"C","text":"Loss"},{"letter":"D","text":"Gain"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not a property of anamplifier?"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"AF detectors"},{"letter":"B","text":"voltage regulators"},{"letter":"C","text":"current regulators"},{"letter":"D","text":"RF detectors"}],"questionText":"Zener diodes are used as:"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ionization"},{"letter":"B","text":"biasing"},{"letter":"C","text":"demodulation"},{"letter":"D","text":"regeneration"}],"questionText":"One important application for diodes isrecovering information from transmittedsignals. This is referred to as:"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"provide a voltage phase shift"},{"letter":"B","text":"to boost the power supply voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"provide a path through which current canflow"},{"letter":"D","text":"regulate or maintain a constant voltage"}],"questionText":"The primary purpose of a Zener diode is to:"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"modulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"rectification"},{"letter":"C","text":"amplification"},{"letter":"D","text":"transformation"}],"questionText":"The action of changing alternating current todirect current is called:"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"cathode and drain"},{"letter":"B","text":"anode and cathode"},{"letter":"C","text":"gate and source"},{"letter":"D","text":"collector and base"}],"questionText":"The electrodes of a semiconductor diode areknown as:"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Steady direct current"},{"letter":"B","text":"Pulsating alternating current"},{"letter":"C","text":"Pulsating direct current"},{"letter":"D","text":"No signal"}],"questionText":"If alternating current is applied to the anodeof a diode, what would you expect to see atthe cathode?"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"cathode to grid"},{"letter":"B","text":"grid to anode"},{"letter":"C","text":"cathode to anode"},{"letter":"D","text":"anode to cathode"}],"questionText":"In a semiconductor diode, electrons flowfrom:"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A neon bulb"},{"letter":"B","text":"A vacuum diode"},{"letter":"C","text":"A light-emitting diode"},{"letter":"D","text":"A fluorescent bulb"}],"questionText":"What semiconductor device glows differentcolours, depending upon its chemicalcomposition?"},{"questionId":"B-004-002-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Zener diode"},{"letter":"B","text":"junction diode"},{"letter":"C","text":"light-emitting diode"},{"letter":"D","text":"vacuum diode"}],"questionText":"Voltage regulation is the principal applicationof the:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A variable resistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"An electrolytic capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"A multiple-cell battery"},{"letter":"D","text":"A PNP transistor"}],"questionText":"Which component can amplify a smallsignal using low voltages?"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"transistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"tube"},{"letter":"C","text":"P-N junction"},{"letter":"D","text":"diode"}],"questionText":"The basic semiconductor amplifying deviceis the:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"collector, source and drain"},{"letter":"B","text":"gate, source and drain"},{"letter":"C","text":"collector, emitter and base"},{"letter":"D","text":"drain, base and source"}],"questionText":"The three leads from a PNP transistor arenamed:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"modulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"rectification"},{"letter":"C","text":"amplification"},{"letter":"D","text":"detection"}],"questionText":"If a low level signal is placed at the input to atransistor, a higher level of signal isproduced at the output lead. This effect isknown as:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2 leads"},{"letter":"B","text":"4 leads"},{"letter":"C","text":"3 leads"},{"letter":"D","text":"1 lead"}],"questionText":"Bipolar transistors usually have:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a bipolar transistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"a silicon diode"},{"letter":"C","text":"a triode"},{"letter":"D","text":"an audio detector"}],"questionText":"A semiconductor is described as a \"generalpurpose audio NPN device\". This would be:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"diode and triode types"},{"letter":"B","text":"varicap and Zener types"},{"letter":"C","text":"P and N channel types"},{"letter":"D","text":"NPN and PNP types"}],"questionText":"The two basic types of bipolar transistorsare:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"saturation"},{"letter":"B","text":"cut-off"},{"letter":"C","text":"excessive heat"},{"letter":"D","text":"excessive light"}],"questionText":"A transistor can be destroyed in a circuit by:"},{"questionId":"B-004-003-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"base"},{"letter":"B","text":"emitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"source"},{"letter":"D","text":"collector"}],"questionText":"In a bipolar transistor, the_____________compares closest to thecontrol grid of a triode vacuum tube."},{"questionId":"B-004-003-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"collector"},{"letter":"B","text":"gate"},{"letter":"C","text":"emitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"base"}],"questionText":"In a bipolar transistor, the_____________compares closest to theplate of a triode vacuum tube."},{"questionId":"B-004-004-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inductive and capacitive"},{"letter":"B","text":"N and P channel"},{"letter":"C","text":"NPN and PNP"},{"letter":"D","text":"germanium and silicon"}],"questionText":"The two basic types of field effect transistors(FET) are:"},{"questionId":"B-004-004-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"gated transistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"bipolar transistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"silicon diode"},{"letter":"D","text":"field-effect transistor"}],"questionText":"A semiconductor having its leads labelledgate, drain, and source is best described asa:"},{"questionId":"B-004-004-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"collector"},{"letter":"B","text":"gate"},{"letter":"C","text":"drain"},{"letter":"D","text":"source"}],"questionText":"In a field effect transistor, the ___________is the terminal that controls the conductanceof the channel."},{"questionId":"B-004-004-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"gate"},{"letter":"B","text":"drain"},{"letter":"C","text":"emitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"source"}],"questionText":"In a field effect transistor, the ___________isthe terminal where the charge carriers enterthe channel."},{"questionId":"B-004-004-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"gate"},{"letter":"B","text":"drain"},{"letter":"C","text":"collector"},{"letter":"D","text":"source"}],"questionText":"In a field effect transistor, the __________ isthe terminal where the charge carriers leavethe channel."},{"questionId":"B-004-004-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Bipolar transistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"Field effect transistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"Junction diode"},{"letter":"D","text":"Zener diode"}],"questionText":"Which semiconductor device hascharacteristics most similar to a triodevacuum tube?"},{"questionId":"B-004-004-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"base"},{"letter":"B","text":"gate"},{"letter":"C","text":"source"},{"letter":"D","text":"drain"}],"questionText":"The control element in the field effecttransistor is the:"},{"questionId":"B-004-004-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"increase the reverse bias voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"decrease the reverse bias voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"increase the forward bias voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"increase the forward bias gain"}],"questionText":"If you wish to reduce the current flowing in afield effect transistor, you could:"},{"questionId":"B-004-004-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"drain"},{"letter":"B","text":"collector"},{"letter":"C","text":"emitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"base"}],"questionText":"The source of a field effect transistorcorresponds to the _______ of a bipolartransistor."},{"questionId":"B-004-004-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Source and base"},{"letter":"B","text":"Source and drain"},{"letter":"C","text":"Source and gate"},{"letter":"D","text":"Gate and drain"}],"questionText":"Which two elements in a field effecttransistor exhibit fairly similarcharacteristics?"},{"questionId":"B-004-005-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It uses less current"},{"letter":"B","text":"It is much smaller"},{"letter":"C","text":"It uses lower voltages"},{"letter":"D","text":"It may be able to handle higher power"}],"questionText":"What is one reason a triode vacuum tubemight be used instead of a transistor in acircuit?"},{"questionId":"B-004-005-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A multiple-cell battery"},{"letter":"B","text":"A vacuum tube"},{"letter":"C","text":"A transistor"},{"letter":"D","text":"An electrolytic capacitor"}],"questionText":"Which component can amplify a smallsignal but must use high voltages?"},{"questionId":"B-004-005-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"have electrons drifting through a vacuum"},{"letter":"B","text":"convert electrical energy to radio waves"},{"letter":"C","text":"use heat to cause electron movement"},{"letter":"D","text":"can amplify signals"}],"questionText":"A feature common to triode tubes andtransistors is that both:"},{"questionId":"B-004-005-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"cathode"},{"letter":"B","text":"grid"},{"letter":"C","text":"plate"},{"letter":"D","text":"filament (heater)"}],"questionText":"In a vacuum tube, the electrode that isoperated with the highest positive potentialis the _________."},{"questionId":"B-004-005-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"grid"},{"letter":"B","text":"filament (heater)"},{"letter":"C","text":"cathode"},{"letter":"D","text":"plate"}],"questionText":"In a vacuum tube, the electrode that isusually a cylinder of wire mesh is the_______."},{"questionId":"B-004-005-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"cathode"},{"letter":"B","text":"filament (heater)"},{"letter":"C","text":"grid"},{"letter":"D","text":"emitter"}],"questionText":"In a vacuum tube, the element that isfurthest away from the plate is the__________."},{"questionId":"B-004-005-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"plate"},{"letter":"B","text":"cathode"},{"letter":"C","text":"grid"},{"letter":"D","text":"collector"}],"questionText":"In a vacuum tube, the electrode that emitselectrons is the __________."},{"questionId":"B-004-005-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Neon"},{"letter":"B","text":"A vacuum"},{"letter":"C","text":"Argon"},{"letter":"D","text":"Air"}],"questionText":"What is inside the envelope of a triode tube?"},{"questionId":"B-004-005-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"One"},{"letter":"B","text":"Two"},{"letter":"C","text":"Three"},{"letter":"D","text":"Three plus a filament"}],"questionText":"How many grids are there in a triode vacuumtube?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The value of the resistor in ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"The resistance material"},{"letter":"C","text":"The power rating in watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"The resistance tolerance in percent"}],"questionText":"What do the first three-colour bands on aresistor indicate?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The resistance tolerance in percent"},{"letter":"B","text":"The value of the resistor in ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"The power rating in watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"The resistance material"}],"questionText":"What would the fourth colour band on a 47ohm resistor indicate?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"90 to 100 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"10 to 100 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"80 to 120 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"90 to 110 ohms"}],"questionText":"What are the possible values of a 100 ohmresistor with a 10% tolerance?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By using the Baudot code"},{"letter":"B","text":"By using the resistor's colour code"},{"letter":"C","text":"By using a voltmeter"},{"letter":"D","text":"By using Thevenin's theorem for resistors"}],"questionText":"How do you find a resistor's value?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"5%"},{"letter":"B","text":"10%"},{"letter":"C","text":"20%"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.1%"}],"questionText":"A club project requires that a resistivevoltage divider provide a very accurate andpredictable ratio. Out of the list below, whichresistor tolerance would you select?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10%"},{"letter":"B","text":"20%"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.1%"},{"letter":"D","text":"5%"}],"questionText":"You need a current limiting resistor for alight-emitting diode (LED). The actualresistance is not critical at all. Out of the listbelow, which resistor tolerance would youselect?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It will increase by 20% for every 10degrees centigrade"},{"letter":"B","text":"It will change depending on the resistor'stemperature coefficient rating"},{"letter":"C","text":"It will stay the same"},{"letter":"D","text":"It will become time dependent"}],"questionText":"If a carbon resistor's temperature isincreased, what will happen to theresistance?"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10%"},{"letter":"B","text":"1%"},{"letter":"C","text":"5%"},{"letter":"D","text":"20%"}],"questionText":"A gold tolerance band on a resistor indicatesthe tolerance is:"},{"questionId":"B-004-006-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Third band"},{"letter":"B","text":"First band"},{"letter":"C","text":"Second band"},{"letter":"D","text":"Fourth band"}],"questionText":"Which colour band would differentiate a 120-ohm from a 1200-ohm resistor?"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3525 kHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"35.25 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"3 525 000 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.003525 kHz"}],"questionText":"If a dial marked in megahertz shows areading of 3.525 MHz, what would it show ifit were marked in kilohertz?"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.003 ampere"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.3 ampere"},{"letter":"C","text":"3 000 000 amperes"},{"letter":"D","text":"3 amperes"}],"questionText":"If an ammeter marked in amperes is used tomeasure a 3000 milliampere current, whatreading would it show?"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"350 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"3.5 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.35 volt"},{"letter":"D","text":"35 volts"}],"questionText":"If a voltmeter marked in volts is used tomeasure a 3500 millivolt potential, whatreading would it show?"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1000 microfarads"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.001 microfarad"},{"letter":"C","text":"1 microfarad"},{"letter":"D","text":"1 000 000 000 microfarads"}],"questionText":"How many microfarads is 1 000 000picofarads?"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.5"},{"letter":"B","text":"5"},{"letter":"C","text":"50"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.02"}],"questionText":"If you have a hand-held transceiver whichputs out 500 milliwatts, how many wattswould this be?"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.1 ohm"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.001 ohm"},{"letter":"C","text":"10 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"1000 ohms"}],"questionText":"A kilohm is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"660 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"66 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"66 000 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"6600 volts"}],"questionText":"6.6 kilovolts is equal to:"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.25 milliampere"},{"letter":"B","text":"250 microamperes"},{"letter":"C","text":"250 milliamperes"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.5 amperes"}],"questionText":"A current of one quarter ampere may bewritten as:"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.000002"},{"letter":"B","text":"2 000 000"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.002"},{"letter":"D","text":"2 000"}],"questionText":"How many millivolts are equivalent to twovolts?"},{"questionId":"B-005-001-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1 000 kHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"100 kHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.001 Hz"}],"questionText":"One megahertz is equal to:"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Copper, gold, mica"},{"letter":"B","text":"Gold, silver, aluminum"},{"letter":"C","text":"Gold, silver, wood"},{"letter":"D","text":"Copper, aluminum, paper"}],"questionText":"Name three good electrical conductors."},{"questionId":"B-005-002-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Paper, glass, air, aluminum"},{"letter":"B","text":"Glass, wood, copper, porcelain"},{"letter":"C","text":"Glass, air, plastic, porcelain"},{"letter":"D","text":"Plastic, rubber, wood, carbon"}],"questionText":"Name four good electrical insulators."},{"questionId":"B-005-002-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"They absorb magnetic energy whichmakes them hot"},{"letter":"B","text":"Some electrical energy passing throughthem is lost as heat"},{"letter":"C","text":"Their reactance makes them heat up"},{"letter":"D","text":"Hotter circuit components nearby heatthem up"}],"questionText":"Why do resistors sometimes get hot whenin use?"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"copper"},{"letter":"B","text":"carbon"},{"letter":"C","text":"silicon"},{"letter":"D","text":"aluminium"}],"questionText":"What is the best conductor among thefollowing materials?"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a semiconductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"a dielectric"},{"letter":"C","text":"a conductor"},{"letter":"D","text":"an insulator"}],"questionText":"Which type of material listed will mostreadily allow an electric current to flow?"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"low resistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"high resistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"high wattage"},{"letter":"D","text":"low wattage"}],"questionText":"A length of metal is connected in a circuitand is found to conduct electricity very well.It would be best described as having a:"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"reluctance"},{"letter":"C","text":"reactance"},{"letter":"D","text":"resistance"}],"questionText":"The letter \"R\" is the symbol for:"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"reluctance"},{"letter":"B","text":"permeability"},{"letter":"C","text":"conductance"},{"letter":"D","text":"reactance"}],"questionText":"The reciprocal of resistance is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the difference in voltage at outputterminals of a transformer"},{"letter":"B","text":"the voltage which is dissipated beforeuseful work is accomplished"},{"letter":"C","text":"the voltage developed across theterminals of a component"},{"letter":"D","text":"any point in a radio circuit which has zerovoltage"}],"questionText":"Voltage drop means:"},{"questionId":"B-005-002-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"gold"},{"letter":"B","text":"mica"},{"letter":"C","text":"lead"},{"letter":"D","text":"carbon"}],"questionText":"The most common material used to make aresistor is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Resistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Power"},{"letter":"C","text":"Current"},{"letter":"D","text":"Voltage"}],"questionText":"What is the word used to describe the rateat which electrical energy is used?"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The 100 watt bulb"},{"letter":"B","text":"They will all be the same"},{"letter":"C","text":"The 40 watt bulb"},{"letter":"D","text":"The 60 watt bulb"}],"questionText":"If you have light bulbs marked 40 watts, 60watts and 100 watts, which one will useelectrical energy the fastest?"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The ampere"},{"letter":"B","text":"The volt"},{"letter":"C","text":"The ohm"},{"letter":"D","text":"The watt"}],"questionText":"What is the basic unit of electrical power?"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A closed circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"An open circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"A short circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"A complete circuit"}],"questionText":"Which electrical circuit will have no current?"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A short circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"A dead circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"A closed circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"An open circuit"}],"questionText":"Which electrical circuit draws too muchcurrent?"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"amperes"}],"questionText":"Power is expressed in:"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Voltage and inductance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Resistance and capacitance"},{"letter":"C","text":"Voltage and current"},{"letter":"D","text":"Inductance and capacitance"}],"questionText":"Which of the following two quantities shouldbe multiplied together to find power?"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Amperes and henrys"},{"letter":"B","text":"Volts and amperes"},{"letter":"C","text":"Volts and farads"},{"letter":"D","text":"Farads and henrys"}],"questionText":"Which two electrical units multipliedtogether give the unit \"watts\"?"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"resistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"current"},{"letter":"D","text":"power"}],"questionText":"A resistor in a circuit becomes very hot andstarts to burn. This is because the resistoris dissipating too much:"},{"questionId":"B-005-003-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"100 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"2 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.5 watt"}],"questionText":"The resistor that could dissipate the mostheat would be marked:"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"48 volts"},{"letter":"C","text":"52 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"25 volts"}],"questionText":"If a current of 2 amperes flows through a 50-ohm resistor, what is the voltage across theresistor?"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Current equals voltage divided byresistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Current equals resistance multiplied byvoltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"Current equals resistance divided byvoltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"Current equals power divided by voltage"}],"questionText":"How is the current in a DC circuit calculatedwhen the voltage and resistance are known?"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Resistance equals voltage divided bycurrent"},{"letter":"B","text":"Resistance equals current multiplied byvoltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"Resistance equals power divided byvoltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"Resistance equals current divided byvoltage"}],"questionText":"How is the resistance in a DC circuitcalculated when the voltage and current areknown?"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Voltage equals current multiplied byresistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Voltage equals current divided byresistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"Voltage equals resistance divided bycurrent"},{"letter":"D","text":"Voltage equals power divided by current"}],"questionText":"How is the voltage in a DC circuit calculatedwhen the current and resistance are known?"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.25 ohm"},{"letter":"B","text":"48 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"3 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"12 ohms"}],"questionText":"If a 12-volt battery supplies 0.25 ampere to acircuit, what is the circuit's resistance?"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"125 kilohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"125 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"1250 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"1.25 kilohms"}],"questionText":"Calculate the value of resistance necessaryto drop 100 volts with current flow of 0.8milliamperes:"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"22.0 volts"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.220 volt"},{"letter":"C","text":"220 volts"},{"letter":"D","text":"2220 volts"}],"questionText":"The voltage required to force a current of 4.4amperes through a resistance of 50 ohms is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.005 ampere"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.2 ampere"},{"letter":"C","text":"2 amperes"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.5 ampere"}],"questionText":"A lamp has a resistance of 30 ohms and a 6volt battery is connected. The current flowwill be:"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"R = I/E"},{"letter":"B","text":"R = E/R"},{"letter":"C","text":"R=ExI"},{"letter":"D","text":"R = E/I"}],"questionText":"The resistance of a circuit can be found byusing one of the following:"},{"questionId":"B-005-004-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"10 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"9 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"5 ohms"}],"questionText":"If a 3 volt battery supplies 300 milliamperesto a circuit, the circuit resistance is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It equals the sum of the branch currentthrough each resistor"},{"letter":"B","text":"It equals the average of the branchcurrent through each resistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"It decreases as more parallel resistorsare added to the circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"It is the sum of each resistor's voltagedrop multiplied by the total number ofresistors"}],"questionText":"In a parallel circuit with a voltage source andseveral branch resistors, how is the totalcurrent related to the current in the branchresistors?"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The voltage drop across the 20 ohmresistance is greater than the voltageacross the 10 ohm resistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"The current through the 10 ohms, 15ohms and 20 ohms separate resistances,when added together, equals the totalcurrent drawn from the battery"},{"letter":"C","text":"The current flowing through the 10 ohmresistance is less than that flowingthrough the 20 ohm resistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"The voltage drop across each resistanceadded together equals 6 volts"}],"questionText":"Three resistors, respectively rated at 10, 15and 20 ohms are connected in parallelacross a 6-volt battery. Which statement istrue?"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"could be equal to the resistance of onebranch"},{"letter":"B","text":"depends upon the applied voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"is always less than the smallestresistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"depends upon the voltage drop acrosseach branch"}],"questionText":"Total resistance in a parallel circuit:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"80 amperes"},{"letter":"B","text":"40 amperes"},{"letter":"C","text":"80 milliamperes"},{"letter":"D","text":"40 milliamperes"}],"questionText":"Two resistors are connected in parallel andare connected across a 40 volt battery. Ifeach resistor is 1000 ohms, the total currentis:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"equal to the highest resistance present"},{"letter":"B","text":"equal to the lowest resistance present"},{"letter":"C","text":"greater than the resistance of any oneresistor"},{"letter":"D","text":"less than the resistance of any oneresistor"}],"questionText":"The total resistance of resistors connectedin series is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1 ohm"},{"letter":"B","text":"50 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"5 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"10 ohms"}],"questionText":"Five 10 ohm resistors connected in seriesequals:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10 + R"},{"letter":"B","text":"R / 10"},{"letter":"C","text":"10 / R"},{"letter":"D","text":"10 x R"}],"questionText":"If ten resistors of equal value were wired inparallel, the total resistance would be:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"12 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"34 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"272 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"17 ohms"}],"questionText":"The total resistance of four 68 ohm resistorswired in parallel is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A has half the resistance of B"},{"letter":"B","text":"the voltage across B is twice that acrossA"},{"letter":"C","text":"the voltage across A is twice that acrossB"},{"letter":"D","text":"B has half the resistance of A"}],"questionText":"Two resistors are in parallel. Resistor Acarries twice the current of resistor B, whichmeans that:"},{"questionId":"B-005-005-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"source voltage divided by the value of oneof the resistive elements"},{"letter":"B","text":"source voltage divided by the sum of theresistive elements"},{"letter":"C","text":"current in any one of the parallelbranches"},{"letter":"D","text":"sum of the currents through all theparallel branches"}],"questionText":"The total current in a parallel circuit is equalto the:"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"For a higher current gain"},{"letter":"B","text":"For less impedance in the circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"For greater power dissipation"},{"letter":"D","text":"For better response time"}],"questionText":"Why would a large size resistor be usedinstead of a smaller one of the sameresistance?"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"24 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"6 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"2.4 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"60 watts"}],"questionText":"How many watts of electrical power are usedby a 12 volt DC light bulb that draws 0.2ampere?"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"500 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"12 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"6 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"20 watts"}],"questionText":"The DC input power of a transmitteroperating at 12 volts and drawing 500milliamperes would be:"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"1 watt"},{"letter":"C","text":"1/2 watt"},{"letter":"D","text":"4 watts"}],"questionText":"When two 500 ohm 1 watt resistors areconnected in series, the maximum totalpower that can be dissipated by theresistors is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"4 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"2 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"1/2 watt"},{"letter":"D","text":"1 watt"}],"questionText":"When two 500 ohm 1 watt resistors areconnected in parallel, they can dissipate amaximum total power of:"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Two 5-watt 100 ohms resistors in series"},{"letter":"B","text":"Two 2-watt 25 ohms resistors in series"},{"letter":"C","text":"Ten quarter-watt 500 ohms resistors inparallel"},{"letter":"D","text":"Four 2-watt 200 ohms resistors in parallel"}],"questionText":"Which combination of resistors could makeup a 50 ohms dummy load capable of safelydissipating 5 watts?"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"18 amperes"},{"letter":"B","text":"360 amperes"},{"letter":"C","text":"12/30 amperes"},{"letter":"D","text":"30/12 amperes"}],"questionText":"A 12 volt light bulb is rated at a power of 30watts. The current drawn would be:"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"20 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"100 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"5 watts"}],"questionText":"If two 10 ohm resistors are connected inseries with a 10 volt battery, the powerconsumption would be:"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the same resistance but greater powerrating"},{"letter":"B","text":"the same resistance but lesser powerrating"},{"letter":"C","text":"greater resistance and similar powerrating"},{"letter":"D","text":"lesser resistance and similar power rating"}],"questionText":"One advantage of replacing a 50 ohmresistor with a parallel combination of twosimilarly rated 100 ohm resistors is that theparallel combination will have:"},{"questionId":"B-005-006-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"determined by heat dissipation qualities"},{"letter":"B","text":"calculated according to physical size andtolerance rating"},{"letter":"C","text":"expressed in joules"},{"letter":"D","text":"variable in steps of one hundred"}],"questionText":"Resistor wattage ratings are:"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Speed"},{"letter":"B","text":"Pulse rate"},{"letter":"C","text":"Inductance"},{"letter":"D","text":"Frequency"}],"questionText":"What term means the number of times persecond that an alternating current flowsback and forth?"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20 000 - 30 000 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"200 - 200 000 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"0 - 20 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"20 - 20 000 Hz"}],"questionText":"Approximately what frequency range canmost humans hear?"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because the human ear can sensesounds in this range"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because the human ear cannot senseanything in this range"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because this range is too low for radioenergy"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because the human ear can sense radiowaves in this range"}],"questionText":"Why do we call signals in the range 20 Hzto 20 000 Hz audio frequencies?"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Radio"},{"letter":"B","text":"Audio"},{"letter":"C","text":"Hyper"},{"letter":"D","text":"Super-high"}],"questionText":"Electrical energy at a frequency of 7125 kHzis in what frequency range?"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It stays the same"},{"letter":"B","text":"It disappears"},{"letter":"C","text":"It gets shorter"},{"letter":"D","text":"It gets longer"}],"questionText":"What happens to a signal's wavelength asits frequency increases?"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It goes down"},{"letter":"B","text":"It disappears"},{"letter":"C","text":"It stays the same"},{"letter":"D","text":"It goes up"}],"questionText":"What happens to a signal's frequency as itswavelength gets longer?"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6000 metres per second"},{"letter":"B","text":"60 metres per second"},{"letter":"C","text":"6000 cycles per second"},{"letter":"D","text":"60 cycles per second"}],"questionText":"What does 60 hertz (Hz) mean?"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10 seconds"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.0001 second"},{"letter":"C","text":"1 second"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.01 second"}],"questionText":"If the frequency of the waveform is 100 Hz,the time for one cycle is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 Hz"},{"letter":"B","text":"1000 Hz"},{"letter":"C","text":"10 Hz"},{"letter":"D","text":"1 Hz"}],"questionText":"Current in an AC circuit goes through acomplete cycle in 0.1 second. This meansthe AC has a frequency of:"},{"questionId":"B-005-007-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a dielectric signal of the main signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"a harmonic of the 2 kHz signal"},{"letter":"C","text":"a fundamental of the 2 kHz signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"the DC component of the main signal"}],"questionText":"A signal is composed of a fundamentalfrequency of 2 kHz and another of 4 kHz.This 4 kHz signal is referred to as:"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3 dB higher"},{"letter":"B","text":"6 dB higher"},{"letter":"C","text":"12 dB higher"},{"letter":"D","text":"1 dB higher"}],"questionText":"A two-times increase in power results in achange of how many dB?"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Divide the original power by 2"},{"letter":"B","text":"Divide the original power by 1.5"},{"letter":"C","text":"Divide the original power by 3"},{"letter":"D","text":"Divide the original power by 4"}],"questionText":"How can you decrease your transmitter'spower by 3 dB?"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Multiply the original power by 1.5"},{"letter":"B","text":"Multiply the original power by 4"},{"letter":"C","text":"Multiply the original power by 3"},{"letter":"D","text":"Multiply the original power by 2"}],"questionText":"How can you increase your transmitter'spower by 6 dB?"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"S9 minus 10 dB"},{"letter":"B","text":"S9 plus 5 dB"},{"letter":"C","text":"S9"},{"letter":"D","text":"S9 plus 3 dB"}],"questionText":"If a signal-strength report is \"10 dB over S9\",what should the report be if the transmitterpower is reduced from 1500 watts to 150watts?"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a single side band signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"a mathematical ratio"},{"letter":"C","text":"an oscilloscope wave form"},{"letter":"D","text":"certain radio waves"}],"questionText":"The unit \"decibel\" is used to indicate:"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6"},{"letter":"B","text":"1"},{"letter":"C","text":"3"},{"letter":"D","text":"30"}],"questionText":"The power output from a transmitterincreases from 1 watt to 2 watts. This is adB increase of:"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20 dB"},{"letter":"B","text":"10 dB"},{"letter":"C","text":"30 dB"},{"letter":"D","text":"40 dB"}],"questionText":"The power of a transmitter is increased from5 watts to 50 watts by a linear amplifier. Thepower gain, expressed in dB, is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"16 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"11 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"20 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"18 watts"}],"questionText":"You add a 9 dB gain amplifier to your 2 watthandheld. What is the power output of thecombination?"},{"questionId":"B-005-008-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"9 dB"},{"letter":"B","text":"6 dB"},{"letter":"C","text":"3 dB"},{"letter":"D","text":"8 dB"}],"questionText":"The power of a transmitter is increased from2 watts to 8 watts. This is a power gain of__________ dB."},{"questionId":"B-005-008-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10 W"},{"letter":"B","text":"33.3 W"},{"letter":"C","text":"100 mW"},{"letter":"D","text":"1W"}],"questionText":"A local amateur reports your 100W 2Msimplex VHF transmission as 30 dB overS9. To reduce your signal to S9, you wouldreduce your power to ______ watts."},{"questionId":"B-005-009-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Twice the value of one inductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"Half the value of one inductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"The same as the value of either inductor"},{"letter":"D","text":"The value of one inductor times the valueof the other"}],"questionText":"If two equal-value inductors are connected inseries, what is their total inductance?"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The value of one inductor times the valueof the other"},{"letter":"B","text":"Half the value of one inductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"Twice the value of one inductor"},{"letter":"D","text":"The same as the value of either inductor"}],"questionText":"If two equal-value inductors are connected inparallel, what is their total inductance?"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Half the value of either capacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"Twice the value of one capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"The same as the value of either capacitor"},{"letter":"D","text":"The value of one capacitor times thevalue of the other"}],"questionText":"If two equal-value capacitors are connectedin series, what is their total capacitance?"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The core material, the number of turnsused to wind the coil and the frequency ofthe current through the coil"},{"letter":"B","text":"The coil diameter, the number of turns ofwire used to wind the coil and the type ofmetal used for the wire"},{"letter":"C","text":"The core material, the coil diameter, thelength of the coil and whether the coil ismounted horizontally or vertically"},{"letter":"D","text":"The core material, the coil diameter, thelength of the coil and the number of turnsof wire used to wind the coil"}],"questionText":"What determines the inductance of a coil?"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The material between the plates, thesurface area of the plates, the number ofplates and the spacing between theplates"},{"letter":"B","text":"The material between the plates, thenumber of plates and the size of thewires connected to the plates"},{"letter":"C","text":"The number of plates, the spacingbetween the plates and whether thedielectric material is N type or P type"},{"letter":"D","text":"The material between the plates, the areaof one plate, the number of plates and thematerial used for the protective coating"}],"questionText":"What determines the capacitance of acapacitor?"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Twice the value of either capacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"The same value of either capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"The value of one capacitor times thevalue of the other"},{"letter":"D","text":"Half the value of either capacitor"}],"questionText":"If two equal-value capacitors are connectedin parallel, what is their capacitance?"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"30 millihenry chokes in parallel"},{"letter":"B","text":"5 millihenry chokes in parallel"},{"letter":"C","text":"5 millihenry chokes in series"},{"letter":"D","text":"20 millihenry chokes in series"}],"questionText":"To replace a faulty 10 millihenry choke, youcould use two:"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"18 microfarads"},{"letter":"B","text":"5 microfarads"},{"letter":"C","text":"45 microfarads"},{"letter":"D","text":"12 microfarads"}],"questionText":"Three 15 microfarad capacitors are wired inseries. The total capacitance of thisarrangement is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Two 10 microfarad capacitors"},{"letter":"B","text":"Twenty 2 microfarad capacitors"},{"letter":"C","text":"Ten 2 microfarad capacitors"},{"letter":"D","text":"Two 20 microfarad capacitors"}],"questionText":"Which series combinations of capacitorswould best replace a faulty 10 microfaradcapacitor?"},{"questionId":"B-005-009-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"found by adding each of the capacitorstogether"},{"letter":"B","text":"always greater than the largest capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"always less than the smallest capacitor"},{"letter":"D","text":"found by adding each of the capacitorstogether and dividing by the total numberof capacitors"}],"questionText":"The total capacitance of two or morecapacitors in series is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"As the frequency of the applied ACincreases, the reactance decreases"},{"letter":"B","text":"As the frequency of the applied ACincreases, the reactance increases"},{"letter":"C","text":"As the amplitude of the applied ACincreases, the reactance decreases"},{"letter":"D","text":"As the amplitude of the applied ACincreases, the reactance increases"}],"questionText":"How does a coil react to AC?"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"applied voltage decreases"},{"letter":"B","text":"frequency increases"},{"letter":"C","text":"frequency decreases"},{"letter":"D","text":"applied voltage increases"}],"questionText":"The reactance of capacitors increases as:"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inductance"},{"letter":"B","text":"capacitance"},{"letter":"C","text":"impedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"resonance"}],"questionText":"In inductances, AC may be opposed by bothresistance of winding wire and reactancedue to inductive effect. The term whichincludes resistance and reactance is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"decreases as frequency increases"},{"letter":"B","text":"applies only to series RLC circuits"},{"letter":"C","text":"increases as frequency increases"},{"letter":"D","text":"increases with the time constant"}],"questionText":"Capacitive reactance:"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an increase in the applied voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"an increase in the applied frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"a decrease in the applied frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"a decrease in the supplied current"}],"questionText":"Inductive reactance may be increased by:"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High reactance at audio frequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"High reactance at radio frequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"Low reactance at radio frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"Low reactance at audio frequencies"}],"questionText":"What property allows a coil wound on aferrite core to mitigate the effects of anoffending radio signal?"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High reactance at radio frequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"Low reactance at audio frequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"High reactance at audio frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"Low reactance at radio frequencies"}],"questionText":"What property allows an RF bypasscapacitor on an audio circuit to divert anoffending radio signal?"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High reactance at high frequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"Low reactance at low frequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"High reactance at low frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"Low reactance at high frequencies"}],"questionText":"What property allows an RF bypasscapacitor to have little effect on an audiocircuit?"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High reactance at high frequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"Low reactance at low frequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"High reactance at low frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"Low reactance at high frequencies"}],"questionText":"What property allows an RF choke coil tohave little effect on signals meant to flowthrough the coil?"},{"questionId":"B-005-010-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"increasing AC frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"decreasing AC frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"decreasing applied voltage"},{"letter":"D","text":"increasing applied voltage"}],"questionText":"In general, the reactance of inductorsincreases with:"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3 watts"},{"letter":"B","text":"13 watts"},{"letter":"C","text":"6 watts"},{"letter":"D","text":"8 watts"}],"questionText":"A transformer operates a 6.3 volt 2 amperelight bulb from its secondary winding. Theinput power to the primary winding isapproximately:"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"5 amperes"},{"letter":"B","text":"215 amperes"},{"letter":"C","text":"25 amperes"},{"letter":"D","text":"50 amperes"}],"questionText":"A transformer has a 240 volt primary thatdraws a current of 250 milliamperes from themains supply. Assuming no losses and onlyone secondary, what current would beavailable from the 12 volt secondary?"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"610 V"},{"letter":"B","text":"26 V"},{"letter":"C","text":"240 V"},{"letter":"D","text":"480 V"}],"questionText":"In a mains power transformer, the primarywinding has 250 turns, and the secondaryhas 500. If the input voltage is 120 volts, thelikely secondary voltage is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"directly proportional to the diameter of theconductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"inversely proportional to the voltage onthe conductor"},{"letter":"C","text":"directly proportional to the current in theconductor"},{"letter":"D","text":"inversely proportional to the diameter ofthe conductor"}],"questionText":"The strength of the magnetic field around aconductor in air is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the current through the coil is of a DCnature"},{"letter":"B","text":"current is going through its least rate ofchange"},{"letter":"C","text":"the magnetic field around the coil is notchanging"},{"letter":"D","text":"current is going through its greatest rateof change"}],"questionText":"Maximum induced voltage in a coil occurswhen:"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"made in a clockwise direction"},{"letter":"B","text":"perpendicular to the lines of force"},{"letter":"C","text":"made in a counter clockwise direction"},{"letter":"D","text":"parallel to the lines of force"}],"questionText":"The voltage induced in a conductor moving ina magnetic field is at a maximum when themovement is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.25 A"},{"letter":"B","text":"2 500 mA"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.01 A"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.25 mA"}],"questionText":"A 100% efficient transformer has a turnsratio of 1/5. If the secondary current is 50milliamperes, the primary current is:"},{"questionId":"B-005-011-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"like"},{"letter":"B","text":"unlike"},{"letter":"C","text":"positive"},{"letter":"D","text":"negative"}],"questionText":"A force of repulsion exists between two_________ magnetic poles."},{"questionId":"B-005-011-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"high primary voltages"},{"letter":"B","text":"warm iron laminations"},{"letter":"C","text":"electrostatic shielding"},{"letter":"D","text":"large secondary currents"}],"questionText":"The fact that energy transfer from primary tosecondary windings in a power transformeris not perfect is indicated by:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inductive reactance is the only oppositionin the circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"the circuit contains no resistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"resistance is equal to the reactance"},{"letter":"D","text":"inductive reactance and capacitivereactance are equal"}],"questionText":"Resonance is the condition that existswhen:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an impedance equal to resistance of thecircuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"high impedance at resonance"},{"letter":"C","text":"low impedance at resonance"},{"letter":"D","text":"zero impedance at resonance"}],"questionText":"Parallel tuned circuits offer:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"an inductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"a set of parallel inductors"},{"letter":"C","text":"the results of tuning a varicap (varactor)"},{"letter":"D","text":"the frequency characteristic of a coil andcapacitor circuit"}],"questionText":"Resonance is an electrical property used todescribe:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"diodes and transistors"},{"letter":"B","text":"inductors and capacitors"},{"letter":"C","text":"resistors and transistors"},{"letter":"D","text":"directors and reflectors"}],"questionText":"A tuned circuit is formed from two basiccomponents. These are:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"resonant frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"impedance frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"inductive frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"reactive frequency"}],"questionText":"When a parallel coil-capacitor combinationis supplied with AC of different frequencies,there will be one frequency where theimpedance will be highest. This is the:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"low mutual inductance"},{"letter":"B","text":"high mutual inductance"},{"letter":"C","text":"high impedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"low impedance"}],"questionText":"In a parallel-resonant circuit at resonance,the circuit has a:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"low mutual inductance"},{"letter":"B","text":"high mutual inductance"},{"letter":"C","text":"low impedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"high impedance"}],"questionText":"In a series resonant circuit at resonance, thecircuit has:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"increase the area of plates in thecapacitor"},{"letter":"B","text":"insert Mylar sheets between the plates ofthe capacitor"},{"letter":"C","text":"wind more turns on the coil"},{"letter":"D","text":"add a resistor to the circuit"}],"questionText":"A coil and an air-spaced capacitor arearranged to form a resonant circuit. Theresonant frequency will remain the same ifwe:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inductive reactance is the only oppositionin the circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"the circuit contains no resistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"resistance is equal to the reactance"},{"letter":"D","text":"inductive reactance and capacitivereactance are equal and opposite in sign"}],"questionText":"Resonance is the condition that existswhen:"},{"questionId":"B-005-012-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"line current lags the applied voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"line current leads the applied voltage"},{"letter":"C","text":"impedance is maximum"},{"letter":"D","text":"line current reaches maximum"}],"questionText":"When a series LCR circuit is tuned to thefrequency of the source, the:"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"In phase with the circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"In parallel with the circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"In series with the circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"In quadrature with the circuit"}],"questionText":"How is a voltmeter usually connected to acircuit under test?"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"In quadrature with the circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"In phase with the circuit"},{"letter":"C","text":"In parallel with the circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"In series with the circuit"}],"questionText":"How is an ammeter usually connected to acircuit under test?"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Voltage, current and resistance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Resistance, capacitance and inductance"},{"letter":"C","text":"Resistance and reactance"},{"letter":"D","text":"SWR and power"}],"questionText":"What does a multimeter measure?"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a wattmeter"},{"letter":"B","text":"a voltmeter"},{"letter":"C","text":"an ammeter"},{"letter":"D","text":"an ohmmeter"}],"questionText":"The correct instrument to measure platecurrent or collector current of a transmitteris:"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An electrostatic voltmeter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A DC ammeter"},{"letter":"C","text":"An RF ammeter"},{"letter":"D","text":"An RF power meter"}],"questionText":"Which of the following meters would you useto measure the power supply current drawnby a small hand-held transistorized receiver?"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a perfect conductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"an extra current drain"},{"letter":"C","text":"an insulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"a low value resistance"}],"questionText":"When measuring current drawn from a DCpower supply, it is true to say that the meterwill act in circuit as:"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"in parallel with both receiver power supplyleads"},{"letter":"B","text":"in parallel with one of the receiver powerleads"},{"letter":"C","text":"in series with one of the receiver powerleads"},{"letter":"D","text":"in series with both receiver power leads"}],"questionText":"When measuring the current drawn by areceiver from a power supply, the currentmeter should be placed:"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"faradmeter"},{"letter":"B","text":"wattmeter"},{"letter":"C","text":"voltmeter"},{"letter":"D","text":"ammeter"}],"questionText":"The instrument used for measuring the flowof electrical current is the:"},{"questionId":"B-005-013-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the voltmeter in series and ammeter inparallel"},{"letter":"B","text":"both voltmeter and ammeter in series"},{"letter":"C","text":"both voltmeter and ammeter in parallel"},{"letter":"D","text":"the voltmeter in parallel and ammeter inseries"}],"questionText":"In measuring volts and amperes, theconnections should be made with:"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The power cord"},{"letter":"B","text":"A ground wire"},{"letter":"C","text":"A dummy load"},{"letter":"D","text":"A transmission line"}],"questionText":"What connects your transceiver to yourantenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"physical dimensions and relativepositions of the conductors"},{"letter":"B","text":"length of the line"},{"letter":"C","text":"frequency at which the line is operated"},{"letter":"D","text":"load placed on the line"}],"questionText":"The characteristic impedance of atransmission line is determined by the:"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"13 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"52 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"26 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"39 ohms"}],"questionText":"The characteristic impedance of a 20 metrepiece of transmission line is 52 ohms. If 10metres were cut off, the impedance wouldbe:"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"is correct for only one size of line"},{"letter":"B","text":"is greater for larger diameter line"},{"letter":"C","text":"can be the same for different diameterline"},{"letter":"D","text":"changes significantly with the frequencyof the energy it carries"}],"questionText":"The characteristic impedance of a coaxialline:"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Coaxial cable"},{"letter":"B","text":"300 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"C","text":"600 ohm open-wire line"},{"letter":"D","text":"75 ohm twin-lead"}],"questionText":"What commonly available antennatransmission line can be buried directly inthe ground for some distance withoutadverse effects?"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the ratio of the power supplied to the lineto the power delivered to the load"},{"letter":"B","text":"equal to the pure resistance which, ifconnected to the end of the line, willabsorb all the power arriving along it"},{"letter":"C","text":"the impedance of a section of the lineone wavelength long"},{"letter":"D","text":"the dynamic impedance of the line at theoperating frequency"}],"questionText":"The characteristic impedance of atransmission line is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"dielectric"},{"letter":"B","text":"velocity of energy on the line"},{"letter":"C","text":"radius of the conductors"},{"letter":"D","text":"centre to centre distance betweenconductors"}],"questionText":"The characteristic impedance of a parallelwire transmission line does not depend onthe:"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A negative impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"An impedance nearly equal to thecharacteristic impedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"Some value of impedance influenced byline length"},{"letter":"D","text":"An infinite impedance"}],"questionText":"If the impedance terminating a transmissionline differs significantly from thecharacteristic impedance of the line, whatwill be observed at the input of the line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The radius of the conductors and thefrequency of the signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"The frequency of the signal and thelength of the line"},{"letter":"C","text":"The distance between the centres of theconductors and the radius of theconductors"},{"letter":"D","text":"The distance between the centres of theconductors and the length of the line"}],"questionText":"What factors determine the characteristicimpedance of a parallel-conductor antennatransmission line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-001-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The diameter of the shield and the lengthof the line"},{"letter":"B","text":"The diameter of the shield and thefrequency of the signal"},{"letter":"C","text":"The frequency of the signal and thelength of the line"},{"letter":"D","text":"The ratio of the diameter of the innerconductor to the diameter of the outershield"}],"questionText":"What factors determine the characteristicimpedance of a coaxial antennatransmission line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Two wires side-by-side held apart byinsulating rods"},{"letter":"B","text":"Two wires twisted around each other in aspiral"},{"letter":"C","text":"A center wire inside an insulatingmaterial which is covered by a metalsleeve or shield"},{"letter":"D","text":"Two wires side-by-side in a plastic ribbon"}],"questionText":"What is a coaxial cable?"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A metal pipe which is as wide or slightlywider than a wavelength of the signal itcarries"},{"letter":"B","text":"Two wires side-by-side held apart byinsulating material"},{"letter":"C","text":"Two wires twisted around each other in aspiral"},{"letter":"D","text":"A center wire inside an insulatingmaterial which is covered by a metalsleeve or shield"}],"questionText":"What is parallel-conductor transmissionline?"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Open wire line"},{"letter":"B","text":"Coaxial cable"},{"letter":"C","text":"Twin lead in a plastic ribbon"},{"letter":"D","text":"Twisted pair"}],"questionText":"What kind of antenna transmission line ismade of two conductors held apart byinsulated rods?"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Between the antenna and the ground"},{"letter":"B","text":"Between the coaxial cable and theground"},{"letter":"C","text":"Between the coaxial cable and theantenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"Between the transmitter and the coaxialcable"}],"questionText":"Where would you install a balun to feed adipole antenna with 50-ohm coaxial cable?"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Transmission line with both conductorsconnected to each other"},{"letter":"B","text":"Transmission line with one conductorconnected to ground"},{"letter":"C","text":"Transmission line with neither conductorconnected to ground"},{"letter":"D","text":"Transmission line with both conductorsconnected to ground"}],"questionText":"What is an unbalanced line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A balun"},{"letter":"B","text":"A triaxial transformer"},{"letter":"C","text":"A wave trap"},{"letter":"D","text":"A loading coil"}],"questionText":"What device can be installed to feed abalanced antenna with an unbalancedtransmission line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"only one conductor"},{"letter":"B","text":"two parallel conductors separated byspacers"},{"letter":"C","text":"braided shield conductor and insulationaround a central conductor"},{"letter":"D","text":"four or more conductors running parallel"}],"questionText":"A flexible coaxial line contains:"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"carries RF current on one wire only"},{"letter":"B","text":"is made of one conductor only"},{"letter":"C","text":"is made of two parallel wires"},{"letter":"D","text":"has one conductor inside the other"}],"questionText":"A balanced transmission line:"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"by using a 4 to 1 trigatron"},{"letter":"B","text":"by inserting a diode in one leg of theantenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"by using a 4 to 1 impedance transformer"},{"letter":"D","text":"with an extra 250 ohm resistor"}],"questionText":"A 75 ohm transmission line could bematched to the 300 ohm feed point of anantenna:"},{"questionId":"B-006-002-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"600 ohm open wire line"},{"letter":"B","text":"Coaxial cable"},{"letter":"C","text":"75 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 ohm twin-lead"}],"questionText":"What kind of antenna transmission line canbe constructed using two conductors whichare maintained a uniform distance apartusing insulated spreaders?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It can be used near metal objects, and itsimpedance is higher than that of mostamateur antennas"},{"letter":"B","text":"You can make it at home, and itsimpedance matches most amateurantennas"},{"letter":"C","text":"It is weatherproof, and its impedancematches most amateur antennas"},{"letter":"D","text":"It is weatherproof, and its impedance ishigher than that of most amateurantennas"}],"questionText":"Why does coaxial cable make a goodantenna transmission line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is difficult to make at home, and it doesnot work very well with a high SWR"},{"letter":"B","text":"It does not work well when tied down tometal objects, and you should use abalun and may have to use animpedance-matching device with yourtransceiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"You must use an impedance-matchingdevice with your transceiver, and it doesnot work very well with a high SWR"},{"letter":"D","text":"It does not work well when tied down tometal objects, and it cannot operateunder high power"}],"questionText":"What are some reasons not to use parallel-conductor transmission line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A banana plug connector"},{"letter":"B","text":"A binding post connector"},{"letter":"C","text":"A PL-259 connector"},{"letter":"D","text":"An F-type cable connector"}],"questionText":"What common connector type usually joinsRG-213 coaxial cable to an HF transceiver?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A PL-259 connector"},{"letter":"B","text":"An F-type cable connector"},{"letter":"C","text":"A binding post connector"},{"letter":"D","text":"An SMA connector"}],"questionText":"What common connector usually joins ahand-held transceiver to its antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A PL-259 connector"},{"letter":"B","text":"A type-N connector"},{"letter":"C","text":"An F-type cable connector"},{"letter":"D","text":"A BNC connector"}],"questionText":"Which of these common connectors has thelowest loss at UHF?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"RG-213"},{"letter":"B","text":"RG-174"},{"letter":"C","text":"RG-59"},{"letter":"D","text":"RG-58"}],"questionText":"If you install a 6 metre Yagi on a tower 60metres (200 ft) from your transmitter, whichof the following transmission lines providesthe least loss?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To keep them looking nice"},{"letter":"B","text":"To keep them from getting stuck in place"},{"letter":"C","text":"To increase their capacitance"},{"letter":"D","text":"To help keep their contact resistance at aminimum"}],"questionText":"Why should you regularly clean and tightenall antenna connectors?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"75 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"B","text":"600 ohm open wire line"},{"letter":"C","text":"300 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"D","text":"Coaxial cable"}],"questionText":"What commonly available antennatransmission line can be buried directly inthe ground for some distance withoutadverse effects?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"600 ohm open wire line"},{"letter":"B","text":"75 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"C","text":"Coaxial cable"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 ohm twin-lead"}],"questionText":"When antenna transmission lines must beplaced near grounded metal objects, whichof the following transmission lines should beused?"},{"questionId":"B-006-003-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"50 ohms"},{"letter":"B","text":"70 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"300 ohms"},{"letter":"D","text":"600 ohms"}],"questionText":"TV twin-lead transmission line can be usedfor a transmission line in an amateur station.The impedance of this line is approximately:"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It has a low impedance, and has lessloss than coaxial cable"},{"letter":"B","text":"It will operate with a high SWR, and hasless loss than coaxial cable"},{"letter":"C","text":"It has low impedance, and will operatewith a high SWR"},{"letter":"D","text":"It will operate with a high SWR, and itworks well when tied down to metalobjects"}],"questionText":"What are some reasons to use parallel-conductor transmission line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Shorten the excess cable so thetransmission line is an odd number ofwavelengths long"},{"letter":"B","text":"Roll the excess cable into a coil which isas small as possible"},{"letter":"C","text":"Shorten the excess cable so thetransmission line is an even number ofwavelengths long"},{"letter":"D","text":"Shorten the excess cable"}],"questionText":"If your transmitter and antenna are 15metres (50 ft) apart, but are connected by 60metres (200 ft) of RG-58 coaxial cable, whatshould be done to reduce transmission lineloss?"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Signal loss increases as lengthincreases"},{"letter":"B","text":"Signal loss decreases as lengthincreases"},{"letter":"C","text":"Signal loss is the least when the lengthis the same as the signal's wavelength"},{"letter":"D","text":"Signal loss is the same for any length oftransmission line"}],"questionText":"As the length of a transmission line ischanged, what happens to signal loss?"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Signal loss increases with decreasingfrequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"Signal loss is the least when the signal'swavelength is the same as thetransmission line's length"},{"letter":"C","text":"Signal loss is the same for any frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"Signal loss increases with increasingfrequency"}],"questionText":"As the frequency of a signal is changed,what happens to signal loss in atransmission line?"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the wire radiating RF energy"},{"letter":"B","text":"less RF power being radiated"},{"letter":"C","text":"an SWR reading of 1:1"},{"letter":"D","text":"reflections occurring in the line"}],"questionText":"Losses occurring on a transmission linebetween transmitter and antenna results in:"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"300 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"B","text":"open wire line"},{"letter":"C","text":"75 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"D","text":"coaxial cable"}],"questionText":"The lowest loss transmission line on HF is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Ohms per metre"},{"letter":"B","text":"dB per unit length"},{"letter":"C","text":"Ohms per MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"dB per MHz"}],"questionText":"In what values are RF transmission linelosses expressed?"},{"questionId":"B-006-004-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It would be reduced by 10%"},{"letter":"B","text":"It would be increased by 10%"},{"letter":"C","text":"It would be reduced to 50%"},{"letter":"D","text":"It would be increased by 100%"}],"questionText":"If the length of coaxial transmission line isincreased from 20 metres (66 ft) to 40metres (132 ft), how would this affect the lineloss?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"No power is going to the antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"The SWR meter is broken"},{"letter":"C","text":"The best impedance match has beenattained"},{"letter":"D","text":"An antenna for another frequency band isprobably connected"}],"questionText":"What does an SWR reading of 1:1 mean?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An impedance match which is too low"},{"letter":"B","text":"A serious impedance mismatch,something may be wrong with theantenna system"},{"letter":"C","text":"An antenna gain of 1.5"},{"letter":"D","text":"A fairly good impedance match"}],"questionText":"What does an SWR reading of less than1.5:1 mean?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A negative reading"},{"letter":"B","text":"No reading at all"},{"letter":"C","text":"A very low reading"},{"letter":"D","text":"A jumpy reading"}],"questionText":"What kind of SWR reading may mean poorelectrical contact between parts of anantenna system?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The signals coming from the antenna areunusually strong, which means very goodradio condition"},{"letter":"B","text":"The antenna is the wrong length for theoperating frequency, or the transmissionline may be open or short circuited"},{"letter":"C","text":"The transmitter is putting out more powerthan normal, showing that it is about togo bad"},{"letter":"D","text":"There is a large amount of solar radiation,which means very poor radio conditions"}],"questionText":"What does a very high SWR reading mean?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The ratio of maximum to minimumvoltages on a transmission line"},{"letter":"B","text":"The ratio of maximum to minimuminductances on a transmission line"},{"letter":"C","text":"The ratio of maximum to minimumresistances on a transmission line"},{"letter":"D","text":"The ratio of maximum to minimumimpedances on a transmission line"}],"questionText":"What does standing-wave ratio mean?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The transmission line is too long"},{"letter":"B","text":"The SWR may be too high, or thetransmission line loss may be high"},{"letter":"C","text":"You should transmit using less power"},{"letter":"D","text":"The conductors in the transmission lineare not insulated very well"}],"questionText":"If your antenna transmission line gets hotwhen you are transmitting, what might thismean?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the antenna will not radiate any signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"standing waves are produced in thetransmission line"},{"letter":"C","text":"heat is produced at the junction"},{"letter":"D","text":"the SWR reading falls to 1:1"}],"questionText":"If the characteristic impedance of thetransmission line does not match theantenna input impedance then:"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"comparing forward and reflected voltage"},{"letter":"B","text":"measuring radiated RF energy"},{"letter":"C","text":"measuring the conductor temperature"},{"letter":"D","text":"inserting a diode in the transmission line"}],"questionText":"An SWR meter measures the degree ofmatch between transmission line andantenna by:"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6:1"},{"letter":"B","text":"3:1"},{"letter":"C","text":"5:1"},{"letter":"D","text":"4:1"}],"questionText":"A resonant antenna having a feed pointimpedance of 200 ohms is connected to atransmission line which has an impedanceof 50 ohms. What will the standing waveratio of this system be?"},{"questionId":"B-006-005-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"75 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"B","text":"coaxial line"},{"letter":"C","text":"300 ohm twin-lead"},{"letter":"D","text":"600 ohm open wire line"}],"questionText":"The type of transmission line best suited tooperating at a high standing wave ratio is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An SWR meter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A low pass filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"A high pass filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"An antenna tuner"}],"questionText":"What device might allow use of an antennaon a band it was not designed for?"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It switches a transceiver between differentkinds of antennas connected to onetransmission line"},{"letter":"B","text":"It matches a transceiver to a mismatchedantenna system"},{"letter":"C","text":"It helps a receiver automatically tune instations that are far away"},{"letter":"D","text":"It switches an antenna system to atransmitter when sending, and to areceiver when listening"}],"questionText":"What does an antenna tuner do?"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A low pass filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A terminating resistor"},{"letter":"C","text":"An impedance-matching device"},{"letter":"D","text":"An SWR meter"}],"questionText":"What would you use to connect a coaxialcable of 50 ohms impedance to an antennaof 17 ohms impedance?"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"When the power-supply fuse ratingequals the primary winding current"},{"letter":"B","text":"When the load resistance is infinite"},{"letter":"C","text":"When the impedance of the load is equalto the impedance of the source"},{"letter":"D","text":"When air wound transformers are usedinstead of iron-core transformers"}],"questionText":"When will a power source deliver maximumoutput to the load?"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The source delivers minimum power tothe load"},{"letter":"B","text":"The source delivers maximum power tothe load"},{"letter":"C","text":"The electrical load is shorted"},{"letter":"D","text":"No current can flow through the circuit"}],"questionText":"What happens when the impedance of anelectrical load is equal to the internalimpedance of the power source?"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"So the source can deliver maximumpower to the load"},{"letter":"B","text":"So the load will draw minimum powerfrom the source"},{"letter":"C","text":"To ensure that there is less resistancethan reactance in the circuit"},{"letter":"D","text":"To ensure that the resistance andreactance in the circuit are equal"}],"questionText":"Why is impedance matching important?"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"proper method of balance"},{"letter":"B","text":"low load resistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"matching of impedance"},{"letter":"D","text":"high load impedance"}],"questionText":"To obtain efficient transfer of power from atransmitter to an antenna, it is important thatthere is a:"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"must be a full wavelength long"},{"letter":"B","text":"must be an odd number of quarter-wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"must be an even number of half-waves"},{"letter":"D","text":"will have no effect on the matching"}],"questionText":"If an antenna is correctly matched to atransmitter, the length of transmission line:"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"prevent frequency drift"},{"letter":"B","text":"overcome fading of the transmitted signal"},{"letter":"C","text":"transfer the maximum amount of power tothe antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"ensure that the radiated signal has theintended polarization"}],"questionText":"The reason that an RF transmission lineshould be matched at the transmitter end isto:"},{"questionId":"B-006-006-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2:1"},{"letter":"B","text":"4:1"},{"letter":"C","text":"10:1"},{"letter":"D","text":"6:1"}],"questionText":"If the centre impedance of a folded dipole isapproximately 300 ohms, and you are usingRG8U (50 ohms) coaxial lines, what is theratio required to have the line and theantenna matched?"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The electric and magnetic lines of force ofa radio wave are perpendicular to theEarth's surface"},{"letter":"B","text":"The electric lines of force of a radio waveare perpendicular to the Earth's surface"},{"letter":"C","text":"The magnetic lines of force of a radiowave are parallel to the Earth's surface"},{"letter":"D","text":"The electric lines of force of a radio waveare parallel to the Earth's surface"}],"questionText":"What does horizontal wave polarizationmean?"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The electric and magnetic lines of force ofa radio wave are parallel to the Earth'ssurface"},{"letter":"B","text":"The electric lines of force of a radio waveare parallel to the Earth's surface"},{"letter":"C","text":"The electric lines of force of a radio waveare perpendicular to the Earth's surface"},{"letter":"D","text":"The magnetic lines of force of a radiowave are perpendicular to the Earth'ssurface"}],"questionText":"What does vertical wave polarization mean?"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Helical"},{"letter":"B","text":"Vertical"},{"letter":"C","text":"Circular"},{"letter":"D","text":"Horizontal"}],"questionText":"What electromagnetic wave polarizationdoes a Yagi antenna have when its elementsare parallel to the Earth's surface?"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Parabolical"},{"letter":"B","text":"Vertical"},{"letter":"C","text":"Circular"},{"letter":"D","text":"Horizontal"}],"questionText":"What electromagnetic wave polarizationdoes a half-wavelength antenna have when itis perpendicular to the Earth's surface?"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the magnetic field"},{"letter":"B","text":"the orientation of the electric field relativeto the Earth's surface"},{"letter":"C","text":"the height of the antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"the type of antenna"}],"questionText":"Polarization of an antenna is determined by:"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A cardioid"},{"letter":"B","text":"A unidirectional cardioid"},{"letter":"C","text":"A sphere"},{"letter":"D","text":"A parabola"}],"questionText":"What is the antenna radiation pattern for anisotropic radiator?"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"random length of wire"},{"letter":"B","text":"horizontal ground-plane antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"horizontal dipole antenna"},{"letter":"D","text":"vertical ground-plane antenna"}],"questionText":"VHF signals from a mobile station using avertical whip antenna will normally be bestreceived using a:"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"mounted vertically"},{"letter":"B","text":"fed with the correct type of RF"},{"letter":"C","text":"too near to the ground"},{"letter":"D","text":"parallel with the ground"}],"questionText":"A dipole antenna will emit a verticallypolarized wave if it is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"polarized at right angles to original"},{"letter":"B","text":"horizontally polarized"},{"letter":"C","text":"polarized in any plane"},{"letter":"D","text":"vertically polarized"}],"questionText":"If an electromagnetic wave leaves anantenna vertically polarized, it will arrive atthe receiving antenna, by ground wave:"},{"questionId":"B-006-007-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"without any comparative difference"},{"letter":"B","text":"if the antenna changes the polarization"},{"letter":"C","text":"at greater strength"},{"letter":"D","text":"at weaker strength"}],"questionText":"Compared with a horizontal antenna, avertical antenna will receive a verticallypolarized radio wave:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It increases"},{"letter":"B","text":"It stays the same"},{"letter":"C","text":"It disappears"},{"letter":"D","text":"It decreases"}],"questionText":"If an antenna is made longer, what happensto its resonant frequency?"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It disappears"},{"letter":"B","text":"It decreases"},{"letter":"C","text":"It increases"},{"letter":"D","text":"It stays the same"}],"questionText":"If an antenna is made shorter, what happensto its resonant frequency?"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"12 metres (39.4 ft)"},{"letter":"B","text":"15 metres (49.2 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"4 metres (13.1 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"32 metres (105 ft)"}],"questionText":"The wavelength for a frequency of 25 MHz is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3000 kilometres per second"},{"letter":"B","text":"150 kilometres per second"},{"letter":"C","text":"186 000 kilometres per second"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 000 kilometres per second"}],"questionText":"The velocity of propagation of radiofrequency energy in free space is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"decrease the resonant frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"increase the resonant frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"have little effect"},{"letter":"D","text":"have no change on the resonantfrequency"}],"questionText":"Adding a series inductance to an antennawould:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"is the same as the speed of light"},{"letter":"B","text":"is infinite in space"},{"letter":"C","text":"is always less than half speed of light"},{"letter":"D","text":"varies directly with frequency"}],"questionText":"The speed of a radio wave:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"prevent any loss of radio waves by theantenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"limit the electrical length of the antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"increase the effective antenna length"},{"letter":"D","text":"allow the antenna to be more easily heldvertically"}],"questionText":"At the end of suspended antenna wire,insulators are used. These act to:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ground one end"},{"letter":"B","text":"centre feed it with TV ribbon transmissionline"},{"letter":"C","text":"lengthen it"},{"letter":"D","text":"shorten it"}],"questionText":"To lower the resonant frequency of anantenna, the operator should:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a coil and capacitor in parallel"},{"letter":"B","text":"large wire-wound resistors"},{"letter":"C","text":"coils wrapped around a ferrite rod"},{"letter":"D","text":"hollow metal cans"}],"questionText":"One solution to multiband operation with ashortened radiator is the \"trap dipole\" or trapvertical. These \"traps\" are actually:"},{"questionId":"B-006-008-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1500 m (4921 ft)"},{"letter":"B","text":"30 m (98 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"150 m (492 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"360 m (1181 ft)"}],"questionText":"The wavelength corresponding to afrequency of 2 MHz is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-001","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An antenna where wave traps are used tomagnetically couple the elements"},{"letter":"B","text":"An antenna where some elements obtaintheir radio energy by induction orradiation from a driven element"},{"letter":"C","text":"An antenna where the driven elementobtains its radio energy by induction orradiation from director elements"},{"letter":"D","text":"An antenna where all elements are drivenby direct connection to the transmissionline"}],"questionText":"What is a parasitic beam antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Use traps on the elements"},{"letter":"B","text":"Use tapered-diameter elements"},{"letter":"C","text":"Use closer element spacing"},{"letter":"D","text":"Use larger diameter elements"}],"questionText":"How can the bandwidth of a parasitic beamantenna be increased?"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A major lobe will develop in the horizontalplane, parallel to the two elements"},{"letter":"B","text":"A major lobe will develop in the verticalplane, away from the ground"},{"letter":"C","text":"The radiation pattern will not be affected"},{"letter":"D","text":"A major lobe will develop in the horizontalplane, from the dipole toward theparasitic element"}],"questionText":"If a parasitic element slightly shorter than ahorizontal dipole antenna is placed parallelto the dipole 0.1 wavelength from it and atthe same height, what effect will this have onthe antenna's radiation pattern?"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"front-to-back ratio"},{"letter":"B","text":"impedance"},{"letter":"C","text":"polarization"},{"letter":"D","text":"bandwidth"}],"questionText":"The property of an antenna, which definesthe range of frequencies to which it willrespond, is called its:"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6.0 dB"},{"letter":"B","text":"2.1 dB"},{"letter":"C","text":"1.5 dB"},{"letter":"D","text":"3.0 dB"}],"questionText":"Approximately how much gain does a half-wave dipole have over an isotropic radiator?"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The power amplifier gain minus thetransmission line losses"},{"letter":"B","text":"The numerical ratio relating the radiatedsignal strength of an antenna to that ofanother antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"The numerical ratio of the signal in theforward direction to the signal in the backdirection"},{"letter":"D","text":"The numerical ratio of the amount ofpower radiated by an antenna comparedto the transmitter output power"}],"questionText":"What is meant by antenna gain?"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The angle between the half-powerradiation points"},{"letter":"B","text":"The angle formed between two imaginarylines drawn through the ends of theelements"},{"letter":"C","text":"The frequency range over which theantenna may be expected to perform well"},{"letter":"D","text":"Antenna length divided by the number ofelements"}],"questionText":"What is meant by antenna bandwidth?"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-009","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Minimum radiation from the ends,maximum broadside"},{"letter":"B","text":"Maximum radiation from the ends,minimum broadside"},{"letter":"C","text":"Omnidirectional"},{"letter":"D","text":"Maximum radiation at 45 degrees to theplane of the antenna"}],"questionText":"In free space, what is the radiationcharacteristic of a half-wave dipole?"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"interpolated"},{"letter":"B","text":"isotropic"},{"letter":"C","text":"ideal"},{"letter":"D","text":"ionosphere"}],"questionText":"The gain of an antenna, especially on VHFand above, is quoted in dBi. The \"i\" in thisexpression stands for:"},{"questionId":"B-006-009-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"undefined"},{"letter":"B","text":"the ratio of the forward power at the 3 dBpoints to the power radiated in thebackward direction"},{"letter":"C","text":"the ratio of the maximum forward powerin the major lobe to the maximumbackward power radiation"},{"letter":"D","text":"the forward power of the major lobe to thepower in the backward direction bothbeing measured at the 3 dB points"}],"questionText":"The front-to-back ratio of a beam antenna is:"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6.76 metres (22.2 ft)"},{"letter":"B","text":"3.36 metres (11.0 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"3.6 metres (11.8 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"7.2 metres (23.6 ft)"}],"questionText":"If you made a quarter-wavelength verticalantenna for 21.125 MHz, how long would itbe?"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"128 cm (50.4 in)"},{"letter":"B","text":"105 cm (41.3 in)"},{"letter":"C","text":"134.6 cm (53 in)"},{"letter":"D","text":"64 cm (25.2 in)"}],"questionText":"If you made a half-wavelength verticalantenna for 223 MHz, how long would it be?"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A 5/8-wavelength antenna has more gain"},{"letter":"B","text":"A 5/8-wavelength antenna has lesscorona loss"},{"letter":"C","text":"A 5/8-wavelength antenna is easier toinstall on a car"},{"letter":"D","text":"A 5/8-wavelength antenna can handlemore power"}],"questionText":"Why is a 5/8-wavelength vertical antennabetter than a 1/4-wavelength vertical antennafor VHF or UHF mobile operations?"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It goes out equally well in all horizontaldirections"},{"letter":"B","text":"Most of it is aimed high into the sky"},{"letter":"C","text":"Most of it goes equally in two oppositedirections"},{"letter":"D","text":"Most of it goes in one direction"}],"questionText":"If a magnetic-base whip antenna is placedon the roof of a car, in what direction does itsend out radio energy?"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It lowers the radiation angle"},{"letter":"B","text":"It brings the feed point impedance closerto 50 ohms"},{"letter":"C","text":"It increases the radiation angle"},{"letter":"D","text":"It brings the feed point impedance closerto 300 ohms"}],"questionText":"What is an advantage of downward slopingradials on a ground plane antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It stays the same"},{"letter":"B","text":"It approaches zero"},{"letter":"C","text":"It increases"},{"letter":"D","text":"It decreases"}],"questionText":"What happens to the feed point impedanceof a ground-plane antenna when its radialsare changed from horizontal to downward-sloping?"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"50 ohms coaxial cable"},{"letter":"B","text":"300 ohms balanced transmission line"},{"letter":"C","text":"75 ohms balanced transmission line"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 ohms coaxial cable"}],"questionText":"Which of the following transmission lines willgive the best match to the base of a quarter-wave ground-plane antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"be easy to feed with TV ribbontransmission line"},{"letter":"B","text":"receive signals equally well from allcompass points around it"},{"letter":"C","text":"be very sensitive to signals coming fromhorizontal antennas"},{"letter":"D","text":"require few insulators"}],"questionText":"The main characteristic of a vertical antennais that it will:"},{"questionId":"B-006-010-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To lower the Q"},{"letter":"B","text":"To filter out electrical noise"},{"letter":"C","text":"To tune out capacitive reactance"},{"letter":"D","text":"To lower the losses"}],"questionText":"Why is a loading coil often used with an HFmobile vertical antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"One"},{"letter":"B","text":"Two"},{"letter":"C","text":"Three"},{"letter":"D","text":"None"}],"questionText":"How many directly driven elements do mostYagi antennas have?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10.21 metres (33.5 feet)"},{"letter":"B","text":"5.21 metres (17 feet)"},{"letter":"C","text":"10.67 metres (35 feet)"},{"letter":"D","text":"20.12 metres (66 feet)"}],"questionText":"Approximately how long is the drivenelement of a Yagi antenna for 14.0 MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"12.8 metres (42 feet)"},{"letter":"B","text":"6.4 metres (21 feet)"},{"letter":"C","text":"5.18 metres (17 feet)"},{"letter":"D","text":"3.2 metres (10.5 feet)"}],"questionText":"Approximately how long is the directorelement of a Yagi antenna for 21.1 MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"10.67 metres (35 feet)"},{"letter":"B","text":"2.66 metres (8.75 feet)"},{"letter":"C","text":"5.33 metres (17.5 feet)"},{"letter":"D","text":"4.88 metres (16 feet)"}],"questionText":"Approximately how long is the reflectorelement of a Yagi antenna for 28.1 MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Gain increases"},{"letter":"B","text":"SWR increases"},{"letter":"C","text":"Weight decreases"},{"letter":"D","text":"Wind load decreases"}],"questionText":"What is one effect of increasing the boomlength and adding directors to a Yagiantenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High gain, lower loss and a low SWR"},{"letter":"B","text":"High front-to-back ratio and lower inputresistance"},{"letter":"C","text":"Shorter boom length, lower weight andwind resistance"},{"letter":"D","text":"High gain, less critical tuning and widerbandwidth"}],"questionText":"What are some advantages of a Yagi withwide element spacing?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It provides excellent omnidirectionalcoverage in the horizontal plane"},{"letter":"B","text":"It is smaller, less expensive and easier toerect than a dipole or vertical antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"It provides the highest possible angle ofradiation for the HF bands"},{"letter":"D","text":"It helps reduce interference from otherstations off to the side or behind"}],"questionText":"Why is a Yagi antenna often used forradiocommunications on the 20-metre band?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The number of directors versus thenumber of reflectors"},{"letter":"B","text":"The power radiated in the major radiationlobe compared to the power radiated inexactly the opposite direction"},{"letter":"C","text":"The relative position of the driven elementwith respect to the reflectors anddirectors"},{"letter":"D","text":"The power radiated in the major radiationlobe compared to the power radiated 90degrees away from that direction"}],"questionText":"What does \"antenna front-to-back ratio\"mean in reference to a Yagi antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-011-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"0.10"},{"letter":"B","text":"0.50"},{"letter":"C","text":"0.75"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.20"}],"questionText":"The spacing between the elements on athree-element Yagi antenna, representingthe best overall choice, is _____ of awavelength."},{"questionId":"B-006-011-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"20 dBi"},{"letter":"B","text":"10 dBi"},{"letter":"C","text":"13 dBi"},{"letter":"D","text":"7 dBi"}],"questionText":"If the forward gain of a six-element Yagi isabout 10 dBi, what would the gain of two ofthese antennas be if they were \"stacked\"?"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"28.55 metres (93.45 ft)"},{"letter":"B","text":"10.16 metres (33.26 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"5.08 metres (16.62 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"10.5 metres (34.37 ft)"}],"questionText":"If you made a half-wavelength dipole antennafor 28.150 MHz, how long would it be?"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It usually produces vertically polarizedradiation"},{"letter":"B","text":"It must be longer than 1 wavelength"},{"letter":"C","text":"You must use an inverted T matchingnetwork for multi-band operation"},{"letter":"D","text":"You may experience RF feedback in yourstation"}],"questionText":"What is one disadvantage of a random wireantenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-003","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is a figure-eight, off both ends of theantenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"It is a figure-eight, perpendicular to theantenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"It is a circle (equal radiation in alldirections)"},{"letter":"D","text":"It is two smaller lobes on one side of theantenna, and one larger lobe on the otherside"}],"questionText":"What is the low angle radiation pattern of anideal half-wavelength dipole HF antenna infree space installed parallel to the Earth?"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"52 and 100"},{"letter":"B","text":"52 and 200"},{"letter":"C","text":"73 and 300"},{"letter":"D","text":"73 and 150"}],"questionText":"The impedances in ohms at the feed point ofthe dipole and folded dipole in free spaceare, respectively:"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"equally in all directions"},{"letter":"B","text":"mostly to the East and West"},{"letter":"C","text":"mostly to the South and North"},{"letter":"D","text":"mostly to the South"}],"questionText":"A horizontal dipole transmitting antenna,installed at an ideal height so that the endsare pointing North/South, radiates:"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is greater"},{"letter":"B","text":"It is essentially the same"},{"letter":"C","text":"It is less than 50%"},{"letter":"D","text":"It is 0.707 times the bandwidth"}],"questionText":"How does the bandwidth of a folded dipoleantenna compare with that of a simple dipoleantenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is too sharply directional at lowerfrequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"It must be neutralized"},{"letter":"C","text":"It can only be used for one band"},{"letter":"D","text":"It may radiate harmonics more readily"}],"questionText":"What is a disadvantage of using an antennaequipped with traps?"},{"questionId":"B-006-012-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"75 meters (245 ft)"},{"letter":"B","text":"38 meters (125 ft)"},{"letter":"C","text":"32 meters (105 ft)"},{"letter":"D","text":"45 meters (145 ft)"}],"questionText":"If you were to cut a half wave dipole for 3.75MHz, what would be its approximate length?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A center-fed wire 1/2-electricalwavelength long"},{"letter":"B","text":"A vertical conductor 1/4-electricalwavelength high, fed at the bottom"},{"letter":"C","text":"Four straight, parallel elements in linewith each other, each approximately 1/2-electrical wavelength long"},{"letter":"D","text":"Two or more parallel four-sided wireloops, each approximately one-electricalwavelength long"}],"questionText":"What is a cubical quad antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An antenna system made of three verticalantennas, arranged in a triangular shape"},{"letter":"B","text":"An antenna made from several triangularcoils of wire on an insulating form"},{"letter":"C","text":"An antenna whose elements are each athree sided loop whose total length isapproximately one electrical wavelength"},{"letter":"D","text":"A large copper ring or wire loop, used indirection finding"}],"questionText":"What is a delta loop antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"14.33 metres (47 feet)"},{"letter":"B","text":"143 metres (469 feet)"},{"letter":"C","text":"3.54 metres (11.7 feet)"},{"letter":"D","text":"0.36 metres (1.17 feet)"}],"questionText":"Approximately how long is each side of acubical quad antenna driven element for 21.4MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"53.34 metres (175 feet)"},{"letter":"B","text":"7.13 metres (23.4 feet)"},{"letter":"C","text":"5.36 metres (17.6 feet)"},{"letter":"D","text":"21.43 metres (70.3 feet)"}],"questionText":"Approximately how long is each side of acubical quad antenna driven element for 14.3MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3.5 metres (11.5 feet)"},{"letter":"B","text":"2.67 metres (8.75 feet)"},{"letter":"C","text":"7.13 metres (23.4 feet)"},{"letter":"D","text":"10.67 metres (35 feet)"}],"questionText":"Approximately how long is each leg of asymmetrical delta loop antenna drivenelement for 28.7 MHz?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"They perform poorly above HF"},{"letter":"B","text":"They compare favourably with a three-element Yagi"},{"letter":"C","text":"They perform very well only at HF"},{"letter":"D","text":"They are effective only when constructedusing insulated wire"}],"questionText":"Which statement about two-element deltaloops and quad antennas is true?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The quad has more directivity in thehorizontal plane but less directivity in thevertical plane"},{"letter":"B","text":"The quad has less directivity in thehorizontal plane but more directivity in thevertical plane"},{"letter":"C","text":"The quad has less directivity in bothhorizontal and vertical planes"},{"letter":"D","text":"The quad has more directivity in bothhorizontal and vertical planes"}],"questionText":"Compared to a dipole antenna, what are thedirectional radiation characteristics of acubical quad antenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The number of directors versus thenumber of reflectors"},{"letter":"B","text":"The power radiated in the major radiationlobe compared to the power radiated inexactly the opposite direction"},{"letter":"C","text":"The relative position of the driven elementwith respect to the reflectors anddirectors"},{"letter":"D","text":"The power radiated in the major radiationlobe compared to the power radiated 90degrees away from that direction"}],"questionText":"What does the term \"antenna front-to-backratio\" mean in reference to a delta loopantenna?"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"one-half wavelength"},{"letter":"B","text":"one wavelength"},{"letter":"C","text":"three-quarters of a wavelength"},{"letter":"D","text":"two wavelengths"}],"questionText":"The cubical \"quad\" or \"quad\" antennaconsists of two or more square loops of wire.The driven element has an approximateoverall length of:"},{"questionId":"B-006-013-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"one-quarter of a wavelength"},{"letter":"B","text":"two wavelengths"},{"letter":"C","text":"one-half of a wavelength"},{"letter":"D","text":"one wavelength"}],"questionText":"The delta loop antenna consists of two ormore triangular structures mounted on aboom. The overall length of the drivenelement is approximately:"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Tunnel propagation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Skywave propagation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Auroral propagation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Line-of-sight propagation"}],"questionText":"What type of propagation usually occursfrom one hand-held VHF transceiver toanother nearby?"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It is much longer"},{"letter":"B","text":"It is much shorter"},{"letter":"C","text":"It is about the same"},{"letter":"D","text":"It depends on the weather"}],"questionText":"How does the range of sky-wave propagationcompare to ground-wave propagation?"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Ground-wave propagation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Earth-Moon-Earth propagation"},{"letter":"C","text":"Sky-wave propagation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Tropospheric propagation"}],"questionText":"When a signal is returned to Earth by theionosphere, what is this called?"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By plane wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"By geometric wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"By direct wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"By sky wave"}],"questionText":"How are VHF signals propagated within therange of the visible horizon?"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"tropospheric wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"ground wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"inverted wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"ionospheric wave"}],"questionText":"Skywave is another name for:"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"inverted wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"ground wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"tropospheric wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"ionospheric wave"}],"questionText":"That portion of the radiation which is directlyaffected by the surface of the Earth is called:"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"is more at higher frequencies"},{"letter":"B","text":"is the same for all frequencies"},{"letter":"C","text":"is less at higher frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"depends on the maximum usablefrequency"}],"questionText":"The distance travelled by ground waves:"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"surface wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"skip wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"ionospheric wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"F layer"}],"questionText":"The radio wave which follows a path from thetransmitter to the ionosphere and back toEarth is known correctly as the:"},{"questionId":"B-007-001-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ground wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"skip wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"surface wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"ionospheric wave"}],"questionText":"Reception of high frequency (HF) radiowaves beyond 4000 km is generally madepossible by:"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Release of fluorocarbons into theatmosphere"},{"letter":"B","text":"Temperature changes ionizing the outeratmosphere"},{"letter":"C","text":"Solar radiation ionizing the outeratmosphere"},{"letter":"D","text":"Lightning ionizing the outer atmosphere"}],"questionText":"What causes the ionosphere to form?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Thermal"},{"letter":"B","text":"Ultraviolet"},{"letter":"C","text":"Microwave"},{"letter":"D","text":"Ionized particles"}],"questionText":"What type of solar radiation is mostresponsible for ionization in the outeratmosphere?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The D region"},{"letter":"B","text":"The E region"},{"letter":"C","text":"The F region"},{"letter":"D","text":"The A region"}],"questionText":"Which ionospheric region is closest to theEarth?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The E region"},{"letter":"B","text":"The D region"},{"letter":"C","text":"The F2 region"},{"letter":"D","text":"The F1 region"}],"questionText":"Which region of the ionosphere is the leastuseful for long distance radio-wavepropagation?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Troposphere and stratosphere"},{"letter":"B","text":"Electrostatic and electromagnetic"},{"letter":"C","text":"D and E"},{"letter":"D","text":"F1 and F2"}],"questionText":"What two sub-regions of ionosphere existonly in the daytime?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Midnight"},{"letter":"B","text":"Dusk"},{"letter":"C","text":"Midday"},{"letter":"D","text":"Dawn"}],"questionText":"When is the ionosphere most ionized?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because it is the lowest ionosphericregion"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because it does not absorb radio wavesas much as other ionospheric regions"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because it is the highest ionosphericregion"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because it exists only at night"}],"questionText":"Why is the F2 region mainly responsible forthe longest distance radio-wavepropagation?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Because of a lack of activity"},{"letter":"B","text":"Because of D-region absorption"},{"letter":"C","text":"Because of auroral propagation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Because of magnetic flux"}],"questionText":"What is the main reason the 160, 80 and 40metre amateur bands tend to be useful onlyfor short-distance communications duringdaylight hours?"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"F1 and F2"},{"letter":"B","text":"D1 and D2"},{"letter":"C","text":"E1 and E2"},{"letter":"D","text":"A and B"}],"questionText":"During the day, one of the ionospheric layerssplits into two parts called:"},{"questionId":"B-007-002-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"sporadic"},{"letter":"B","text":"above the F layer"},{"letter":"C","text":"below the F layer"},{"letter":"D","text":"below the D layer"}],"questionText":"The position of the E layer in the ionosphereis:"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"An area covered by sky-wave propagation"},{"letter":"B","text":"An area covered by ground-wavepropagation"},{"letter":"C","text":"An area which is too far away for ground-wave propagation, but too close for sky-wave propagation"},{"letter":"D","text":"An area which is too far away for ground-wave or sky-wave propagation"}],"questionText":"What is a skip zone?"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"2000 km (1250 miles)"},{"letter":"B","text":"300 km (190 miles)"},{"letter":"C","text":"4000 km (2500 miles)"},{"letter":"D","text":"None, the F2 region does not supportradio-wave propagation"}],"questionText":"What is the maximum distance along theEarth's surface that is normally covered inone hop using the F2 region?"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"4000 km (2500 miles)"},{"letter":"B","text":"None, the E region does not supportradio-wave propagation"},{"letter":"C","text":"2000 km (1250 miles)"},{"letter":"D","text":"300 km (190 miles)"}],"questionText":"What is the maximum distance along theEarth's surface that is normally covered inone hop using the E region?"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a zone of silence caused by lost skywaves"},{"letter":"B","text":"a zone between any two refracted waves"},{"letter":"C","text":"a zone between the antenna and thereturn of the first refracted wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"a zone between the end of the groundwave and the point where the firstrefracted wave returns to Earth"}],"questionText":"Skip zone is:"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Back scatter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Tropospheric scatter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Multihop"},{"letter":"D","text":"Sporadic \"E\""}],"questionText":"The distance to Europe from your location isapproximately 5000 km. What sort ofpropagation is the most likely to be involved?"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"maximum usable frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"skip distance"},{"letter":"C","text":"skip zone"},{"letter":"D","text":"angle of radiation"}],"questionText":"The distance from the transmitter to thenearest point where the sky wave returns tothe Earth is called the:"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"the minimum distance reached by asignal after one reflection by theionosphere"},{"letter":"B","text":"the maximum distance reached by asignal after one reflection by theionosphere"},{"letter":"C","text":"the minimum distance reached by aground-wave signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"the maximum distance a signal will travelby both a ground wave and reflected wave"}],"questionText":"Skip distance is the:"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"selective fading of local signals"},{"letter":"B","text":"high gain antennas being used"},{"letter":"C","text":"local cloud cover"},{"letter":"D","text":"reflection and refraction from theionosphere"}],"questionText":"Skip distance is a term associated withsignals from the ionosphere. Skip effects aredue to:"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"polarization is vertical"},{"letter":"B","text":"ionosphere is most densely ionized"},{"letter":"C","text":"signal given out is strongest"},{"letter":"D","text":"angle between the ground and theradiation is smallest"}],"questionText":"The skip distance of a sky wave will begreatest when the:"},{"questionId":"B-007-003-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"decreases"},{"letter":"B","text":"becomes greater"},{"letter":"C","text":"stays the same"},{"letter":"D","text":"varies regularly"}],"questionText":"If the height of the reflecting layer of theionosphere increases, the skip distance of ahigh frequency (HF) transmission:"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It refracts the radio waves back to Earth"},{"letter":"B","text":"It has little or no effect on 80-metre radiowaves"},{"letter":"C","text":"It absorbs the signals"},{"letter":"D","text":"It bends the radio waves out into space"}],"questionText":"What effect does the D region of theionosphere have on lower frequency HFsignals in the daytime?"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The splitting of the F region"},{"letter":"B","text":"The weather below the ionosphere"},{"letter":"C","text":"The ionization of the D region"},{"letter":"D","text":"The presence of ionized clouds in the Eregion"}],"questionText":"What causes distant AM broadcast and 160metre ham band stations not to be heardduring daytime hours?"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"baffling"},{"letter":"B","text":"absorption"},{"letter":"C","text":"skip"},{"letter":"D","text":"fading"}],"questionText":"Two or more parts of the radio wave followdifferent paths during propagation and thismay result in phase differences at thereceiver. This \"change\" at the receiver iscalled:"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"fluctuation"},{"letter":"B","text":"path loss"},{"letter":"C","text":"fading"},{"letter":"D","text":"absorption"}],"questionText":"A change or variation in signal strength atthe antenna, caused by differences in pathlengths, is called:"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"prevent communications by ground wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"increase the maximum usable frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"cause a fade-out of sky-wave signals"},{"letter":"D","text":"produce extreme weather changes"}],"questionText":"The usual effect of ionospheric storms is to:"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The ionosphere can change thepolarization of the signal from moment tomoment"},{"letter":"B","text":"The ground wave and the sky wavecontinually shift the polarization"},{"letter":"C","text":"Anomalies in the Earth's magnetic fieldproduce a profound effect on HFpolarization but not on VHF & UHFfrequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"Greater selectivity is possible with HFreceivers making changes in polarizationredundant"}],"questionText":"On the VHF and UHF bands, polarization ofthe receiving antenna is very important inrelation to the transmitting antenna, yet onHF bands it is relatively unimportant. Why isthat so?"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Large changes in the height of theionosphere at the receiving stationordinarily occurring shortly before sunriseand sunset"},{"letter":"B","text":"Phase differences between radio wavecomponents of the same transmission,as experienced at the receiving station"},{"letter":"C","text":"Small changes in beam heading at thereceiving station"},{"letter":"D","text":"Time differences between the receivingand transmitting stations"}],"questionText":"What causes selective fading?"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only the receiver bandwidth determinesthe selective fading effect"},{"letter":"B","text":"It is more pronounced at narrowbandwidths"},{"letter":"C","text":"It is more pronounced at wide bandwidths"},{"letter":"D","text":"It is the same for both wide and narrowbandwidths"}],"questionText":"How does the bandwidth of a transmittedsignal affect selective fading?"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-010","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Parabolic interaction"},{"letter":"B","text":"Reflections"},{"letter":"C","text":"Passage through magnetic fields(Faraday rotation)"},{"letter":"D","text":"Refractions"}],"questionText":"Polarization change often takes place onradio waves that are propagated over longdistances. Which of these does not causepolarization change?"},{"questionId":"B-007-004-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"a high-pitch squeal at the receiver"},{"letter":"B","text":"little or no phase-shift distortion"},{"letter":"C","text":"phase-shift distortion"},{"letter":"D","text":"signal cancellation at the receiver"}],"questionText":"Reflection of a SSB transmission from theionosphere causes:"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-001","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The more sunspots there are, the lessthe ionization"},{"letter":"B","text":"Unless there are sunspots, the ionizationis zero"},{"letter":"C","text":"They have no effect"},{"letter":"D","text":"The more sunspots there are, the greaterthe ionization"}],"questionText":"How do sunspots change the ionization ofthe atmosphere?"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"7 years"},{"letter":"B","text":"11 years"},{"letter":"C","text":"17 years"},{"letter":"D","text":"5 years"}],"questionText":"How long is an average sunspot cycle?"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A measure of solar activity that comparesdaily readings with results from the lastsix months"},{"letter":"B","text":"A measure of solar activity that is takenannually"},{"letter":"C","text":"A measure of solar activity that is takenat a specific frequency"},{"letter":"D","text":"Another name for the American sunspotnumber"}],"questionText":"What is the solar-flux index?"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The F1 region of the ionosphere"},{"letter":"B","text":"Lunar tidal effects"},{"letter":"C","text":"Solar radiation"},{"letter":"D","text":"The F2 region of the ionosphere"}],"questionText":"What influences all radiocommunicationbeyond ground-wave or line-of-sight ranges?"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Infrared and gamma-ray emissions"},{"letter":"B","text":"Electromagnetic and particle emissions"},{"letter":"C","text":"Subaudible and audio-frequencyemissions"},{"letter":"D","text":"Polar region and equatorial emissions"}],"questionText":"Which two types of radiation from the suninfluence propagation?"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"High frequency radio signals areabsorbed"},{"letter":"B","text":"Frequencies up to 100 MHz or higher arenormally usable for long-distancecommunication"},{"letter":"C","text":"High frequency radio signals becomeweak and distorted"},{"letter":"D","text":"Frequencies up to 40 MHz or even higherbecome usable for long-distancecommunication"}],"questionText":"When sunspot numbers are high, how ispropagation affected?"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-008","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"aurora borealis"},{"letter":"B","text":"atmospheric conditions"},{"letter":"C","text":"sun"},{"letter":"D","text":"ionosphere"}],"questionText":"All communication frequencies throughoutthe spectrum are affected in varying degreesby the:"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"1 year"},{"letter":"B","text":"11 years"},{"letter":"C","text":"3 years"},{"letter":"D","text":"6 years"}],"questionText":"Average duration of a solar cycle is:"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"upper atmosphere weather conditions"},{"letter":"B","text":"the amount of solar radiation"},{"letter":"C","text":"the power of the transmitted signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"the receiver sensitivity"}],"questionText":"The ability of the ionosphere to reflect highfrequency radio signals depends on:"},{"questionId":"B-007-005-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"centuries"},{"letter":"B","text":"years"},{"letter":"C","text":"months"},{"letter":"D","text":"days"}],"questionText":"HF radio propagation cycles have a period ofapproximately 11:"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-002","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The temperature of the ionosphere"},{"letter":"B","text":"The speed of the winds in the upperatmosphere"},{"letter":"C","text":"The type of weather just below theionosphere"},{"letter":"D","text":"The amount of radiation received from thesun, mainly ultraviolet"}],"questionText":"What causes the maximum usablefrequency to vary?"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The lowest frequency signal that willreach its intended destination"},{"letter":"B","text":"The highest frequency signal that is mostabsorbed by the ionosphere"},{"letter":"C","text":"The lowest frequency signal that is mostabsorbed by the ionosphere"},{"letter":"D","text":"The highest frequency signal that willreach its intended destination"}],"questionText":"What does maximum usable frequencymean?"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-004","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Try a higher frequency band"},{"letter":"B","text":"Try the other sideband"},{"letter":"C","text":"Try a different antenna polarization"},{"letter":"D","text":"Try a different frequency shift"}],"questionText":"What can be done at an amateur station tocontinue HF communications during asudden ionospheric disturbance?"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Listen for signals from 39-metrebroadcast stations"},{"letter":"B","text":"Listen for WWVH time signals on 20MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"Listen for signals from 10-metre beaconstations"},{"letter":"D","text":"Listen for signals from 20-metre beaconstations"}],"questionText":"What is one way to determine if themaximum usable frequency (MUF) is highenough to support 28 MHz propagationbetween your station and western Europe?"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"They are completely absorbed by theionosphere"},{"letter":"B","text":"They pass through the ionosphere"},{"letter":"C","text":"They are bent back to the Earth"},{"letter":"D","text":"They are changed to a frequency abovethe MUF"}],"questionText":"What usually happens to radio waves withfrequencies below the maximum usablefrequency (MUF) when they are sent into theionosphere?"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Only at the minimum point of the solarcycle"},{"letter":"B","text":"Only at the maximum point of the solarcycle"},{"letter":"C","text":"At the summer solstice"},{"letter":"D","text":"At any point in the solar cycle"}],"questionText":"At what point in the solar cycle does the 20-metre band usually support worldwidepropagation during daylight hours?"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"sunspot frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"maximum usable frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"skip distance"},{"letter":"D","text":"speed of light"}],"questionText":"If we transmit a signal, the frequency ofwhich is so high we no longer receive areflection from the ionosphere, the signalfrequency is above the:"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"evening in winter"},{"letter":"B","text":"evening in summer"},{"letter":"C","text":"daytime in winter"},{"letter":"D","text":"daytime in summer"}],"questionText":"Communication on the 80 metre band isgenerally most difficult during:"},{"questionId":"B-007-006-011","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"30 metres"},{"letter":"B","text":"20 metres"},{"letter":"C","text":"160 and 80 metres"},{"letter":"D","text":"40 metres"}],"questionText":"During summer daytime, which bands arethe most difficult for communications beyondground wave?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"The E region"},{"letter":"B","text":"The F2 region"},{"letter":"C","text":"The F1 region"},{"letter":"D","text":"The D region"}],"questionText":"Which ionospheric region most affects sky-wave propagation on the 6 metre band?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-002","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It garbles the signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"It reverses the sideband of the signal"},{"letter":"C","text":"It lets you contact stations farther away"},{"letter":"D","text":"It causes them to travel shorter distances"}],"questionText":"What effect does tropospheric bending haveon 2-metre radio waves?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A temperature inversion"},{"letter":"B","text":"Lightning between the transmitting andreceiving stations"},{"letter":"C","text":"An aurora to the north"},{"letter":"D","text":"A very low pressure area"}],"questionText":"What causes tropospheric ducting of radiowaves?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"ionospheric wave"},{"letter":"B","text":"tropospheric wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"inverted wave"},{"letter":"D","text":"ground wave"}],"questionText":"That portion of the radiation kept close to theEarth's surface due to bending in theatmosphere is called the:"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Variations in E-region height caused bysunspot variations"},{"letter":"B","text":"A brief decrease in VHF signals causedby sunspot variations"},{"letter":"C","text":"Patches of dense ionization at E-regionheight"},{"letter":"D","text":"Partial tropospheric ducting at E-regionheight"}],"questionText":"What is a sporadic-E condition?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"6 metres"},{"letter":"B","text":"160 metres"},{"letter":"C","text":"20 metres"},{"letter":"D","text":"2 metres"}],"questionText":"On which amateur frequency band is theextended-distance propagation effect ofsporadic-E most often observed?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"West"},{"letter":"B","text":"South"},{"letter":"C","text":"North"},{"letter":"D","text":"East"}],"questionText":"In the northern hemisphere, in whichdirection should a directional antenna bepointed to take maximum advantage ofauroral propagation?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"At D-region height"},{"letter":"B","text":"At E-region height"},{"letter":"C","text":"At F-region height"},{"letter":"D","text":"In the equatorial band"}],"questionText":"Where in the ionosphere does auroralactivity occur?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"3200 km (2000 miles)"},{"letter":"B","text":"1600 km (1000 miles)"},{"letter":"C","text":"800 km (500 miles)"},{"letter":"D","text":"2400 km (1500 miles)"}],"questionText":"Excluding enhanced propagation modes,what is the approximate range of normalVHF tropospheric propagation?"},{"questionId":"B-007-007-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Faraday rotation"},{"letter":"B","text":"D-region absorption"},{"letter":"C","text":"Moon bounce (EME) Earth - Moon -Earth"},{"letter":"D","text":"Tropospheric ducting"}],"questionText":"What effect is responsible for propagating aVHF signal over 800 km (500 miles)?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Scatter-mode"},{"letter":"B","text":"Sky-wave with low radiation angle"},{"letter":"C","text":"Ducting"},{"letter":"D","text":"Ground-wave"}],"questionText":"What kind of unusual HF propagation allowsweak signals from the skip zone to be heardoccasionally?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Scatter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Ground-wave"},{"letter":"C","text":"Line-of-sight"},{"letter":"D","text":"Ducting"}],"questionText":"If you receive a weak, distorted signal from adistance, and close to the maximum usablefrequency, what type of propagation isprobably occurring?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Reversed modulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Reversed sidebands"},{"letter":"C","text":"High intelligibility"},{"letter":"D","text":"Rapid flutter or hollow sounding distortion"}],"questionText":"What is a characteristic of HF scattersignals?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Auroral activity and changes in theEarth's magnetic field"},{"letter":"B","text":"Propagation through ground waves thatabsorb much of the signal"},{"letter":"C","text":"The state of the E-region at the point ofrefraction"},{"letter":"D","text":"Energy scattered into the skip zonethrough several radio-wave paths"}],"questionText":"What makes HF scatter signals often sounddistorted?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-005","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Auroral activity absorbs most of thesignal energy"},{"letter":"B","text":"Only a small part of the signal energy isscattered into the skip zone"},{"letter":"C","text":"Propagation through ground wavesabsorbs most of the signal energy"},{"letter":"D","text":"The F region of the ionosphere absorbsmost of the signal energy"}],"questionText":"Why are HF scatter signals usually weak?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Scatter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Short-path skip"},{"letter":"C","text":"Sporadic-E skip"},{"letter":"D","text":"Ground wave"}],"questionText":"What type of propagation may allow a weaksignal to be heard at a distance too far forground-wave propagation but too near fornormal sky-wave propagation?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Ionospheric scatter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Absorption scatter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Meteor scatter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Tropospheric scatter"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not a scattermode?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"40 metres"},{"letter":"B","text":"15 metres"},{"letter":"C","text":"160 metres"},{"letter":"D","text":"6 metres"}],"questionText":"Meteor scatter is most effective on whatband?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Forward scatter"},{"letter":"B","text":"Inverted scatter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Side scatter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Back scatter"}],"questionText":"Which of the following is not a scattermode?"},{"questionId":"B-007-008-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"100 - 300 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"30 - 100 MHz"},{"letter":"C","text":"10 - 30 MHz"},{"letter":"D","text":"3 - 10 MHz"}],"questionText":"In which frequency range is meteor scattermost effective for extended-rangecommunication?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Too much current from the power supply"},{"letter":"B","text":"Too much voltage from the power supply"},{"letter":"C","text":"Interference caused by strong signalsfrom a nearby transmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Interference caused by turning the volumeup too high"}],"questionText":"What is meant by receiver overload?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"If connecting a low pass filter to thetransmitter greatly cuts down theinterference"},{"letter":"B","text":"If the interference is about the same nomatter what frequency is used for thetransmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"If grounding the receiver makes theproblem worse"},{"letter":"D","text":"If connecting a low pass filter to thereceiver greatly cuts down theinterference"}],"questionText":"What is one way to tell if radio frequencyinterference to a receiver is caused by front-end overload?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Receiver overload"},{"letter":"B","text":"Incorrect antenna length"},{"letter":"C","text":"Receiver VR tube discharge"},{"letter":"D","text":"Too little transmitter harmonicsuppression"}],"questionText":"If a neighbour reports television interferencewhenever you transmit, no matter what bandyou use, what is probably the cause of theinterference?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Low-pass"},{"letter":"B","text":"Band-pass"},{"letter":"C","text":"No filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"High-pass"}],"questionText":"What type of filter should be connected to aTV receiver as the first step in trying toprevent RF overload from an amateur HFstation transmission?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"distortion on transmitted voice peaks"},{"letter":"B","text":"interference continuously across the dial"},{"letter":"C","text":"the undesired signal in the background ofthe desired signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"interference only when a broadcast signalis tuned"}],"questionText":"Inter-modulation in a broadcast receiver by anearby transmitter would be noticed in thereceiver as:"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Receiver intermodulation interference"},{"letter":"B","text":"Harmonic interference from other stations"},{"letter":"C","text":"Audio stage overload interference"},{"letter":"D","text":"Audio stage intermodulation interference"}],"questionText":"You have connected your hand-held VHFtransceiver to an outside gain antenna. Younow hear a mixture of signals together withdifferent modulation on your desiredfrequency. What is the nature of thisinterference?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Intermodulation interference"},{"letter":"B","text":"Receiver quieting"},{"letter":"C","text":"Capture effect"},{"letter":"D","text":"Front-end desensitization"}],"questionText":"Two or more strong out-of-band signals mixin your receiver to produce interference on adesired frequency. What is this called?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-009","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"There are many more simplexfrequencies than repeater frequenciesavailable"},{"letter":"B","text":"The strong signal of one mobiletransmitter may desensitize the receiverof the other mobile receiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"Simplex operation does not require theuse of CTCSS tones"},{"letter":"D","text":"There is less time delay using simplexoperation compared to using a repeater"}],"questionText":"Two mobile stations are traveling along thesame road in close proximity to each otherand having trouble communicating through alocal repeater. Why may it be necessary touse simplex operation to communicatebetween these cars?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Insert a low pass filter at the antennaconnector of the television"},{"letter":"B","text":"Insert a high pass filter at the antennaconnector of the television"},{"letter":"C","text":"Insert a low pass filter at the antennaconnector of the HF transmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Insert a high pass filter at the antennaconnector of the HF transmitter"}],"questionText":"A television receiver suffers interference onchannel 5 (76 - 82 MHz) only when youtransmit on 14 MHz. From your home yousee the tower of a commercial FM stationknown to broadcast on 92.5 MHz. Which ofthese solutions would you try first?"},{"questionId":"B-008-001-011","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By using a better antenna"},{"letter":"B","text":"By increasing the receiver RF gain whiledecreasing the AF gain"},{"letter":"C","text":"By adjusting the passband tuning"},{"letter":"D","text":"By installing a suitable filter at thereceiver"}],"questionText":"How can intermodulation be reduced?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Metal-oxide varistors"},{"letter":"B","text":"Bypass inductors"},{"letter":"C","text":"Coils on ferrite cores"},{"letter":"D","text":"Bypass resistors"}],"questionText":"What devices would you install to reduce oreliminate audio-frequency interference tohome entertainment systems?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-003","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Clearly audible speech from thetransmitter's signals"},{"letter":"B","text":"On-and-off humming or clicking"},{"letter":"C","text":"A steady hum whenever the transmitter'scarrier is on the air"},{"letter":"D","text":"Distorted speech from the transmitter'ssignals"}],"questionText":"What sound is heard from a public-addresssystem if audio rectification of a nearbysingle-sideband phone transmission occurs?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-004","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Audible, possibly distorted speech"},{"letter":"B","text":"Muffled, severely distorted speech"},{"letter":"C","text":"A steady whistling"},{"letter":"D","text":"On-and-off humming or clicking"}],"questionText":"What sound is heard from a public-addresssystem if audio rectification of a nearby CWtransmission occurs?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-005","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Use CW only"},{"letter":"B","text":"Use a solid-state transmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"Ensure that all station equipment isproperly grounded"},{"letter":"D","text":"Install bypass capacitors on all powersupply rectifiers"}],"questionText":"How can you minimize the possibility ofaudio rectification of your transmitter'ssignals?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-006","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"harmonics interference from thetransmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"poor image rejection"},{"letter":"C","text":"splatter from the transmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"audio rectification in the receiver"}],"questionText":"An amateur transmitter is being heardacross the entire dial of a broadcastreceiver. The receiver is most probablysuffering from:"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-007","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Lack of receiver sensitivity and selectivity"},{"letter":"B","text":"Audio rectification of strong signals"},{"letter":"C","text":"Harmonics generated at the transmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Improper filtering in the transmitter"}],"questionText":"Your SSB HF transmissions are heardmuffled on a sound system in the living roomregardless of its volume setting. Whatcauses this?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-008","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Diode"},{"letter":"B","text":"Ferrite core"},{"letter":"C","text":"Magnet"},{"letter":"D","text":"Attenuator"}],"questionText":"What device can be used to minimize theeffect of RF pickup by audio wiresconnected to stereo speakers, intercomamplifiers, telephones, etc.?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Lengthen the leads"},{"letter":"B","text":"Connect the speaker through an audioattenuator"},{"letter":"C","text":"Connect a diode across the speaker"},{"letter":"D","text":"Shorten the leads"}],"questionText":"Stereo speaker leads often act as antennasto pick up RF signals. What is one methodyou can use to minimize this effect?"},{"questionId":"B-008-002-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"around a copper bar"},{"letter":"B","text":"around an iron bar"},{"letter":"C","text":"around a wooden dowel"},{"letter":"D","text":"through a ferrite core"}],"questionText":"One method of preventing RF from entering astereo set through the speaker leads is towrap each of the speaker leads:"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"By using a key-click filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"By increasing power"},{"letter":"C","text":"By using a better power supply"},{"letter":"D","text":"By sending CW more slowly"}],"questionText":"How can you prevent key-clicks?"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-002","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Your hand-held is transmitting spuriousemissions"},{"letter":"B","text":"You need a power amplifier for your hand-held"},{"letter":"C","text":"Your hand-held has a chirp from weakbatteries"},{"letter":"D","text":"You need to turn the volume up on yourhand-held"}],"questionText":"If someone tells you that signals from yourhand-held transceiver are interfering withother signals on a frequency near yours,what could be the cause?"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-003","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Spurious emissions"},{"letter":"B","text":"Side tones"},{"letter":"C","text":"Transmitter chirping"},{"letter":"D","text":"Off-frequency emissions"}],"questionText":"If your transmitter sends signals outside theband where it is transmitting, what is thiscalled?"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-004","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It may transmit a chirpy signal"},{"letter":"B","text":"It may radiate spurious emissions"},{"letter":"C","text":"It may transmit a weak signal"},{"letter":"D","text":"It may interfere with other stationsoperating near its frequency"}],"questionText":"What problem may occur if your transmitteris operated without the cover and othershielding in place?"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-005","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"frequency shifting caused by poor voltageregulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"the power amplifier, and is caused byhigh frequency parasitic oscillations"},{"letter":"C","text":"poor waveshaping caused by a poorvoltage regulator"},{"letter":"D","text":"the making and breaking of the circuit atthe Morse key"}],"questionText":"In Morse code transmission, local RFinterference (key-clicks) is produced by:"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-006","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"changes in oscillator frequency on keying"},{"letter":"B","text":"too sharp rise and decay times of thekeyed carrier"},{"letter":"C","text":"power supply hum modulating the carrier"},{"letter":"D","text":"sparks emitting RF from the key contacts"}],"questionText":"Key-clicks, heard from a Morse codetransmitter at a distant receiver, are theresult of:"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-007","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"sparking at the key contacts"},{"letter":"B","text":"sudden movement in the receiverloudspeaker"},{"letter":"C","text":"poor shaping of the waveform"},{"letter":"D","text":"shift in frequency when keying thetransmitter"}],"questionText":"In a Morse code transmission, broadbandwidth RF interference (key-clicks) heardat a distance is produced by:"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"does not cause any radio interference"},{"letter":"B","text":"is produced in a transmitter oscillatorstage"},{"letter":"C","text":"is an unwanted signal developed in atransmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"is generated by parasitic elements of aYagi beam"}],"questionText":"A parasitic oscillation:"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-010","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"at high frequencies only"},{"letter":"B","text":"at low frequencies only"},{"letter":"C","text":"at high or low frequencies"},{"letter":"D","text":"on harmonic frequencies"}],"questionText":"Parasitic oscillations in the RF poweramplifier stage of a transmitter may befound:"},{"questionId":"B-008-003-011","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"on harmonics of the transmitter frequency"},{"letter":"B","text":"above or below the transmitter frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"on VHF frequencies only"},{"letter":"D","text":"on the transmitter fundamental frequency"}],"questionText":"Transmitter RF amplifiers can generateparasitic oscillations:"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-001","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Harmonic radiation from your transmitter"},{"letter":"B","text":"De ionization of the ionosphere near yourneighbour's TV antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"TV receiver front-end overload"},{"letter":"D","text":"Too much low pass filtering on thetransmitter"}],"questionText":"If a neighbour reports television interferenceon one or two channels only when youtransmit on 15 metres, what is probably thecause of the interference?"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Signals which cause skip propagation tooccur"},{"letter":"B","text":"Unwanted signals at frequencies whichare multiples of the fundamental (chosen)frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"Unwanted signals that are combined witha 60-Hz hum"},{"letter":"D","text":"Unwanted signals caused bysympathetic vibrations from a nearbytransmitter"}],"questionText":"What is meant by harmonic radiation?"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-003","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"It may cause sympathetic vibrations innearby transmitters"},{"letter":"B","text":"It may cause auroras in the air"},{"letter":"C","text":"It may cause interference to otherstations and may result in out-of-bandsignals"},{"letter":"D","text":"It uses large amounts of electric power"}],"questionText":"Why is harmonic radiation from an amateurstation not wanted?"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Intermodulation"},{"letter":"B","text":"Auroral distortion"},{"letter":"C","text":"Harmonic radiation"},{"letter":"D","text":"Parasitic excitation"}],"questionText":"What type of interference may come from amulti-band antenna connected to a poorlytuned transmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-006","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Signals from a transmitter's output circuitare being sent back to its input circuit"},{"letter":"B","text":"The transmitting antenna is the wronglength"},{"letter":"C","text":"Overmodulating a transmitter"},{"letter":"D","text":"Keying a transmitter too fast"}],"questionText":"What causes splatter interference?"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-007","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"no high-pass filter on the TV"},{"letter":"B","text":"a bad ground at the transmitter"},{"letter":"C","text":"front-end overload of the TV"},{"letter":"D","text":"harmonic radiation from the transmitter"}],"questionText":"Your amateur radio transmitter appears tobe creating interference to the television onchannel 3 (60-66 MHz) when you aretransmitting on the 15 metre band. Otherchannels are not affected. The most likelycause is:"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-008","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"retune transmitter output"},{"letter":"B","text":"use another antenna"},{"letter":"C","text":"reduce oscillator output"},{"letter":"D","text":"reduce microphone gain"}],"questionText":"One possible cause of TV interference byharmonics from an SSB transmitter is from\"flat topping\" - driving the power amplifier intonon-linear operation. The most appropriateremedy for this is:"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-009","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"low SWR"},{"letter":"B","text":"resonant circuits"},{"letter":"C","text":"a linear amplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"overdriven stages"}],"questionText":"In a transmitter, excessive harmonics areproduced by:"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-010","answer":"D","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"crystal oscillator operating on itsfundamental"},{"letter":"B","text":"seventh harmonic of an 80 metretransmission"},{"letter":"C","text":"third harmonic of a 15 metre transmission"},{"letter":"D","text":"second harmonic of a 10 metretransmission"}],"questionText":"An interfering signal from a transmitter isfound to have a frequency of 57 MHz (TVChannel 2 is 54 - 60 MHz). This signal couldbe the:"},{"questionId":"B-008-004-011","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"excessive drive signal is applied to it"},{"letter":"B","text":"the output tank circuit is tuned to thefundamental frequency"},{"letter":"C","text":"the oscillator frequency is unstable"},{"letter":"D","text":"modulation is applied to a high-levelstage"}],"questionText":"Harmonics may be produced in the RFpower amplifier of a transmitter if:"},{"questionId":"B-008-005-001","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"A high pass filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"A CW filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"A low pass filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"A key-click filter"}],"questionText":"What type of filter might be connected to anamateur HF transmitter to cut down onharmonic radiation?"},{"questionId":"B-008-005-002","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"To reduce RF energy below a cut-off point"},{"letter":"B","text":"To reduce harmonic radiation"},{"letter":"C","text":"To reduce fundamental radiation"},{"letter":"D","text":"To reduce low frequency interference toother amateurs"}],"questionText":"Why do modern HF transmitters have abuilt-in low pass filter in their RF outputcircuits?"},{"questionId":"B-008-005-004","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Twice the transmission line impedance"},{"letter":"B","text":"Substantially higher"},{"letter":"C","text":"About the same"},{"letter":"D","text":"Substantially lower"}],"questionText":"What should be the impedance of a lowpass filter as compared to the impedance ofthe transmission line into which it isinserted?"},{"questionId":"B-008-005-005","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"Low pass"},{"letter":"B","text":"Key click"},{"letter":"C","text":"High pass"},{"letter":"D","text":"Rejection"}],"questionText":"In order to reduce the harmonic output of ahigh frequency (HF) transmitter, which of thefollowing filters should be installed at thetransmitter?"},{"questionId":"B-008-005-006","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"low pass filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"high pass filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"band reject filter"},{"letter":"D","text":"wave trap"}],"questionText":"To reduce harmonic output from a highfrequency transmitter, you would put a____________ in the transmission line asclose to the transmitter as possible."},{"questionId":"B-008-005-007","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"high pass filter"},{"letter":"B","text":"low pass filter"},{"letter":"C","text":"wave trap"},{"letter":"D","text":"band reject filter"}],"questionText":"To reduce energy from an HF transmittergetting into a television set, you would placea ____________ as close to the TV aspossible."},{"questionId":"B-008-005-008","answer":"A","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"allow only certain frequencies through"},{"letter":"B","text":"attenuate high frequencies but not low"},{"letter":"C","text":"pass frequencies each side of a band"},{"letter":"D","text":"stop frequencies in a certain band"}],"questionText":"A band pass filter will:"},{"questionId":"B-008-005-009","answer":"C","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"pass frequencies below 100 MHz"},{"letter":"B","text":"stop frequencies each side of a band"},{"letter":"C","text":"pass frequencies each side of a band"},{"letter":"D","text":"allow only two frequencies through"}],"questionText":"A band reject filter will:"},{"questionId":"B-008-005-010","answer":"B","answers":[{"letter":"A","text":"between transmitter output andtransmission line"},{"letter":"B","text":"at the antenna terminals of the TVreceiver"},{"letter":"C","text":"between microphone and speechamplifier"},{"letter":"D","text":"at the Morse key or keying relay in atransmitter"}],"questionText":"A high pass filter would normally be fitted:"}]
